<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Software Tester (Posts about career)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/career.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 16:03:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>TestBash NYC 2015: A Push in the Right Direction</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/testbash_nyc_2015/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/testbash-nyc.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2015 when TestBash came to the United States for the first time, it was to New York. I was living in the city, but I was stuck at a job that wouldn't pay for a ticket. "Ask Rosie if you can volunteer," my mentor/sponsor/benefactor Martin Hynie suggested. Rosie, who I knew only as the lady who'd mailed me Ministry of Testing stickers from England for...no reason at all, obviously let me in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask "can we do it?" instead of asking "should we do it?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to crash the speakers dinner. I got to go to Selena Delesie's workshop about leadership and change. At the end of the day, she praised my active participation and thanked me for being in her workshop. I was already confident in my testing skills, but she helped me see myself as a potential leader. In a follow-up coaching session I had with Selena about negotiating a higher salary, she asked me why I wanted more money. I'd recently moved into an apartment by myself, and couldn't think of what I would do with more money. It's something I think about with every job change, every growth in title and responsibility. Realizing I didn't want or need more money was a crucial step on the path to life-changing relocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common denominator in all your dysfunctional relationships is you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a break between talks the following day, I snuck on stage wearing "the" Ministry of Testing tutu. During another, I wrote a bunch of notes to give a 99-second talk about leaving a closing comment on a story (which I completely forgot about, &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/defining-story-completion-as-a-software-tester"&gt;before later writing on this topic for the Dojo&lt;/a&gt;). While waiting on stage behind dozens of people waiting to give their 99-second talks, I improvised one about moonwalking instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/99-second-talk.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="The 99-second talk I didn't give"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;The 99-second talk I didn't give&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Helena Jeret-Mäe, Maaret Pyhäjärvi, Dan Ashby, who along with the conference friendships I was just beginning to foster, gave me a vision of what my career could be, and where it could go at a time when I knew I needed something different. Helena saw my talk at Let's Test the following spring, and gave me valuable critical feedback that helped shaped future talks. Maaret introduced me to strong-style pairing, which changed the way I worked with my colleagues to this day. Dan had me on his podcast, reinforcing for me the success of my talk at the following year's TestBash USA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down when you receive a compliment. Maybe it's true. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Helena Jeret-Mäe&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I revisiting my notes from this conference six years later? I might be feeling a bit nostalgic for the seeing-people-in-person events a year into pandemic-induced isolation. I'm also in the middle of reading "Becoming a Technical Leader" by Jerry Weinberg. One of the questions asks you to read an autobiography of someone you admire. It turns out none of the people I shared TestBash NYC with have published autobiographies...yet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>conference</category><category>testbash</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/testbash_nyc_2015/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Karen Johnson at CAST 2015</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/karen_johnson_moving_testing_forward_cast_2015/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/karen-johnson.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was about to throw away a whole notebook full of conference notes I'd already blogged about. But because I'd already shipped these notes across an ocean and ignored them for a few years, I figured I'd give them a final read first. Luckily I found a few pages of gems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen Johnson's talk at CAST (The Conference for the Association of Software Testing) in 2015 covered the breath and depth of her experience in the software industry. I've taken on the career coaching role for some colleagues, and so much of what Karen emphasized is what I've been saying to them as they try to advocate for that promotion, discover their next step, or accept that they have done the best they could given the circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mi5R3mOILrw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Testers should have a portfolio&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you make your work visible? Particularly when your work is invisible when done well? Tell people about it in standups. Tell your boss at your 1-on-1. Write it down and then share a link the next time it comes up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;If you were to do a retro on yourself, what would you want it to be?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen advocated for giving back to the community, and challenged the gentleman who pointed out this was not strictly part of the job description. "That's just who I am." The senior roles at my current company are often differentiated not by technical prowess, but by building others up. Sharing to a big audience trips people up, but the steady radiating of information in writing, pairing with people to solve problems, and being the go-to person for questions serves to enrich and scale a company more effectively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Where's the gap between what you're doing now and what you want to do?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I'm able to concretely address within my company, when I know how the departments are structured and how the job descriptions fit into the org chart. I've made a list (or tasked my colleagues to do this for themselves) comparing their current job description to the one they're aiming for. Next to each item, list what you're already doing to fill that gap, or at least one thing you could be doing in that direction. Sometimes it's a matter of recognizing for yourself how much you already do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Your boss may never be your mentor&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These talks from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vXIZpe-x4o8"&gt;Marianne Duijst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/the-lost-art-of-the-journeyman-martin-hynie"&gt;Martin Hynie&lt;/a&gt; dive into this deeper, but find help where you can get it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;In five years you might specialize in something that doesn't exist today&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel a bit silly asking people in 2021 where they see themselves in the future, or even what they want for themselves. Don't feel bad if you don't have it all planned out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How to get promoted&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be reliable, dependable, the one to be counted on, and willing to take on more. Who wouldn't want someone like that around all the time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen says during the talk that she doesn't know what mark she will leave on the testing community. I certainly appreciate this bit of her wisdom. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/karen_johnson_moving_testing_forward_cast_2015/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>