<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Software Tester (Posts about career)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/career.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:46:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Long Haul</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_long_haul/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been both the lead of my team and a tester on that team for a year now. Getting answers, adapting to change, and identifying solutions have completely different time horizons in each of these roles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tester experiments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing experiments can run quickly. A testing experiment might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call an API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare that to the specification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Question whether either or both need changing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to a developer about the changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the specification and/or tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of that happens within minutes or hours, or days if schedules are extremely incompatible and asynchronous communication is failing. I can be confident in the experiment's outcome. I can weigh the relative merits of caring vs. not caring about a particular error response code or required field, and leave my work at work. The next time I see a particular error response, I know what to look for and where changes might be needed. A failing test is evidence that something used to work in a particular way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Team lead experiments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team lead experiments take longer. A team lead experiment might look something more like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team members complain that it's hard to get their ideas in during refinement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I mention this to the talking-dominant team member at a 1-on-1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member dominates following refinement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I remind talking-dominant team member in Slack about our previous conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member spills over their allotted time during big unit meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bring both of these instances in our 1-on-1, sharing the consequences (they're the single point of failure, other team members aren't heard) of their actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member does it again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ask team member what I can do to help them change their behavior, given that we are both adults in control of our own behavior. They agree that change is their responsibility. We agree that setting their microphone on mute at the start of the meeting would help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member dominates some of the following refinement, until I remind them to mute, after which other team members have time to think and contribute too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ask talking-dominant team member to set up a Slackbot to send them a reminder to mute their microphone each week before the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other people are able to contribute at the following refinement. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This took place over months. We're not to a point where we have a solution that works every time. I went in with a different hypothesis each time, not knowing when I'd hit on the right one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. I think the talking-dominant team member isn't aware of their behavior.&lt;br&gt;
4. I think the team member has forgotten our first conversation.&lt;br&gt;
6. I think the team member doesn't understand the impact of their behavior.&lt;br&gt;
8. I think the team member hasn't found a tool or a trigger to change their habit.&lt;br&gt;
10. I think the team member needs both a tool and a trigger to change their habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of the first four experiments taken by itself looks like a failure. The talking-dominant team member prevents other team members from contributing effectively. It takes me time as a leader to come up with a different hypothesis, try something else, and discover where to go from there. And this was a relatively straightforward issue to assess. Imagine how long it might take to find an effective response to a problem with more variables and more consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also thinking not just about the experiments themselves, but how they might come across to the wider team. For the testing experiment, I could present my results in standup the next day as "I tested it, everything's good" but it's more valuable for everyone if I &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/defining-story-completion-as-a-software-tester"&gt;tell a bit more of the story&lt;/a&gt;. In the team lead experiment, I can imagine my team member telling my boss "Elizabeth told me to be quiet" or me telling my boss "The talking-dominant team member is giving room for others to contribute." Telling a slightly longer story of the journey displays my value as a team lead in a better light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What experiments are you running right now? Is something that looks or feels like a failure getting you closer to a solution? How long is your time horizon?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>critical-thinking</category><category>humans</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>teaching</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_long_haul/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TestBash NYC 2015: A Push in the Right Direction</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/testbash_nyc_2015/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/testbash-nyc.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2015 when TestBash came to the United States for the first time, it was to New York. I was living in the city, but I was stuck at a job that wouldn't pay for a ticket. "Ask Rosie if you can volunteer," my mentor/sponsor/benefactor Martin Hynie suggested. Rosie, who I knew only as the lady who'd mailed me Ministry of Testing stickers from England for...no reason at all, obviously let me in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask "can we do it?" instead of asking "should we do it?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to crash the speakers dinner. I got to go to Selena Delesie's workshop about leadership and change. At the end of the day, she praised my active participation and thanked me for being in her workshop. I was already confident in my testing skills, but she helped me see myself as a potential leader. In a follow-up coaching session I had with Selena about negotiating a higher salary, she asked me why I wanted more money. I'd recently moved into an apartment by myself, and couldn't think of what I would do with more money. It's something I think about with every job change, every growth in title and responsibility. Realizing I didn't want or need more money was a crucial step on the path to life-changing relocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common denominator in all your dysfunctional relationships is you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a break between talks the following day, I snuck on stage wearing "the" Ministry of Testing tutu. During another, I wrote a bunch of notes to give a 99-second talk about leaving a closing comment on a story (which I completely forgot about, &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/defining-story-completion-as-a-software-tester"&gt;before later writing on this topic for the Dojo&lt;/a&gt;). While waiting on stage behind dozens of people waiting to give their 99-second talks, I improvised one about moonwalking instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/99-second-talk.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="The 99-second talk I didn't give"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;The 99-second talk I didn't give&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Helena Jeret-Mäe, Maaret Pyhäjärvi, Dan Ashby, who along with the conference friendships I was just beginning to foster, gave me a vision of what my career could be, and where it could go at a time when I knew I needed something different. Helena saw my talk at Let's Test the following spring, and gave me valuable critical feedback that helped shaped future talks. Maaret introduced me to strong-style pairing, which changed the way I worked with my colleagues to this day. Dan had me on his podcast, reinforcing for me the success of my talk at the following year's TestBash USA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down when you receive a compliment. Maybe it's true. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Helena Jeret-Mäe&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I revisiting my notes from this conference six years later? I might be feeling a bit nostalgic for the seeing-people-in-person events a year into pandemic-induced isolation. I'm also in the middle of reading "Becoming a Technical Leader" by Jerry Weinberg. One of the questions asks you to read an autobiography of someone you admire. It turns out none of the people I shared TestBash NYC with have published autobiographies...yet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>conference</category><category>testbash</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/testbash_nyc_2015/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Karen Johnson at CAST 2015</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/karen_johnson_moving_testing_forward_cast_2015/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/karen-johnson.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was about to throw away a whole notebook full of conference notes I'd already blogged about. But because I'd already shipped these notes across an ocean and ignored them for a few years, I figured I'd give them a final read first. Luckily I found a few pages of gems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen Johnson's talk at CAST (The Conference for the Association of Software Testing) in 2015 covered the breath and depth of her experience in the software industry. I've taken on the career coaching role for some colleagues, and so much of what Karen emphasized is what I've been saying to them as they try to advocate for that promotion, discover their next step, or accept that they have done the best they could given the circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mi5R3mOILrw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Testers should have a portfolio&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you make your work visible? Particularly when your work is invisible when done well? Tell people about it in standups. Tell your boss at your 1-on-1. Write it down and then share a link the next time it comes up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;If you were to do a retro on yourself, what would you want it to be?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen advocated for giving back to the community, and challenged the gentleman who pointed out this was not strictly part of the job description. "That's just who I am." The senior roles at my current company are often differentiated not by technical prowess, but by building others up. Sharing to a big audience trips people up, but the steady radiating of information in writing, pairing with people to solve problems, and being the go-to person for questions serves to enrich and scale a company more effectively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Where's the gap between what you're doing now and what you want to do?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I'm able to concretely address within my company, when I know how the departments are structured and how the job descriptions fit into the org chart. I've made a list (or tasked my colleagues to do this for themselves) comparing their current job description to the one they're aiming for. Next to each item, list what you're already doing to fill that gap, or at least one thing you could be doing in that direction. Sometimes it's a matter of recognizing for yourself how much you already do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Your boss may never be your mentor&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These talks from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vXIZpe-x4o8"&gt;Marianne Duijst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/the-lost-art-of-the-journeyman-martin-hynie"&gt;Martin Hynie&lt;/a&gt; dive into this deeper, but find help where you can get it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;In five years you might specialize in something that doesn't exist today&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel a bit silly asking people in 2021 where they see themselves in the future, or even what they want for themselves. Don't feel bad if you don't have it all planned out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How to get promoted&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be reliable, dependable, the one to be counted on, and willing to take on more. Who wouldn't want someone like that around all the time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen says during the talk that she doesn't know what mark she will leave on the testing community. I certainly appreciate this bit of her wisdom. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/karen_johnson_moving_testing_forward_cast_2015/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>