<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Organizational Anarchist (Posts about coaching)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/coaching.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 18:55:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Not Every Detail Matters</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/02_12_not_every_detail_matters/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I was looking at a user story for one of the teams I support. The story was about improving a very particular page. Our users do see it. But only for 5-10 minutes per week, if they've started their work early. We deploy this product weekly just before working hours. Deploying currently involves taking the whole product down. Customers can sign up for noticifications so they're reminded about this downtime window. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story was to improve the look of a page. People might see it and be confused if the stars aligned and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They started work early.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They hadn't signed up for the notification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They hadn't seen the web app with just a logo on it before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They didn't try it again in a few minutes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I asked the ticket writer, "This doesn't impact customers much (5-10 minutes per week). Is fixing this worth the effort?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They wrote back "I believe in 'Every detail matters.' This particular detail should take very little effort to realize, so my answer on this question is Yes."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's possible they're right to pick this ticket up. It was a small enough effort that we might as well do it. If they're wrong, they're the one feeling the pain of explaining the ticket to the team, verifying the fix, deciding what to put in the release notes, etc. It's a safe-to-fail experiment for me as a quality coach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I didn't have the same mindset. I don't believe that we should fix everything we find in our app that violates my expectations. I don't think it's possible to identify one correct set of expectations and priorities that our users will share. I don't think the things that we've already fixed will stay fixed. I don't think it's possible to cover every issue with an automated test. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we need to let go. We need to decide what's important, and focus on that. The details of the downtime page -- the new design, and the time the team spent updating it, and the effort I'd spend having the conversation about it -- none of them mattered too much to me. We need to notice details, and also know when to turn our brains off to being bothered by them. We need to think about the risks of our tests could uncover; our goal isn't 100% test coverage. In short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every detail matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are limited by our attention, energy, health, meetings on our schedule, time left on this earth. Software is complex enough that it's very unlikely we'll be able to solve every issue we find. The more time we spend solving the unimportant ones, the less time we have left to look for the important ones. Or decide what is important. Or understand our users better to be able to more effectively evaluate the relative importance of such issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerry Weinberg cheekily noted the impossibility of this endeavor in his book accurately titled &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/8ba29269-1843-4ac1-be0c-226752b17937"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perfect Software and Other Illusions About Testing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Black Box Software Testing Course on Test Design emphasized the need for testers to balance risk vs. coverage. Its focus on &lt;a href="https://www.developsense.com/blog/2010/05/why-we-do-scenario-testing/"&gt;scenario testing&lt;/a&gt; insisted we tie our testing to a user's journey through the software that was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coherent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;credible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;motivating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;complex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easy to evaluate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this is the right approach. It will leave time to build new features and learn new skills. It's what will make it possible for us to feel fulfilled and motivated in our work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I just need to figure out how to scale this mindset. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>mindset</category><category>risk-based-testing</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/02_12_not_every_detail_matters/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Try Asking Different Questions</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/try_asking_different_questions/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/paths.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I'll never know everything, but I love asking questions to get to know more. Obviously, the same question applied in different contexts will yield different results. A couple questions that worked exactly as I'd wanted with engineering teams really fell flat with UX and product. And a couple &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/"&gt;meta-level&lt;/a&gt; questions allowed openings I wouldn't have imagined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When I asked the wrong question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Joining standups&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the charter for my role is to help improve processes and communication around the department. I'd attended each of the engineering team daily standup meetings, and I wanted to do the same for our designers. My intention was something everyone would agree to, but how I asked made it difficult for the designer to see that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Do designers all meet once a day? I've joined all the other standups; may I join yours?""&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might have given an impression that I was trying to inflict help or take over, rather than listen and see if my expertise was needed. Even following up with more details about wanting not to duplicate their work didn't seem to clarify my intention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, speaking to another colleague and starting with my intention helped me understand what space I could be included in. There was a weekly meeting the engineering and product managers attended, where deeper design sessions were planned for that week. I would have never known to ask:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Can I attend your weekly meeting with the managers?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;because I didn't know there was a weekly meeting. Sharing my intention might have gotten me there sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;End-to-end flow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd made a big, complicated diagram of how our users moved through our connected products. I'd imagined it could trigger discussions about all sorts of things, but the two things I wanted it to give the most perspective on were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Are we testing the end-to-end flow?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Are we capturing metrics on the end-to-end flow?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describing the specific actions a user could take and how the products were interconnected showed that, for the development teams, it was hard to know what the ends were. I showed the diagram to most of the development teams and asked the question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What could users do that I haven't captured?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They each thought of things inside the little bubble of their work. But asking the same question to a product owner yielded completely different results: more questions, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Who are our users? Where do I see them here?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Can we separate out one flow for one use case for one user?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How are people onboarded? Where do our users start?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those last two were completely left of my diagram, since they were outside the scope of what our development teams would build or test for a particular user story. But indeed, the product owners were right that onboarding was part of the end-to-end flow, and thus should be included in how we're looking at the user's journey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few more discussions, I identified an even better question for the product owners: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How are you thinking about the whole journey a user takes?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When I asked the right question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Is this the right agenda?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started a meeting with a group of about 12 people with the question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Is this the right agenda?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make sure the needs that I could see from my position matched what was most important to them. There were five items on the agenda. When we got to the third one, someone determined that there was another way we could approach it, and we changed the agenda right there. Offering the opportunity at the beginning allowed for the team members to take ownership of their time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What fell through the cracks?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrospectives I've attended and facilitated have often had a "What went wrong?" kind of section. I asked a different question in a session about test strategy, hoping to uncover something slightly different: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What fell through the cracks?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving enough silence let people ponder their work in the recent weeks. People named a few product bugs logged to start. After even more silence, some process bugs came to light as well. It was interesting to see how a slight change in the phrasing of the question uncovered things the retrospectives hadn't. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What questions do you tend to ask to the same people in the same way? What might you discover if you change the way you're asking the question? Can you leave more room for thought and contemplation in your conversations?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>communication</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/try_asking_different_questions/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Unblocking Your Test Strategy</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/unblocking_your_test_strategy/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/lightbulb.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;In my new role as Quality Lead for my department, I get to figure out how to infuse everybody's work with "quality", and also figure out what that means exactly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my colleagues made it easy for me on my second day by coming with a relatively concrete problem: they wanted an acceptance environment for their team. Their team (henceforth: Eager Team) integrated with chronically overloaded and busy team (henceforth: Busy Team), so they wanted an environment where they could test their stuff together before it went into production. They wanted me to help set that up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my conversation with Eager Team Lead by taking one step back: why did they want this environment? They'd proposed a solution, but I wanted to spend at least a few minutes digging into the problem space with them to hear more about why they wanted this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Come up with dream scenario&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked Eager Team Lead what their dream setup would be for their test automation, and why that was the dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eager Team and Busy Team already had a test environment hooked up to one another. But they both threw whatever they were in the middle of on that environment. Eager Team couldn't count on a stable, usable version of Busy Team's software, and vice versa. Eager Team wanted a place to see what would happen against the production version of Busy Team's code. They wanted to automate all the things they could, and have a place to run that automation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Identify (and confirm they are indeed) constraints&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Busy Team was busy. They wouldn't be able to make setting up an environment for Eager Team a priority in the next few months. I had that impression, and so did Eager Team Lead. They were, after all, Busy Team. But I wanted to make sure that the busyness of Busy Team was a constraint. I took on the action point to follow up with Boss Person about how we could both (1) check that Busy Team was indeed too busy, and (2) how to get this request on Busy Team's long list for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also dispelled one of assumptions underlying Eager Team Lead's dream setup: it was important to test everything, in an automated way, in the ideal environment, or else testing wouldn't be valuable. I explained that it's &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/8ba29269-1843-4ac1-be0c-226752b17937"&gt;impossible to test everything&lt;/a&gt;. Testing in an automated way would be more likely to reveal known unknowns than the unknown unknowns their team was interested in. And that it wasn't all-or-nothing - every little bit would help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Choose achieveable pieces within constraints&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than killing the dream, I identified a valuable first step in the direction of the dream. Eager Team would write down, in English to start, 3-5 things that they want to test using both their software and Busy Team's. They'd show those to their product owner to make sure they were things customers cared about. From there, we could look at whether to build automation, and if so, where to run it. There was that test environment already. We had production, could we use feature flags? Could we keep the data only visible to our employees internally? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew I'd hit a nerve when Eager Team Lead said "Oh, we can just start iterating over this!" Because of course, the software itself is not the only thing you can build in an iterative way. Your test automation can also mitigate risk, confirm assumptions, and provide value along the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how'd it go? I confirmed Busy Team's busyness, and got more details on how and when to add this request to their list. I'm following up with Eager Team next week to see where they are in identifying valuable scenarios, or if I should jump in there too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wow, what a feeling to be able to lift the weight of "I need a thing I don't know how to build and don't think I can ever get" off someone's shoulders and replace it with "I know what to do next and it's achievable." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more quality leading to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>automation</category><category>coaching</category><category>risk-based-testing</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/unblocking_your_test_strategy/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Praise the Messenger</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/praise_the_messenger/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I hear no a lot. No, that's not in scope for this story. No, it's not worth fixing that now. No, that's not risky enough for you to spend time testing. Hearing no on a good day sparks my creativity and pushes me into more valuable directions. On a bad day, it makes me wonder why I should keep going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying no in a good way takes practice. I've honed this skill with wisdom from some of the best. Elisabeth Hendrickson tweeted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/testobsessed/status/1361844997276930049"&gt;a list of some of the different ways she has of saying no&lt;/a&gt;. It reminded me that the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1376971216653856770"&gt;sassy replies&lt;/a&gt; I send to recruiters and speaking engagements in which I have no interest or connection. If you're looking for a style that builds bridges rather than burns them down, I'd recommend Elisabeth's Hendrickson's examples, not mine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Let's Test in Sweden in 2016, Fiona Charles gave a workshop on Learning to Say No. We practiced different ways to say no, complete with supporting arguments and steadfast determination tailored to the real-life situations participants brought to the workshop. (In a demonstration of having embraced the message of the workshop, we disbanded halfway through the allotted time. I spent the rest of the afternoon on a memorable bike ride along the Swedish coast.) The strongest revelation from the group was: we have more power than we think we do. There may be consequences to saying no, refusing a particular task, or turning down an opportunity, but it's often within our power to do so. Saying no effectively makes room you to decide how to spend your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Agile Testing Days in 2018, Liz Keogh gave a keynote on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KvKFlMfEqxM"&gt;how to tell people they failed (and make them feel great)&lt;/a&gt; that culminated in a surprising conclusion: don't. Don't tell people they failed. Use positive reinforcement to encourage the behaviors you want to see, and the others will fall away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a tester leave the company recently. They'd set goals with their manager that directly opposed the test strategy I helped them shape. Bugs they reported were shot down, postponed until future stories, or grouped together as issues to be fixed eventually someday. They were facing a lot of "no," and as far as I could see from a different team, not a lot of yes. How long would you last in this situation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a tester reporting to me at the moment. They've been catching tricky things, find bugs, and preventing problems. I want them to keep doing what they're doing. I get that a developer's first reaction when they hear about a bug might not be "Oh wow, thank you so much for this pile of questions and work!" I have to give them that positive reinforcement so they keep reporting and digging into issues, so I call it out in their 1-on-1. They thank me, and says it keeps them going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't shoot the messenger. Praise the messenger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tired: Don't shoot the messenger.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Wired: Encourage and support the messenger, so they are motivated to keep bringing you messages.&lt;/p&gt;— Elizabeth Zagroba (@ezagroba) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1403356865694683137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are you saying no to frequently? Is your no driving them away, or encouraging them? Do you need to say no? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/sign.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="If you were waiting for a sign - this is it."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;If you were waiting for a sign - this is it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>communication</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>reporting</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/praise_the_messenger/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>