<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Organizational Anarchist (Posts about communication)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/communication.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 14:47:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Talk About Your Test Strategy</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/06_06_talk_about_your_test_strategy/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I was invited to join a team's debate this week about what environment to point our third-party security testers towards for their upcoming penetration test. I asked what I thought was both an obvious question and something worth discussing with the team: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Do we want them to identify security risks, or are we just checking boxes here?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A combination of stunned silence and nervous giggling (muted over Zoom) ran through the team. "We don't talk about that out loud," the team lead told me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's exactly what I'm there to help uncover as the Quality Lead for this team and the others in our unit: how deep or shallow should our testing be? If our testing uncovers issues, are we interested in mitigating them? &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-05-24_if_a_test_falls_in_a_forest/"&gt;If not, why are we testing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Test Strategy in Five W's&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conversation took me back to a few years ago. I was working on a product in a phase before production-level quality that we dubbed "demo-driven development" in retrospect. We were showing off a combination of Powerpoint slides and small pieces of the product in order to gain more funding. A person interested in testing but with too large a scope to pay attention to my team in particular asked me for a test strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the demos kept changing. What was important this week wouldn't be important the next. There wasn't a lot of exploratory testing being performed or automated tests being written. All my time was occupied in figuring out what had already been promised, what we were trying to sell, and filling in the gaps between those with a very specific path our product owner would follow during a demo, down to browser and screen resolution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the person who wanted the test strategy document what they were going to do with it, what it might be used for. They sent me the enormous table where a link to my test strategy would be added, and clearly never looked at or noticed again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could I document in an official test strategy document for my team that I wasn't doing much testing? It turns out, yes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I outlined the document with the five w's: who, what, when, where, and why. The whole document looked something like this. I don't think you even needed to scroll to read it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who: Our stakeholders are the people we're selling to, our product owner, and our team, in that order. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What: We're testing one particular happy path in Firefox (our product owner's default browser).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When: Due to the volatile nature of our product's priorities, our minimal testing has been concentrated after user stories are completed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where: We're running the application locally for demos. We haven't had a chance to set everything up we'd need to have in a hosted environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why: We test to ensure that the one happy path is demonstrable to a customer in a demo, and to provide our product owner with the work-arounds for the gaps in our product. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sent it to the person, expecting them to get back to me and tell me I couldn't do testing like this. Or at least, I couldn't write it down. But they never read the document! They thanked me, linked it in their table, and went on their merry way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Test Strategy in Stakeholders and Risks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the way I shaped my test strategy around the very specific set of stakeholders and their risks in the five w's strategy. I wanted to bring this same connection to the teams I support when I started as Quality Lead for my unit. I ran a test strategy workshop for each of them to identify their stakeholders, talk about the risks that matter to them, and see how their team activities mitigated those risks. I got to this Miro board template after a few rounds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List the software the team is responsible for. (Our teams typically have legacy products they're maintaining in addition to the new things their roadmap focuses on.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mind map the stakeholders for these products. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add stickies next to the stakeholders' names with their possible risks and concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the types of testing activities (things like exploratory testing, reviewing the production logs, static code analysis, etc.) for comprehension and completeness. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move each testing activity onto the impact (it's important vs. it's not important) and priority (we do this vs. we don't do this) quadrants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vote on stickies that landed in an unexpected spot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk about the most-voted stickies in order, and identify action points with owners from there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of this workshop was to show the teams that not every piece of testing is something that matters to the stakeholders. I didn't expect them to do every possible kind of testing imaginable. But I did want them to all understand and agree what kinds of testing they were and weren't doing. I got them talking about it out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Test Strategy Derived from a Vision&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, a one-time workshop was not enough to get everyone to identify and build the perfect test strategy! As the teams grew and the workshop faded from memory, I got questions about the test strategy for the teams. I heard about goals of "bug-free software" and asked about "what best practices to follow" to get there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As fun as it would be to pontificate about how &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/8ba29269-1843-4ac1-be0c-226752b17937"&gt;there is no such thing as bug-free software&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.jrothman.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Cynefin.jpg"&gt;there are no best practices outside of the obvious domain&lt;/a&gt;, that doesn't help people know what to do. So I wrote a "Quality Vision" document. (Pro tip: use a noun you wouldn't use for anything else so it's easy to pull it up by typing "vision" in your browser bar.) The Quality Vision for the unit places trust in the expertise of the teams to choose their own ways forward. It has things like: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is our product at the right level of quality to release right now?&lt;/strong&gt; This is a constant conversation between the development team and your product owner. Think about the risks and concerns of the customers you're targeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Security&lt;/strong&gt; We're not to use production/customer data for development purposes outside support incidents. Here's a link to a more in-depth document from our Security team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability&lt;/strong&gt; Here's a link to the document of what we promise our customers in our service-level agreement. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not going to tell you what the right answer is for your team right now, but it'll give you some things to point to when you're discussing quality with your team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because after all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality is value to some person who matters at a particular point in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the penetration test, the team lead quickly followed their "We don't talk about that out loud" comment with a "why not both?" jest.  Why can't we both check the boxes for the authorities, and uncover valuable information that we want to act on? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, that's where we landed. We decided to point the security team to the production environment because that would reveal the best information. Unless that setup takes too long for the team, then we'll point them to the test environment. But regardless: we'll tell our bosses and our product owner what we're doing and why. We'll talk about our test strategy out loud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How have you started a conversation about quality with your team? When have you decided not to test something? What have you not tested and also not discussed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/megaphone.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@patrickian4"&gt;Patrick Fore&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/06_06_talk_about_your_test_strategy/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>CVs From A Hiring Perspective</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_27_cvs_from_a_hiring_perspective/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In my department at work, every tester is on their own team. I'm in a position where I look at tester resumes before we decide to screen them. Some of the resumes come in from people applying on the company website. We've also got a recruiter searching for people on LinkedIn. She asked me before we posted a new job: if we're not requiring experience with a particular tech stack, what should she search for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't have a great answer for her at first. It took me some time to think about what we'd value in this role, what would make a candidate's resume stand out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't look for particular buzzwords on resumes, and no particular buzzword can eliminate you from the hiring process. But I do look for some of the same &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/defining-story-completion-as-a-software-tester"&gt;things I look for in a test report&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/how-to-interview-like-a-tester"&gt;an indicator of the depth and quality of your work, and an ability to connect your work to the value to the development team or the business&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A resume that regurgitates the calendar or job description of the candidate doesn't stand out to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attended standup, refinement, sprint planning, sprint review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made test plan, executed tests, reported tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to know what was hard about it. I want to know who else was there and how you interacted with them. I want to know what you do that other people in your position don't do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitated hybrid standup across three time zones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refined ideas into user stories with acceptance criteria that met our definition of ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoke to key stakeholders to identify risks and incorporate them into a test plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared test results verbally to spark conversation with developers about impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented test plan at guild to inspire other testers to shift left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on a &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/series/testbash-careers-2022/lessons/discussion-creating-cvs-that-get-noticed-elizabeth-zagroba-nicola-martin-peet-michielsen"&gt;TestBash Careers panel&lt;/a&gt; about having a CV that gets you noticed. (I regret to inform you that my ability to think of an answer and unmute are not always fast enough to chime in!) I'm digging into the unanswered questions on &lt;a href="https://club.ministryoftesting.com/t/testbash-careers-2022-discussion-with-elizabeth-zagroba-nicola-martin-a-peet-michielsen/59274"&gt;the club thread&lt;/a&gt;, and can tell you that my fellow panelists and host are more shrewed about when or when not to reveal a personal detail on a resume. I am privileged enough to &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/assets/resumes/trustworthy-resume.pdf"&gt;lean towards the truth&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at work, I told the recruiter there were a couple things should could search for: exploratory testing and integration testing. Our desire to cast as wide and inclusive a net as possible has been an investment of her time, and the time of the team members who speak to the candidates first. It's not cheap. I hope it's worth it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jobs.lever.co/mendix/92c1c255-2455-4c25-bd78-a05c154d5f8e"&gt;Join us if you're interested&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/women-interview.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@wocintechchat?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Christina @ wocintechchat.com&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>communication</category><category>testbash</category><category>writing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_27_cvs_from_a_hiring_perspective/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Communicate Using Three Layers of Information</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_12_communicate_using_three_layers_of_information/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've joked about writing Buzzfeed-style clickbait titles for JIRA tickets: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Stuck in purgatory after hitting logout &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Maybe not so clickbait-ey but I logged this for more than one system I tested. The navigation had a different login state than the page and you couldn't escape.)&lt;/p&gt;— Elizabeth Zagroba (@ezagroba) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1503647930061885444?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 15, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partly, clickbait titles gave me an easy way to search the database, or type a few words in my browser bar, to pull up the right issue quickly. The JIRA ticket itself had steps to reproduce, an explanation of why it was important, and an annotated screenshot for people to easily understand if what I saw was happening on their machine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partly, clickbait titles gave us a convenient shorthand to help us remember whether it's this logout issue or some other logout that we're talking about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partly, clickbait titles made the developers interested to investigate and pick up the issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading Giles Turnbull's &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/876240f0-8657-4482-b5c5-8160bef6d372"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The agile comms handbook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last weekend and found the &lt;em&gt;lure&lt;/em&gt; part of the three communication layers he described (&lt;em&gt;lure&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;detail&lt;/em&gt;) reminiscent of the clickbait JIRA ticket titles I'd written. And that I'd see these three communication layers (title, description, details) described similarly in lots of places before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lure, context, detail&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole (short and great) &lt;em&gt;The agile comms handbook&lt;/em&gt; is about how to communicate in ways that move as fast as the work does on an Agile team while still being effective for busy people to consume. In the book, Giles Turnbull describes creating different layers of information as &lt;em&gt;lure&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;detail&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Lure&lt;/em&gt; grabs the attention of busy people and gets them interested in knowing more. &lt;em&gt;Context&lt;/em&gt; gets people to the point where they know just enough. &lt;em&gt;Detail&lt;/em&gt; is for people who need to know more and have the time to follow a link to another page, read a whole PDF, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why, how, what&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek describes it as &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qp0HIF3SfI4"&gt;this TED Talk on "How great leaders inspire action"&lt;/a&gt;. He gives the example of an advertisement for Apple, where starting with the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; is much more inspiring and motivating than starting with the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;. Getting people to buy into your vision will ensure that they follow along to the goal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Title, executive summary, list of issues&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we worked together, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vds4"&gt;Martin Hynie&lt;/a&gt; taught me to write weekly test reports with a &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;executive summary&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;list of issues&lt;/em&gt;, with the idea that the &lt;em&gt;executive summary&lt;/em&gt; should be enough for the busy person to understand, but that less busy and more curious people would want the detail in the &lt;em&gt;list of issues&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Intent, location, details&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maaretp"&gt;Maaret Pyhäjärvi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/mob-testing-an-introduction-experience-report"&gt;describes the ensemble (mob) programming practice&lt;/a&gt; of communicating at the highest level of abstraction (&lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt;) before being more specific about where we're going (&lt;em&gt;location&lt;/em&gt;) or if necessary, mouse clicks and keystrokes (&lt;em&gt;details&lt;/em&gt;). Giving keystrokes and mouse clicks to someone who knows how to operate the software is frustrating, but so is giving a high-level explanation to someone who's never used the software before. Expressing intent first can lead to better action, even if another member of the ensemble has a different action in mind than you do. Being able to identify when to jump between the levels is key for effective communication. Knowing when to jump to a different layer of communication is the skill I find hardest to build while learning to ensemble. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Title, lede, body&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the content management system I tested for New York Public Radio, article pages were broken down into &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;lede&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;body&lt;/em&gt;, presumably reflecting something every journalist learns on their first day at a newspaper. On the website, &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;lede&lt;/em&gt; were displayed on the homepage and tag pages. You'd only see the &lt;em&gt;body&lt;/em&gt; once you clicked in to read or listen to the story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read so many JIRA tickets and Slack messages that only contain the lowest/detail level of information. The person trying to bring everyone else up-to-speed on an issue does need to include all the detail. It makes sense that that's where their mind is. Giles Turnbull identifies why the detail layer of information is the default: the details already exist. Creating the other lure and context layers of information takes more work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to zoom out and answer the kinds of questions you'd expect in a refinement meeting ("Who will benefit from this? How does it work now and why does it need to change?") helps you prioritize the work. It helps the team understand how what they're doing fits into the bigger picture. Learning how to write the &lt;em&gt;lure&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt; is a separate technical skill that needs to be recognized and built. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you learn to break down your communication into different layers? Do the title, headers, and paragraphs of this blog post fit this model? Which of these breakdowns resonates most with you? Where are you practicing communicating this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/colorful-layers.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@snapsbyclark?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Clark Van Der Beken&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/elevated?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>writing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_12_communicate_using_three_layers_of_information/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tell Your Colleagues About Your Work</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/04_02_tell_your_colleagues_about_your_work/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;At the interview for my very first job at my hometown library, the librarian  recounted my work as a volunteer. In addition to reshelving the returned books, I'd put the books that were already on the shelves back in order. She asked if I had anything else to share. "No," I said. I let the librarian speak for me. My work spoke for itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My job at the library took no coordination, little or no communication, and was quite boring. There was always someone else at the desk to talk to patrons and handle the actual "returning the books" part. I could just listen to my iPod and shelve the books. The disappearing books and neatness of the shelves were evidence of my work that anyone could notice and evaluate at a glance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work in software has been quite the opposite. It's been hard to evaluate by a person who doesn't know where (or how) to look. They might notice if I'd done my job very poorly or not at all. But the difference between a job very well done and a job just, well, &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; has been overwhelmingly large and invisible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent most days in my career thus far as a tester on a development team with a daily standup. Standup was the place I could make at least a small part of my work visible. Contributions only became clear in bigger groups if someone else championed my testing work, or if the impact of my leadership was felt more widely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I'm serving several teams. I don't have a daily standup. I've been working remotely for two years. I could put in a lot of work in my current role that no one would ever see. It's felt strange to feel like everyone is wondering how I spent an hour, to being much less accountable for my time. I have the freedom to waste a lot of time on something that isn't important or doesn't matter to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not how I want to spend my time. I want to use my time and effort effectively. There's always more to do. I want to share with my colleagues what I've done and what I'm planning on picking up next, so they can tell me if my effort is duplicated, wasted, or in need of a course-correction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where, who, what, and how I tell them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have invitations to each of the standups for the teams I support. I go once every couple weeks to keep an ear out for how I can help them. Sometimes that's the right time to share a bit of what I've been working on too, if it's just for them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also held myself accountable in three other meetings that span across the department: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's a weekly meeting for the whole department. There I share highlights of general interest for less than five minutes and add linked details in the shared agenda. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do a similar thing for the bi-weekly sync of all the engineering leads, tailored to their interests. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these quick updates, I share why I picked up the work, who it serves, and what problem it solves. I've seen so many sprint demos that share the "what" but not the "who" or the "why" that I try to include all three pieces in my stories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I host a meeting every few weeks with the engineering and product managers that's all about my work. They're the ones who need to see the outcomes and impact, so it's worth investing a bit of time to make sure I'm focusing on the right things for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meeting focused on my role, I let the conversation be freer. We dig into more of the why's and "is this valuable?"'s of what I'm up to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also got a 1-on-1 with my manager. I've got 5-10 minutes every two weeks to share and get advice on particularly triumphant or hairy situations not fit for a wider audience. The rest of our half hour 1-on-1 is my boss responding to what I shared and sharing information with me from the wider company context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why I tell them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I do all of this? Why do I invest so much time in talking about the work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the work does not speak for itself. Testing is not like shelving books in a library. Being able to explain my work helps me collaborate. It makes it clear what kinds of problems they can come to be with, and ensures that I'm top-of-mind when such problems do arise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharing what I'm working on &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2017/2017-08-06_doubt-builds-trust/"&gt;builds trust&lt;/a&gt;. It's not arrogant, bragging, or self-indulgent. It's a neccesary part of making sure I'm doing the right thing, and &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2015/11/13/why-men-get-all-the-credit-when-they-work-with-women/"&gt;getting credit for it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/orange-desert.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@gspyadav?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Shiva Prasad Gaddameedi&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/elevated?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/04_02_tell_your_colleagues_about_your_work/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Strengthen Your Code Review Skills</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/02_27_strengthen_your_code_review_skills/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I spent my first two years at my current company getting my code reviewed and the following almost two years reviewing 3-10 merge requests per week. Our tech stack was in Python, with pytest as our test running, the requests library for API tests, and Selenium for browser tests, all hosted in our company's paid gitlab instance. All that experience shaped how (and whether I) offer feedback on the merge requests I reviewed for members of my own team and neighboring teams working in the same tech stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Define the relationship.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are power dynamics at play in any relationship at work. For members of my team, they had to have a really good argument to refute one of my "suggestions" because I was their test specialist &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; their team lead evaluating their ability to respond to feedback and change their behavior by performance review time. No pressure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For members of other teams, they had more power to push back. It could empower them with the knowledge I shared, but they were free to reject it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Focus on what matters.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I review a merge request, I start with the question "what is this code supposed to do?" If it's a merge request for my team, the JIRA ticket number in the title or the branch name would clue me in. For code from other teams, champions would use the description field to explain what the product change was and how the test code supported that. Most merge requests left me guessing a bit. I'd have to read the code contained in the tests to figure out what the test, and ultimately the product, was supposed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading the code also got me thinking about the things I was best equipped to help the code submitter with: maintainability and "what if?" scenarios. As a tester, I could look at a list of tests that create, read, and delete a thing and ask "is update also part of the picture here?" As a code reviewer with a longer tenure at the company, I had a more informed view of whether copy and pasting would work or if a new function was needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had two linters set up to run on every commit: flake8 covered style enforcement (indentation, blank lines, etc.) and vulture identified unused code. For issues of style that a machine couldn't decide, we had written guidelines to point to. I pointed to these three the most often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comments explain why the code is the way it is, not what it does (so code is clearer to read and update)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setup and teardown should take place outside the test (so pytest reporting tells you there's an &lt;code&gt;error&lt;/code&gt; instead of a &lt;code&gt;failure&lt;/code&gt; when something's off)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API tests assert the status code before any details about the response body (because the body's not going to have the right stuff in it anyway if the status code is wrong)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would give feedback about these topics, trying to ask questions to disambiguate my observations from interpretations. I knew that the person who'd written the code had spent more time and thought steeped in the problem than I had. Questions allowed me to assume competence while gathering evidence to the contrary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I read other people's code, I saw lots of weird stuff: stuff I would name differently, stuff I would put in a different order, stuff that took up more or fewer lines than I would have to write the same thing. My experience living in a non-native English speaking culture served me well here: I let it go. Was the test name meaningful to them and their team? Did putting it across a couple more lines help them understand it better? Was it actually a problem with what the code did or just a personal opinion? Did they want to set the constant right before they used it instead of at the top? Go for it! It works, I can understand what they meant, and that should be the threshold. My review was not an opportunity for me to show off my Python skills. I was there to help the code submitter with their tests. I reserved the right to remain silent on unimportant matters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Communicate well.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Praise the good!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice when people have done something well and praise them for it! Positive reinforcement is the best way to turn up the good on what's already happening in your code base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Right level of abstraction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reviewed merge requests that were 30% done that I mistook for 100% done; conversely I saw at 110% done that I would have killed at 30%. A little [WIP] label in the name of the merge request or bullet list of which tests were still missing helped me offer the code submitter the right kind of feedback at the right time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the code isn't the problem, the product is. I've seen a 500 http status code returned for something the user screwed up, which should be in the 400-range. A code comment "Should this be a 400 response?" opened up a more interesting conversation about where the product was in its lifecycle and the code submitter could lobby their team to change the product's behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If having the conversation about the code isn't the right approach, I tried having &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/"&gt;the meta-conversation&lt;/a&gt; instead. "I'm not convinced this API spec is done. Where are you in that process?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/wtf.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Code quality measurement: WTFs/minute"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Code quality measurement: WTFs/minute&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Right format&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tone is hard in writing. I do prefer writing, because it gives me the opportunity to have several drafts, separating my WTFs-per-minute from what the code submitter receives. I just don't always hit send. Before leaving a comment on a particular line in gitlab, I ask myself: is this the right format? Have I removed any judgy adverbs like "just", "obviously", or "actually"? Would a video call, a Slack message, or a comment on the whole merge request be more likely to be embraced?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The receiving&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the many tough things about feedback is that the receiver determines the priority of the feedback. (For all the other tough things about feedback, read &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/15270135-7360-4e66-b079-4cbd618dfb76"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Did You Say? The Art of Giving and Receiving Feedback&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.) The code submitter often completely miss what I meant the first time. Even if I thought I'd delivered my feedback as well as I could have, it wasn't always accepted. Everyone extracts different information from the same situation. The feedback that provides the most information can be the hardest to accept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It doesn't have to be like this.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Asynchronous&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have read my first paragraph and asked yourself "why is she doing so many async code reviews?" and you'd be right! The company was scaling at a speed that I was forced to optimize for "number of minutes per day without video calls" over shared understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Synchronous&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that working in a pair or an ensemble can do all this feedback and knowledge-sharing stuff in a better way? See more about how an ensemble made learning happen in &lt;a href="https://ezagroba.github.io/mob-testing/"&gt;this slide deck&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was able to, having a conversation helped me make sure that I was giving the right feedback at the right time to the right person. Pairing with the code submitter got not only the mistakes fixed, but also the thought processes behind those mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/two_birds.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don't take my word for it.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the benefit of learning from smart people who are also thinking through what code reviews are and what they can be. I have yet to be free at a time when &lt;a href="https://github.com/neontribe/code-reading-club/"&gt;the code reading club&lt;/a&gt; Felienne Hermans started has met, but I look forward to joining sometime in the future. Here is a collection resources that I've already found useful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Videos&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah Mei on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YL-6RCTywbc"&gt;The Power of Agile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nina Zakharenko on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6L3ZVLtSeo8"&gt;Code Review Skills for Pythonistas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sasha Laundy on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hY14Er6JX2s"&gt;Giving and Getting Technical Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Books&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/15270135-7360-4e66-b079-4cbd618dfb76"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Did You Say? The Art of Giving and Receiving Feedback&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/b15fe452-5b8e-49f5-9e0b-90da490b944c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crucial Conversations: Tool for Talking When Stakes Are High&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blog posts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michaela Greiler on &lt;a href="https://www.michaelagreiler.com/respectful-constructive-code-review-feedback/"&gt;giving respectful code reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michaela Greiler on &lt;a href="https://www.michaelagreiler.com/accept-code-review-feedback/"&gt;how to handle criticism during code reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica Joy Kerr on &lt;a href="https://jessitron.com/2021/03/27/those-pesky-pull-request-reviews/"&gt;those pesky code reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Angie Jones with &lt;a href="https://angiejones.tech/ten-commandments-code-reviews/"&gt;the 10 commandments of navigating code reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lucas Rocha on &lt;a href="https://lucasr.org/2011/01/29/micro-commits/"&gt;microcommits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Quotes found on Twitter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;April Wensel on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maaretp/status/1024995595973525510"&gt;compassionate code review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patricia Aas on the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pati_gallardo/status/1373343835330383878"&gt;zero-trust process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michaela Greiler on how &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mgreiler/status/1482247806798733317"&gt;everybody needs an editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michaela Greiler &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mgreiler/status/1481902327640608770"&gt;thread on the biggest annoyances during code reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amy Edmondson on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmyCEdmondson/status/1476198824012136460"&gt;psychological safety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jerry Weinberg on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mstine/status/1481660769456513029"&gt;egoless programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allen Holub on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/allenholub/status/1491168642586710016"&gt;async code reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allen Holub on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/allenholub/status/1482564778149175298"&gt;inspecting quality in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@robinmathlener?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Robin Mathlener&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>code-review</category><category>communication</category><category>feedback</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/02_27_strengthen_your_code_review_skills/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Try Asking Different Questions</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/try_asking_different_questions/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/paths.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I'll never know everything, but I love asking questions to get to know more. Obviously, the same question applied in different contexts will yield different results. A couple questions that worked exactly as I'd wanted with engineering teams really fell flat with UX and product. And a couple &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/"&gt;meta-level&lt;/a&gt; questions allowed openings I wouldn't have imagined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When I asked the wrong question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Joining standups&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the charter for my role is to help improve processes and communication around the department. I'd attended each of the engineering team daily standup meetings, and I wanted to do the same for our designers. My intention was something everyone would agree to, but how I asked made it difficult for the designer to see that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Do designers all meet once a day? I've joined all the other standups; may I join yours?""&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might have given an impression that I was trying to inflict help or take over, rather than listen and see if my expertise was needed. Even following up with more details about wanting not to duplicate their work didn't seem to clarify my intention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, speaking to another colleague and starting with my intention helped me understand what space I could be included in. There was a weekly meeting the engineering and product managers attended, where deeper design sessions were planned for that week. I would have never known to ask:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Can I attend your weekly meeting with the managers?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;because I didn't know there was a weekly meeting. Sharing my intention might have gotten me there sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;End-to-end flow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd made a big, complicated diagram of how our users moved through our connected products. I'd imagined it could trigger discussions about all sorts of things, but the two things I wanted it to give the most perspective on were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Are we testing the end-to-end flow?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Are we capturing metrics on the end-to-end flow?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describing the specific actions a user could take and how the products were interconnected showed that, for the development teams, it was hard to know what the ends were. I showed the diagram to most of the development teams and asked the question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What could users do that I haven't captured?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They each thought of things inside the little bubble of their work. But asking the same question to a product owner yielded completely different results: more questions, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Who are our users? Where do I see them here?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Can we separate out one flow for one use case for one user?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How are people onboarded? Where do our users start?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those last two were completely left of my diagram, since they were outside the scope of what our development teams would build or test for a particular user story. But indeed, the product owners were right that onboarding was part of the end-to-end flow, and thus should be included in how we're looking at the user's journey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few more discussions, I identified an even better question for the product owners: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How are you thinking about the whole journey a user takes?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When I asked the right question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Is this the right agenda?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started a meeting with a group of about 12 people with the question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Is this the right agenda?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make sure the needs that I could see from my position matched what was most important to them. There were five items on the agenda. When we got to the third one, someone determined that there was another way we could approach it, and we changed the agenda right there. Offering the opportunity at the beginning allowed for the team members to take ownership of their time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What fell through the cracks?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrospectives I've attended and facilitated have often had a "What went wrong?" kind of section. I asked a different question in a session about test strategy, hoping to uncover something slightly different: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What fell through the cracks?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving enough silence let people ponder their work in the recent weeks. People named a few product bugs logged to start. After even more silence, some process bugs came to light as well. It was interesting to see how a slight change in the phrasing of the question uncovered things the retrospectives hadn't. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What questions do you tend to ask to the same people in the same way? What might you discover if you change the way you're asking the question? Can you leave more room for thought and contemplation in your conversations?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>communication</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/try_asking_different_questions/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cutting People Off</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/cutting_people_off/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/shushing.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;Impatience is a virtue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If impatience is solely your own, sorry, but you're the asshole. But if impatience is shared, saving your colleagues from a tiresome conversation will make their day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notice that a topic should come to a close&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you listen actively, you'll notice when something has already been said. It is much easier (particularly when remote) to give up, zone out, and think about something else. Don't be that person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engage with your colleagues! Save yourself and others from the perpetual purgatory that is an ineffective meeting. Pay attention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Decide whether you are the right person to close a topic&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be settings where you are the right person to decide if a topic should come to a close: in a small group of relative equals, when you're the appointed facilitator, or you're in some other position of power relative to the individuals or the subject matter. Recognize when you're not in the right position to change what's happening in the moment, and skip to Follow-up for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the group already has expectations about what is or isn't on topic, your interruption should be enough. If it doesn't, or you want to take this opportunity to set a new one, interrupt with a meta-question. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How to deliver this message&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not always in the best position to decide whether now is the right time for a topic, so I tend to deliver topic-closing messages as questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I agree with your point about Thing B, but can we come back to Thing D?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We agreed that Person A is going to follow-up with Person C, is there anything more that we need to discuss about Thing B right now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could discuss Thing B more in this group, but since we're missing Person C's crucial input, should we?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've captured what Person A said here in the notes. Was there anything I missed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Person A already said Thing B, shall we move on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It sounds like we're still discussing Thing B after we just agreed not to, am I understanding that correctly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we leave it there for now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're not sure if it's the right time for a question, try a meta-question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is now the right time to decide if we should keep talking about Thing B?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we going to be able to come to Decision D today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did we decide on a next step towards Thing B, or is that what you were describing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give the group a chance to decide, but don't be afraid to hold them to their decision. These are not questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've agreed to that. Let's move on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That's all we needed Person A for, let's let them go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That's all I have for you, I'll let you go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thank you for your input/time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got it, thanks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Follow-up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get feedback on your behavior. This is how you learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A retrospective or 1-on-1 would be a good place to find out if the balance was right between gathering/sharing information and staying on topic. Asking someone to watch out for this particular behavior ahead of time will allow them to give you better feedback afterwards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A colleague once declared me the "queen of cutting people off" because I did so very politely. I have a compliment stickie note from "ruling refinement with an iron fist." We should all be so lucky to have our work appreciated this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on meta-information, see &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/"&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;. For more on setting agendas and preparing for meetings to make them effective, see &lt;a href="https://j19sch.github.io/slides/atd2020-making-meetings-work.html"&gt;this deck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>humans</category><category>leadership</category><category>meetings</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/cutting_people_off/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Praise the Messenger</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/praise_the_messenger/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I hear no a lot. No, that's not in scope for this story. No, it's not worth fixing that now. No, that's not risky enough for you to spend time testing. Hearing no on a good day sparks my creativity and pushes me into more valuable directions. On a bad day, it makes me wonder why I should keep going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying no in a good way takes practice. I've honed this skill with wisdom from some of the best. Elisabeth Hendrickson tweeted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/testobsessed/status/1361844997276930049"&gt;a list of some of the different ways she has of saying no&lt;/a&gt;. It reminded me that the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1376971216653856770"&gt;sassy replies&lt;/a&gt; I send to recruiters and speaking engagements in which I have no interest or connection. If you're looking for a style that builds bridges rather than burns them down, I'd recommend Elisabeth's Hendrickson's examples, not mine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Let's Test in Sweden in 2016, Fiona Charles gave a workshop on Learning to Say No. We practiced different ways to say no, complete with supporting arguments and steadfast determination tailored to the real-life situations participants brought to the workshop. (In a demonstration of having embraced the message of the workshop, we disbanded halfway through the allotted time. I spent the rest of the afternoon on a memorable bike ride along the Swedish coast.) The strongest revelation from the group was: we have more power than we think we do. There may be consequences to saying no, refusing a particular task, or turning down an opportunity, but it's often within our power to do so. Saying no effectively makes room you to decide how to spend your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Agile Testing Days in 2018, Liz Keogh gave a keynote on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KvKFlMfEqxM"&gt;how to tell people they failed (and make them feel great)&lt;/a&gt; that culminated in a surprising conclusion: don't. Don't tell people they failed. Use positive reinforcement to encourage the behaviors you want to see, and the others will fall away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a tester leave the company recently. They'd set goals with their manager that directly opposed the test strategy I helped them shape. Bugs they reported were shot down, postponed until future stories, or grouped together as issues to be fixed eventually someday. They were facing a lot of "no," and as far as I could see from a different team, not a lot of yes. How long would you last in this situation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a tester reporting to me at the moment. They've been catching tricky things, find bugs, and preventing problems. I want them to keep doing what they're doing. I get that a developer's first reaction when they hear about a bug might not be "Oh wow, thank you so much for this pile of questions and work!" I have to give them that positive reinforcement so they keep reporting and digging into issues, so I call it out in their 1-on-1. They thank me, and says it keeps them going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't shoot the messenger. Praise the messenger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tired: Don't shoot the messenger.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Wired: Encourage and support the messenger, so they are motivated to keep bringing you messages.&lt;/p&gt;— Elizabeth Zagroba (@ezagroba) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1403356865694683137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are you saying no to frequently? Is your no driving them away, or encouraging them? Do you need to say no? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/sign.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="If you were waiting for a sign - this is it."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;If you were waiting for a sign - this is it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>communication</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>reporting</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/praise_the_messenger/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Delivering Information vs. Delivering Meta-Information</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/victor-garcia-unsplash.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of the first testing skills I built was &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2014/2014-02-24_writing-clear-and-effective-bug-reports/"&gt;bug reporting&lt;/a&gt;. I practiced narrowing down the steps to reproduce. I told my developers what was happening now and what should happen instead. I learned to include where the issue was occurring, so my developers would stop closing my bugs with the &lt;code&gt;Works for me&lt;/code&gt; resolution in Trac. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PaulHolland_TWN"&gt;Paul Holland&lt;/a&gt; taught me to tell the story of my testing. That is, meta-information about my testing. Sure, I still reported the outcomes: these things didn't work, these things did. But I also reported:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how I tested the product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how good that testing was&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long did it take me to test? What was difficult about my testing, made it difficult to get started, or slowed it down? What wasn't I able to test? The reason we tell those stories is to help uncover product risks, process risks, and get help from those around us to solve the issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is meta-information about my testing. It's what I'm seeing as I'm doing it, one level removed from the actual testing itself. (Look up &lt;code&gt;testopies&lt;/code&gt; [testing + autopsy] for more on gathering meta-level information about your testing.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the skills around meta-information are important for doing any job well. These skills include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identifying when you're communicating at the information level, or the meta-level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;switching between and keep track of whether you're communicating at the information level or meta-level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;naming the different levels, and bringing the people you're communicating with on this level-switching journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These recent examples stick in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Addresing the question vs. addressing the miscommunication&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was interviewing a candidate for a Software Development Manager position. For about a half hour, every question proceeded more or less like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd ask a question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The candidate would speak for a minute or a few, without answering the question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd rephrase the question, be more specific, or add more details to help the candidate understand the question&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The candidate would speak again, again not answering the question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd try once or twice more, before moving on to the next question. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized early on that this was happening. I consider it an essential skill to be able to answer a question directly, or identify when you're having trouble doing that, as a Software Development Manager. I decided I'd reject the candidate, but realized I'd still have to get through the rest of this hour with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague, my co-interviewer, took a different approach. He called out the miscommication problem to the candidate! He said "Elizabeth is asking you questions, and you're not answering them. Did you notice that? Why is that?" It was direct in a way that made me uncomfortable, and that I would have trouble doing with someone I just met. But he moved the conversation to where it needed to be: the meta-level. The candidate struggled to answer this question as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I jumped in to ease the awkwardness. I offered up my theory: the candidate's responses weren't answers, they were the candidate agreeing with the premise of the question. My colleague completely agreed, thanked me for contribution, but politely redirected the burden of this problem onto the candidate. The candidate continued to struggle without acknowledging the issue or the awkwardness for the rest of the interview. It was a clear decision for both me and my colleague: we would not be hiring this person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty scheduling a meeting vs. telling them that&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was asking for more details on the planning of a project in standup. My developer described how hard it was to find time with a particular developer on another team. They said the project was going to take weeks to scope instead of the days they thought it could take, if only they could find time with this person. The project seemed important, already had a deadline (or really, sadline&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;), and waiting until the next free spot on this person's calendar wasn't working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked my developer "Have you given his this feedback directly?" I suspected that only the information had been communicated: the following meeting would have to wait a week. My hunch was correct. I suggested my developer try giving this person the meta-information: about how hard they were to schedule, how this was cutting into the time we had to work on the project once it was scoped, and how that threatened the deadline. Imagine how differently this person could react and rearrange what they were doing, or share their relative priorities so we could adjust our expectations, when given this meta-information. This was last week, so I don't know yet how this story ends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Adding testing details to the story vs. why I'm asking for them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a user story about being able to send metrics from our application to another application. I was picking up the testing on the story. My developer said they'd confirmed in the other application that our metrics were sent. They'd only sent a success, so I was planning on using the same setup as they did to look in the other application, but see what a failure looked like instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not what I told my developer. What I said to them was: "Add enough details to the ticket so I can test it." It turned out, we had different ideas about what &lt;code&gt;enough&lt;/code&gt; meant. First they added a URL. I followed the URL and it went to a blank page with a header. I said the same thing again, "Add enough details to the ticket so I can test it." They wrote down the first button they had to click on. I asked a third time. They added one more detail, which still didn't tell me enough. But I got tired of asking. I tried all the options in the application, Googled to figure out what SQL query I needed, executed it, triggered a variety of different failures, and confirmed that they were received. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I explained to my developer the difference between my expectations and what they wrote. They explained how their expectations were also violated: they had to reach out to the team from the other product, figure out what to do, poke around in the product, and that the details they left me were all they received to be able to eventually figure it out. To them, just the URL going to a blank screen was &lt;code&gt;enough&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fn:3"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized then that I had left out a crucial piece of meta-information: the reason I was asking for the details. I wanted to skip that poking around time. I had ten other tasks this day, and expected this to only take 20 minutes instead of the few hours it ended up taking. I was hoping to benefit from the poking around work my developer had already done. I was expecting a lot of context, and my developer was expecting to only need to share a little bit of context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I shared this with them, they understood where the gap was between my expectations and theirs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suggestion about scheduling difficulties, that was an easy conversation to have. The other two were quite difficult for me. They took patient, active listening. I had to keep asking myself if I'd been clear enough with my expectations. They definitely made me sweat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving between information communication and meta-level communication is a skill. It takes time, failure, reflection, and practice to do it. Doing it well is a leadership skill. &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/b15fe452-5b8e-49f5-9e0b-90da490b944c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crucial Conversations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helped me identify when it's worth working on the relationship with a person and investing in these conversations. You don't have to be managing people (as I am currently) to be building or using this skill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What meta-level conversations are you avoiding? Are there people where you find you're only able to communicate on an information level? Have you tried communicating with them on a meta-level? What would happen if you told them that's what you were trying?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high-context cultures like the United States and the Netherlands, the deliverer assumes the burden of the miscommunication, not the receiver. There's more about this in &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/f0d396c1-fcd9-4beb-9538-4d11e04e3e1c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Culture Map&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A deadline is when somebody dies. Most things we call deadlines at work are just sadlines, in that people are alive but just sad when they're missed. Read more about it in &lt;a href="https://lizkeogh.com/2017/08/31/reflecting-reality/"&gt;Liz Keogh's blog post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague is coming from a low-context culture. I'm coming from a high-context culture. You can read more examples of this in &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/f0d396c1-fcd9-4beb-9538-4d11e04e3e1c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Culture Map&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but it's the kind of non-fiction book that could have been a blog post, so just read the rest of this blog post instead? &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fnref:3" title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>