<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Software Tester (Posts about communication)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/communication.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 12:44:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Praise the Messenger</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/praise_the_messenger/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hear no a lot. No, that's not in scope for this story. No, it's not worth fixing that now. No, that's not risky enough for you to spend time testing. Hearing no on a good day sparks my creativity and pushes me into more valuable directions. On a bad day, it makes me wonder why I should keep going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying no in a good way takes practice. I've honed this skill with wisdom from some of the best. Elisabeth Hendrickson tweeted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/testobsessed/status/1361844997276930049"&gt;a list of some of the different ways she has of saying no&lt;/a&gt;. It reminded me that the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1376971216653856770"&gt;sassy replies&lt;/a&gt; I send to recruiters and speaking engagements in which I have no interest or connection. If you're looking for a style that builds bridges rather than burns them down, I'd recommend Elisabeth's Hendrickson's examples, not mine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Let's Test in Sweden in 2016, Fiona Charles gave a workshop on Learning to Say No. We practiced different ways to say no, complete with supporting arguments and steadfast determination tailored to the real-life situations participants brought to the workshop. (In a demonstration of having embraced the message of the workshop, we disbanded halfway through the allotted time. I spent the rest of the afternoon on a memorable bike ride along the Swedish coast.) The strongest revelation from the group was: we have more power than we think we do. There may be consequences to saying no, refusing a particular task, or turning down an opportunity, but it's often within our power to do so. Saying no effectively makes room you to decide how to spend your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Agile Testing Days in 2018, Liz Keogh gave a keynote on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KvKFlMfEqxM"&gt;how to tell people they failed (and make them feel great)&lt;/a&gt; that culminated in a surprising conclusion: don't. Don't tell people they failed. Use positive reinforcement to encourage the behaviors you want to see, and the others will fall away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a tester leave the company recently. They'd set goals with their manager that directly opposed the test strategy I helped them shape. Bugs they reported were shot down, postponed until future stories, or grouped together as issues to be fixed eventually someday. They were facing a lot of "no," and as far as I could see from a different team, not a lot of yes. How long would you last in this situation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a tester reporting to me at the moment. They've been catching tricky things, find bugs, and preventing problems. I want them to keep doing what they're doing. I get that a developer's first reaction when they hear about a bug might not be "Oh wow, thank you so much for this pile of questions and work!" I have to give them that positive reinforcement so they keep reporting and digging into issues, so I call it out in their 1-on-1. They thank me, and says it keeps them going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't shoot the messenger. Praise the messenger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tired: Don't shoot the messenger.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Wired: Encourage and support the messenger, so they are motivated to keep bringing you messages.&lt;/p&gt;— Elizabeth Zagroba (@ezagroba) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1403356865694683137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are you saying no to frequently? Is your no driving them away, or encouraging them? Do you need to say no? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/sign.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="If you were waiting for a sign - this is it."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;If you were waiting for a sign - this is it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>communication</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>reporting</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/praise_the_messenger/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Delivering Information vs. Delivering Meta-Information</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/victor-garcia-unsplash.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the first testing skills I built was &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2014/2014-02-24_writing-clear-and-effective-bug-reports/"&gt;bug reporting&lt;/a&gt;. I practiced narrowing down the steps to reproduce. I told my developers what was happening now and what should happen instead. I learned to include where the issue was occurring, so my developers would stop closing my bugs with the &lt;code&gt;Works for me&lt;/code&gt; resolution in Trac. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PaulHolland_TWN"&gt;Paul Holland&lt;/a&gt; taught me to tell the story of my testing. That is, meta-information about my testing. Sure, I still reported the outcomes: these things didn't work, these things did. But I also reported:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how I tested the product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how good that testing was&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long did it take me to test? What was difficult about my testing, made it difficult to get started, or slowed it down? What wasn't I able to test? The reason we tell those stories is to help uncover product risks, process risks, and get help from those around us to solve the issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is meta-information about my testing. It's what I'm seeing as I'm doing it, one level removed from the actual testing itself. (Look up &lt;code&gt;testopies&lt;/code&gt; [testing + autopsy] for more on gathering meta-level information about your testing.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the skills around meta-information are important for doing any job well. These skills include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identifying when you're communicating at the information level, or the meta-level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;switching between and keep track of whether you're communicating at the information level or meta-level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;naming the different levels, and bringing the people you're communicating with on this level-switching journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These recent examples stick in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Addresing the question vs. addressing the miscommunication&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was interviewing a candidate for a Software Development Manager position. For about a half hour, every question proceeded more or less like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd ask a question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The candidate would speak for a minute or a few, without answering the question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd rephrase the question, be more specific, or add more details to help the candidate understand the question&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The candidate would speak again, again not answering the question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd try once or twice more, before moving on to the next question. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized early on that this was happening. I consider it an essential skill to be able to answer a question directly, or identify when you're having trouble doing that, as a Software Development Manager. I decided I'd reject the candidate, but realized I'd still have to get through the rest of this hour with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague, my co-interviewer, took a different approach. He called out the miscommication problem to the candidate! He said "Elizabeth is asking you questions, and you're not answering them. Did you notice that? Why is that?" It was direct in a way that made me uncomfortable, and that I would have trouble doing with someone I just met. But he moved the conversation to where it needed to be: the meta-level. The candidate struggled to answer this question as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I jumped in to ease the awkwardness. I offered up my theory: the candidate's responses weren't answers, they were the candidate agreeing with the premise of the question. My colleague completely agreed, thanked me for contribution, but politely redirected the burden of this problem onto the candidate. The candidate continued to struggle without acknowledging the issue or the awkwardness for the rest of the interview. It was a clear decision for both me and my colleague: we would not be hiring this person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty scheduling a meeting vs. telling them that&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was asking for more details on the planning of a project in standup. My developer described how hard it was to find time with a particular developer on another team. They said the project was going to take weeks to scope instead of the days they thought it could take, if only they could find time with this person. The project seemed important, already had a deadline (or really, sadline&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;), and waiting until the next free spot on this person's calendar wasn't working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked my developer "Have you given his this feedback directly?" I suspected that only the information had been communicated: the following meeting would have to wait a week. My hunch was correct. I suggested my developer try giving this person the meta-information: about how hard they were to schedule, how this was cutting into the time we had to work on the project once it was scoped, and how that threatened the deadline. Imagine how differently this person could react and rearrange what they were doing, or share their relative priorities so we could adjust our expectations, when given this meta-information. This was last week, so I don't know yet how this story ends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Adding testing details to the story vs. why I'm asking for them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a user story about being able to send metrics from our application to another application. I was picking up the testing on the story. My developer said they'd confirmed in the other application that our metrics were sent. They'd only sent a success, so I was planning on using the same setup as they did to look in the other application, but see what a failure looked like instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not what I told my developer. What I said to them was: "Add enough details to the ticket so I can test it." It turned out, we had different ideas about what &lt;code&gt;enough&lt;/code&gt; meant. First they added a URL. I followed the URL and it went to a blank page with a header. I said the same thing again, "Add enough details to the ticket so I can test it." They wrote down the first button they had to click on. I asked a third time. They added one more detail, which still didn't tell me enough. But I got tired of asking. I tried all the options in the application, Googled to figure out what SQL query I needed, executed it, triggered a variety of different failures, and confirmed that they were received. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I explained to my developer the difference between my expectations and what they wrote. They explained how their expectations were also violated: they had to reach out to the team from the other product, figure out what to do, poke around in the product, and that the details they left me were all they received to be able to eventually figure it out. To them, just the URL going to a blank screen was &lt;code&gt;enough&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fn:3"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized then that I had left out a crucial piece of meta-information: the reason I was asking for the details. I wanted to skip that poking around time. I had ten other tasks this day, and expected this to only take 20 minutes instead of the few hours it ended up taking. I was hoping to benefit from the poking around work my developer had already done. I was expecting a lot of context, and my developer was expecting to only need to share a little bit of context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I shared this with them, they understood where the gap was between my expectations and theirs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suggestion about scheduling difficulties, that was an easy conversation to have. The other two were quite difficult for me. They took patient, active listening. I had to keep asking myself if I'd been clear enough with my expectations. They definitely made me sweat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving between information communication and meta-level communication is a skill. It takes time, failure, reflection, and practice to do it. Doing it well is a leadership skill. &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/b15fe452-5b8e-49f5-9e0b-90da490b944c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crucial Conversations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helped me identify when it's worth working on the relationship with a person and investing in these conversations. You don't have to be managing people (as I am currently) to be building or using this skill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What meta-level conversations are you avoiding? Are there people where you find you're only able to communicate on an information level? Have you tried communicating with them on a meta-level? What would happen if you told them that's what you were trying?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high-context cultures like the United States and the Netherlands, the deliverer assumes the burden of the miscommunication, not the receiver. There's more about this in &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/f0d396c1-fcd9-4beb-9538-4d11e04e3e1c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Culture Map&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A deadline is when somebody dies. Most things we call deadlines at work are just sadlines, in that people are alive but just sad when they're missed. Read more about it in &lt;a href="https://lizkeogh.com/2017/08/31/reflecting-reality/"&gt;Liz Keogh's blog post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague is coming from a low-context culture. I'm coming from a high-context culture. You can read more examples of this in &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/f0d396c1-fcd9-4beb-9538-4d11e04e3e1c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Culture Map&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but it's the kind of non-fiction book that could have been a blog post, so just read the rest of this blog post instead? &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/#fnref:3" title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>