<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Software Tester (Posts about conference)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/conference.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 20:52:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Agile Testing Days 2020</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-11-29_agile_testing_days_2020/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/log-of-zero.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you say no to what you don't have the energy for, you leave your time, attention, and devotion free to pursue what keeps you energized. Through a tumult of plans and dreams that only 2020 could continue to crush, the Agile Testing Days crew put on a revitalizing conference. I only caught a glimpse of the preparation that went into providing a top-notch experience for speakers and participants, and I have to commend the group on their commitment to the cause. Bravo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talks were recorded. I've decided to cut myself off on catching up on missed talks after two weeks. Reflecting on what wisdom I've garned from a small subset of the offerings at Agile Testing Days will be more valuable than being exposed to every last word. In that spirit, let me give you a few takeaways in place of an exhaustive recap or analysis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parveen Khan: watch this if you're looking to collaborate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is in doing the work that we discover what we must do. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't get stuck when learning something alone; pair. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;João Proença: watch this if you need a different direction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing a health check and making a diagnosis are different skills. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What barriers do we set for ourselves?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The product is all the pieces the customers see, including the cloud infrastructure (and whatever else your team isn't responsible for). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Holland &amp;amp; Huib Schoots: watch this if your automation isn't providing valuable information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sunk cost fallacy means we're unlikely to get rid of automation code, even if it's ineffective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We often fail at getting people to change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gitte Kligaard talk: watch this if you've been hiding your true self at work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I'm just going to rewind." (Possibly my favorite takeaway from this conference, I'm going to use this anytime I trip over my words.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creativity comes when inspired by others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being professional is knowing your craft, and admitting when you don't know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend time with yourself to listen to yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Schladebeck &amp;amp; Ashley Hunsberger: no recording, but follow these ladies on Twitter for how to balance life and leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell people what you want. They may be able to help you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a clear vision of what you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down your fear. Ask yourself: Why is this positive? How can I build the courage to do this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be explicit about what you're doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show how you're working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a practice of reflection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angie Jones: watch this if you need a push to get into automation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine your goal first. If you don't know it, you'll definitely fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're a leader, celebrate the small victories. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's no reason to shame people for being creative and doing the best they can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's not realistic to assume master level by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out why developers don't participate in automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob Meaney: watch this if you don't get why observability is important&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We learn profound lessons from painful experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build relationships. Influence people at the right time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pain + reflection =&amp;gt; progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't matter how much we test a thing if nobody wants to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobias Geyer: watch this if you're struggling with an ethical dilemna &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could ethics be a non-functional requirement?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the codes of ethics proposed by the IEEE, ISTQB, ACM, and James Bach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A hippocrattic oath for software testing: avoid harm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote environment sustainability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smita Mishra: watch this if you're interviewing users &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to be able to ask clarifying questions and dig deeper. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask users: their objective, what they found, about the impact, where they're struggling, what could make their lives easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eveline Moolenaars: watch this if you're learning to coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"We have a policy; it's somewhere on the internet" isn't enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Everyone deserves a coach to make them aware of what they've forgotten." ~Brad Gilbert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federico Toledo: watch this if you or those around you are losing steam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tester with a sense of purpose is more resilient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on strengths more than weaknesses, turning up the good. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide visibility that you're doing something with the feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask people if they're getting what they need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicola Sedgwick: watch this if you're the gatekeeper for quality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not correlate your own successes with the quality of the entire system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contract-driven work is not holistic quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report when there has been no progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for a code walk-through before a build is ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift quality left all the way to the executive team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testers were hoarding responsibility for quality. Let it go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joep Schuurkes: watch this if (or while) you're stuck in an ineffective meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: is my work inside or outside of meetings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the right group of people in the room before holding a meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Express specific appreciations for things done well so people will keep doing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meetings are synchornous collaboration with a purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standups should remove impediments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The metaphors we choose say something about how we feel about our work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership is creating an environment where everyone can contribute to solving a problem. ~Jerry Weinberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clare Norman: watch this if you're truly stuck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality is everyone's care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Success is liking who you are, what you do, and how you do it." ~Maya Angelou&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your courage quota for the day might vary. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don't get better by doing the same thing everyday. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn't know how I needed to be helped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can't drag someone through time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We live far less in the present than we ought to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How magical is it when people value the change that you're making?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passion spreads when other people share in your excitement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a cheerleader in your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/success.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Clare Norman channeling Maya Angelou on success"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Clare Norman channeling Maya Angelou on success&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny Bramble: watch this if your tests are failing on expected behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many defects I filed are never fixed. Unfixed defects become expected behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation has never found a defect. Automation tells us behavior has changed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests should pass on expected behavior, including some defects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document your tests for others, including your future self.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Lyndsay &amp;amp; Anne Colder: watch this if you feel like an impostor &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge when you can't help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you could take one step forward, what would you do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to your person, or ask a smaller group of people if they have an answer to your problem. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness is one of the most powerful things you can do as a human being.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After you make a mistake: wallow in it (really feel it first), forgive yourself, then dance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your job title allows other people to figure out how to work with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gitte Klitgaard AMA: watch this if you miss the hallway track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to hear what's being said, not to respond. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can't read minds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a safe space allows you to feel uncomfortable. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silence is a tool. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sophie Küster: watch this if you're ready to tell your colleagues your big secret&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is strength in showing vulnerability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People want to help you. Let them. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: how am I treating myself?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything worth doing is worth doing poorly. Poorly done is better than not done at all. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gitte Klitgaard &amp;amp; Morgan Ahlström: watch this if you want to get psychological safety in the boardroom and on the roadmap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make time to address psychological safety. Put it on the same level in your team's goals as your product goals. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are role models. We lead by example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More people were uncomfortable giving than receiving code reviews. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ard Kramer: watch this if you're getting burned out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humans have an unrealitic belief in our own influence. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing your testing role doesn't make you popular. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most people looking for confirmation that the software is working. To form a logical proof, we look for evidence that the software doesn't work. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: which circumstances could I control? Did I manage expectations correctly? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm grateful I got to connect with people who keep me going. I'm grateful Agile Testing Days tried to make this work in person. I'm grateful I was able to drop my workshop instead of abaondoning people in breakout rooms to do something they've never done before. I'm grateful the mobbing session I helped organize and facilitate went smoothly. I'm grateful that my job allows me the time and space to be rejunivated by this all. I'm grateful. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>agile-testing-days</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-11-29_agile_testing_days_2020/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SoCraTes UK, August 2020</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-08-02_socrates-uk-august-2020/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After years of envying the tweets and stories from SoCraTes conferences, this cursèd disease finally made attending one possible. I could afford the time (part of one day, instead of a whole weekend + travel) and the cost (£2.50, instead of €€€). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm preparing to host an open space of our own in September (&lt;a href="http://testcraftcamp.nl/"&gt;TestCraftCamp&lt;/a&gt;, tickets are free!), so aside from the sessions, I was also interested in the infrastructure of the event. The hosts hung out in one central Zoom room (a one-month subscription cost them £10). Each attendee was appointed co-host, allowing us to move around among the many breakout rooms as we pleased. (There may have been as many breakout rooms as there were participants, named with varying levels of creativity but functionally the same.) A &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/"&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; board captured the user-generated schedule, along with links to the &lt;a href="https://www.mural.co/"&gt;Mural&lt;/a&gt; whiteboards the organizers created for each room, rather than for each session. Chat happened in a &lt;a href="https://discord.com/"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; channel, but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1287372791168278529"&gt;I wouldn't recommend it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first session I attended was a discussion about the value and hazards of leaving a job. First: decide where you want to go, what kind of thing you're looking for. You're not going to get where you want to go by running away from your current role. Run &lt;em&gt;towards&lt;/em&gt; something. Have honest conversations with your peers, manager, mentor, coach, etc. about what change you can affect at the organization. (Things like the nature of the product, the tech stack, or the customer base are unlikely to change quickly.) If you do decide to change jobs, it will take a lot of energy to find something new and build your network at the new place. You may have to prove yourself all over again, and solve the problems you've already solved with this different group of people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After taking a total of three bullet points in my notebook, the host of the second session I attended about hypergrowth was having trouble taking notes and listening to/facilitating the session. I volunteered to jump in to take the notes. Here's what I made:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/hypergrowth.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Notes from hypergrowth session"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Notes from hypergrowth session&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was trying to capture what people said, change the background colors, and move the notes around to put similar ideas next to each other. It was hard to know in the moment whether all of that is legible or helpful for anyone else. Luckily people in the session and in the Discord channel later thanked me for my work. I'm still struggling with how to impart any note-taking skill onto others, particularly when this can be seen as a gendered task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men: Wow, you are so good at taking notes!&lt;br&gt;
Me: You would be too if you got stuck being the one doing it all the time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I digress, back to hypergrowth: The things that worked before COVID and at smaller orgs don't work at a bigger org today. Find your people within the smaller org - your department, your mentor, your friends - so you can feel stable even as things around you grow and change. Communicate your expectations clearly, for yourself and for your team. Keep a journal of what you've accomplished to feel more anchored in the value of your work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch, I started off in the wrong room because I didn't notice the sessions had been moved, but found my way to the one about coaching your peers. The conversation floated from a definition of terms to how to make space for mentoring. In order for people to mentor, there must be consent from the mentee. Ideally there is also some expertise in the organization around what is good, and someone (mentor or not) to teach the mentee what is good. The conversation reminded me of a talk I saw from Marianne Duijst; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vXIZpe-x4o8?t=595"&gt;here's the moment she started talking about the difference between coaches, sponsors, teachers, and role models, and how they can support you in different ways&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anytime Maaret Pyhäjärvi is running an exploratory testing session, go to it. You will be better for it. This time, we tested a simple web application. We ended up spending most of the time adding scenarios to the automated tests Maaret had already set up in Robot framework. One of the questions it brought up for me: do you leave failed tests in your automation suite to highlight unexpected behavior? I had this problem this week: I'd updated a schema to validate against the current behavior while the story was in progress, instead of the behavior we wanted when it was done, so I could verify other fields in the output. Next time I think I'll separate them into two tests and leave them both as pending (marked as xfail in the pytest framework) so it's clear something needs to change before the software is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the SoCraTes organizers for, as I learned a coach does, holding this space for us to examine ourselves and reflect. As someone who is much more fluent in emoji than GIF, I'm grateful to have won the hearts of the participants with this "leting the cat out of the bag" GIF in the GIF challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://media1.tenor.com/images/e49bc18b66056a71171ae6f16046a2a4/tenor.gif?itemid=11543319" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Cat aggressively jumping out of a backpack"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Cat aggressively jumping out of a backpack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>note-taking</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-08-02_socrates-uk-august-2020/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TestBash Netherlands 2019</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-14_testbash_netherlands_2019/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In reviewing my notes from the TestBash Netherlands that occurred in May of 2019, two big, related themes jump out at me: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep exploratory testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn by sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Brown gave a talk about human factors in highly automated systems. As flying airplanes becomes more automated, pilots know less about how to switch to manual overrides in a time of crisis. You might not have more than a few hours a year of practice for when things go down. Continuing to share stories from the past and learn from them is one way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Godtesen"&gt;Gitte Ottosen&lt;/a&gt;, who gave us a tester's perspective on Agile, learning never ends. Understanding the customer journey and tying your work back to the business value are essential for making informed decisions about what to test, and which subset of those things to automate. Teaching, knowledge-sharing, coaching, and pairing can get the whole team involved in advancing quality, even if they're not all strong exploratory testers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JitGo"&gt;Jit Gosai&lt;/a&gt; spoke about continuous testing. Practice test-driven development, story mapping, and three amigos meetings before the code is written. Improve automation test suites, use exploratory and mob testing, and incorporate feedback from the customer. When you're exploratory testing, you're not just confirming that the software functions as expected, you're testing the goal of your whole organization. Jit found that getting everybody on the team exploratory testing caught more bugs than automated tests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MaritvanDijk77"&gt;Marit van Dijk&lt;/a&gt; hit the nail on the head with her talk: keep exploratory testing. Maintaining a consistent state of test data across mutliple teams is difficult. Rather than spend your time setting up control mechanisms for those systems, explore the systems themselves. Bugs are found not in the things we can control or know about, but in the space between systems. Pairing a developer with a tester was a lot faster than testing solo, because nobody had to go back and reproduce bugs. Spread the risk across systems by hooking them up one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VeraGeBa"&gt;Vera Gehlen-Baum&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/isleoftesting"&gt;Beren Van Daele&lt;/a&gt; spoke about incorporating your learning into your backlog. Identify what you want to learn, and write actionable acceptance criteria for your learning. This should include sharing what you've learned individually or with the team; it doesn't have to be confined to same sprint as the work for the team. Linking personal goals to business goals will ensure that people see they're improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/j19sch"&gt;Joep Schuurkes&lt;/a&gt; talked us through what he was thinking as he was live-coding, which is learning and sharing at the most granular level. Separate concerns when you automate: keep what the code is supposed to accomplish separate from how it's accomplishing it. He expanded the CRUD heuristic that helps me decide what to automate, and added an extra DERR to make it CRUDDERR to ensure you can also debug, explore, run, and report on your code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Annosofie"&gt;Anne Colder&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VinWijNL"&gt;Vincent Wijnen&lt;/a&gt; gave an experience report about their mentor-mentee relationship. Mentoring is different from teaching. Ask questions about your mentee's experience, and expect different questions from them than you'd receive from your more experienced colleagues. Mentoring stimulates reflection on both sides. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drew Pontikis spoke about the illusion of control. Challenge your own thinking by listening to new voices. Recognize when you can affect change in a situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/QualityFrog"&gt;Ben Simo&lt;/a&gt; gave the last talk of the day about the art of scientific investigation. Design your next experiment based on your previous ones, and adapt as you go along. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a whole slew of 99-second talks, but the only memorable and explicable thing I wrote down from them was something Ilena said: "Understand your team doesn't function the way that you do." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day prior to the day of talks, I helped facilitate and debrief a workshop that Joep Schuurkes developed around building an API testing framework. It was the first time we'd given it together, so that whole day was a 'learn by sharing' experience for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>testbash</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-14_testbash_netherlands_2019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Humans Conf, June 2020</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-12_humans_conf_june_2020/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found Humans Conf on Twitter, and found myself in a position to attend when &lt;em&gt;gestures at the general state of the world&lt;/em&gt; moved it online. You can check out the output from the entire open space on the &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/June-2nd-2020-Virtual-Open-Space-26d1d0595b4b4574baf647025f3be544"&gt;Notion page&lt;/a&gt;. It took place for a few hours on a Tuesday night. I discovered the energy it takes to listen and participate attentively in the evening affected my work for the following couple of days. I am only human!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first session I attended was about making diversity more inclusive, and hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/buggylina"&gt;Lina Zubyte&lt;/a&gt;. Due to the makeup of the participants, the conversation veered towards being a woman in tech. We spoke about incorrect assumptions, how we felt about particular language (especially &lt;code&gt;guys&lt;/code&gt;), and how much energy that drains from us all the time. I heard stories from other women that echoed situations from my experience. I recognized how telling a story from a memorably bad day helps others understand and connect. I pondered if there's a way to make people understand, without reliving everyday indignities. My takeaway from the conversation was clear: you get to decide how to spend your energy. There will be people whose minds need changing, but the energy you would expend making that happen wouldn't be worth it. Let those people who challenge the premises of the problem space fall off your radar, and invest in people where you can make a difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second session, I started off in motivating interactions, hosted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/innoviva"&gt;Maren Baermann&lt;/a&gt;. I truly enjoyed the model she introduced regarding &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-determination_theory#Motivations"&gt;extrinsic vs. intrinsic motivation&lt;/a&gt;, and tying those to our &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-determination_theory#Basic_needs_and_intrinsic_motivation"&gt;basic needs&lt;/a&gt;. But when the Zoom gods kicked me out of the free room, I took it as a sign to go search for a less interactive session where I could just listen. I landed in a session relating couples therapy to your team dynamics, hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DariaDorda"&gt;Daria Dorda&lt;/a&gt;. The conversation covered some national stereotypes, how people get distracted from the real message, and how to get the necessary distance to engage with a topic. My takeaway here was: if you don't set boundaries, others will for you. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm grateful to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/benjamin"&gt;Benjamin Reitzammer&lt;/a&gt; who hosted the open space, and all the others who made it run smoothly. Seeing just a handful of familiar faces set me at ease. I'd never seen Zoom chat used effectively, but the rush of answers to the closing questions at the end of the evening gave me that warm &amp;amp; fuzzy feeling like I'd actually attended a conference in person. I needed that, so thank you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think I can bring myself to join the next Humans Conf on Wednesday, 15 July. I've got a week off, and I need some time away from Zoom to be feeling more human. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>humans</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-12_humans_conf_june_2020/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Test Automation Day 2018</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-13_test_automation_day_2018/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a free ticket to Test Automation Day in 2018, just after I'd moved to Rotterdam. I was overwhelmed by the confluence of events: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/techgirl1908"&gt;Angie Jones&lt;/a&gt; keynoting, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ard_kramer"&gt;Ard Kramer&lt;/a&gt; running the show, and meeting &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/amyjph"&gt;Amy Phillips&lt;/a&gt; in real life. (Neither of us were sure it was the first time we'd met because we'd been following each other on Twitter for so long!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most shocking note from Angie's keynote is "clicker, no notes," because of course Angie had her talk down pat. In a talk that anticipated the current, urgent conversation in AI and machine learning, Angie recognized that we can't agree on what human ethics should look like. Figure out who you're advocating for, and tie the bugs back to that business value. You're not going to be able to define all the business requirements up front; expect the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy Phillips spoke about how tests in a DevOps environemnt allow you to get fast feedback. Like Agile, this style of working is not about minimizing the pain and struggle in developing software, but rather about bringing that pain forward. DevOps allows us to become aware of problems sooner, so we can act on them sooner. Running more tests is not necessarily better. Do not accept flaky tests. Free yourself from an overreliance on end-to-end tests and tests that cover non-critical paths to get your build time down. Rather than running tests on every commit, improve your monitoring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got some quotes from other talks and the panel that day: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"A tester is someone who believes things can be different." ~ Jerry Weinberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The team was not mature enough to determine priorities."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Maintain the relationships you want to build."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Are you just doing it because you can?" (regarding UI automation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't tell everybody how welcome and in the right place I felt by being able to jump in this day on short notice. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>automation</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-13_test_automation_day_2018/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TestBash Home (Spring 2020)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-05-03_testbash-home/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typing to the people you usually see in person can have the same energy as tweeting at them from across a big room. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/events/testbash-home-2020"&gt;TestBash Home&lt;/a&gt;, put on by the &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/"&gt;Ministry of Testing&lt;/a&gt;, was a 24-hour around-the-world tour of talks, panels, and coaching from the best of the best. I &lt;del&gt;missed&lt;/del&gt; purposely and prudently skipped a big chunk of the schedule to get a good night's sleep and properly absorb what I could attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was definitely overloaded with places to chat (Slack, the video streaming app Crowdcast, Twitter, or &lt;a href="https://tbhome.herokuapp.com/"&gt;the app built for the occasion&lt;/a&gt;) simultaneously with the video stream, the same way I would be at an in-person conference. I got that same "I want to hang out more but I'm so tired" feeling I get in real life. Though as Gwen correctly noted, this is real life now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cost-Benefit of Automated Tests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jrosaproenca"&gt;João Proença&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mgreiler"&gt;Michaela Greiler&lt;/a&gt; weighed the costs and benefits of continually updating and running automated tests. Coming from two different angles (cognitive biases vs. Ph.D.-level number-crunching), they shared a similar quadrant model to make better decisions about your automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/joao-quadrants.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="João's model on my actual TV screen"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;João's model on my actual TV screen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/michaela-quadrants.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Michaela's model"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Michaela's model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;João took a stronger "if it's not providing value, do something about it" approach, whether that's editing the test or deleting it altogether. He asked us to consider: If you were asked to write the same test from scratch today, would you do it the same way? When you need fast feedback, what's the opportunity cost of fixing, or even just running, a particular test? João reminded us to ask "what is being tested?" and decide if that still matters before jumping in to fix a failing test. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michaela brought a perspective from a much larger software company (Microsoft) than I've worked at before. Her approach left open another option for the fate of tests with questionable value: only run them at certain stages. Only run the tests now where the cost of running them at a later stage is too high. Running tests at the wrong stage can increase false alarms and diagnosis time. Running tests that exercise unchanged code should be avoided. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/michaela-quadrants.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Michaela's stages"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Michaela's stages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Learning &amp;amp; Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/witchofthetest"&gt;Veerle Verhagen&lt;/a&gt;'s 99-second talk got me rethinking some learning experiences I've had. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It boiled down to this: learning is easy and teaching is hard. Try everything you've had trouble learning again, but with a better teacher this time. Whoa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Evil User Stories&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every security talk I've heard tells you to look at the &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/www-project-top-ten/"&gt;OWASP Top 10&lt;/a&gt; and make a threat model. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Anne_Oikarinen"&gt;Anne Oikarinen&lt;/a&gt; told us what to do next: make an evil user story. If I were a person who made a mistake, shouldn't have access at all, or received more access to the system than anticipated, what would happen? How could we mitigate those risks? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your team doesn't know where to start with web security, Anne suggested adding static code analysis tools and exploratory testing to your practice. If you've got outside penetration testers exploring your software, add logging around the issues they trigger so you know better what's happening next time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/minimaxir/big-list-of-naughty-strings/blob/master/blns.txt"&gt;big list of naughty strings&lt;/a&gt; to test for security vulnerabilities I don't always completely understand. Anne also recommended &lt;a href="https://www.hacker101.com/"&gt;Hacker 101&lt;/a&gt;, a free class about web security. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Live Coaching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/workroomprds"&gt;James Lyndsay&lt;/a&gt;'s coaching session reminded me how valuable gathering information and stepping back to ask "what will I learn by performing this test?" are when you're stuck. I've got to go back to my notes from a workshop I took with him a couple years ago to reinforce some of these lessons for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Continuous Delivery Survival Guide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/amyjph"&gt;Amy Phillips&lt;/a&gt; might be the first person I met where neither of us could remember if we'd met in person before, or if we just knew each other from Twitter. Her talk about surviving continuous delivery from 2017 lives on an essential onboarding guide for testers today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy wants you to have enough context about your new team and their values before you jump into ideas about what you could change. People probably won't come to you to hand things over for the testing phase, so you have to figure out for yourself where you fit into their process. Amy recommended what I think of as "digital archaeology": reading through all the team artifacts to get a sense of their culture. Even if you don't get write access, looking at the customer support tickets, team backlog, and git commits can show you how the team actually works, rather than how they tell you they should work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy really made me laugh when she described learning about the different development environments. Ask what the developers use. Ask what sales uses. Ask how many environments there are, how they're different, and what people's expectations are around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can ask questions without knowing what a good answer is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even without knowing how to implement something, you can ask questions about it to trigger developers' wheels to start turning. Looking at the structure of the code and what's been changed may give you ideas about what hasn't been covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Burnout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maryamumar"&gt;Maryam Umar&lt;/a&gt; spoke about being burned out from juggling too many priorities, combined with unmedicated anxiety. Maryam called out how difficult it can be to start from scratch and build a support network when you relocate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/failure-garden.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Seemed appropriate to watch this one from the garden"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Seemed appropriate to watch this one from the garden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worried a lot about building a support network before I relocated, but not much since. I'm so glad I've been able to recognize the "this is too much" feeling for myself. Saying no to big but overwhelming opportunities has left space in my life for things I know I want, and greener pastures I couldn't have imagined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Leadership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leadership panel made me want to have &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nicolasedgwick"&gt;Nicola Sedgwick&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/testchick"&gt;Alessandra Moreira&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SheyMouse"&gt;Shey Compton&lt;/a&gt; in my corner as I transition to a manager position. Obviously (to me at this point in my career and after various other trainings I've participated in) leaders do not have to be people managers, and vice versa. People need to give you permission to lead them. Leaders have a vision they can communicate up and down the chain of command. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to be a leader is to lead by example. Sponsor other people at your organization who you see can be better leaders. Having the technical chops will allow people to believe in your value. It's easy for testers to underestimate our ability to influence behavior, but bug advocacy is a lot about that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicola's framework for sharing feedback is something I'm defintely going to try in a 1-on-1 meeting this week: share an observation, recount the accompanying behavior, and describe the impact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Morale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jennydoesthings"&gt;Jenny Bramble&lt;/a&gt; spoke about bad and good metrics, specifically that morale was the only good one. Morale encompasses psychological safety, emotional health, contentment, pride, deilght, and core values. It's hard to measure, but that also means it's hard to game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your team isn't one where people can have negative emotions, disagree, or talk about mistakes or risks, you're doing it wrong. Genuinely asking people how it's going and taking action on the results is the best thing you can do to improve morale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/survey-questions.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Possible survey questions to help measure morale"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Possible survey questions to help measure morale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to Jenny's proposed next talk about the oral history of bugs on teams. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Titles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd seen this talk from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vds4"&gt;Martin Hynie&lt;/a&gt; on the Ministry of Testing Dojo, and worked with Martin in the past. So I was expecting to be reminded that testing isn't a straightforward observe -&amp;gt; evaluate -&amp;gt; report operation. I'd seen him take on challenges  outside the perceived role of tester, and I'd done so myself. I knew that it's easier to create a good artifact if you start by creating an imperfect one and ask people to correct it, rather than starting from scratch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest takeaway was in the Q&amp;amp;A: Someone's association and past experiences of people with my job title are more meaningful than the job title itself in setting up my working relationship with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optimism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite 99-second talk from the second set was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jen_kitson"&gt;Jen Kitson&lt;/a&gt;'s about optimism. While we discover and often have to report a lot of bad news as testers, optimism is essential to testing. We notice things, report bugs, and pushing for fixes because we can imagine a world that can be better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm so glad I got to attend TestBash Home. I would listen to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TesterFromLeic"&gt;Vernon Richards&lt;/a&gt; talk about sports balls I don't understand. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gwendiagram"&gt;Gwen Diagram&lt;/a&gt; gives me life and energy in a way that I cannot fully explain. There were people I got to see or chat with that I haven't encountered for months, or years, and it felt good. It felt like home. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>testbash</category><category>testbinge</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-05-03_testbash-home/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Remembering TestBash Brighton 2018</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-04-19_remembering_testbash_brighton-2018/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;TestBash Brighton was one of 10,000 things I had to do in the weeks just before I left my whole life (family, friends, job, apartment, belongings) and moved across the ocean into the unknown. It was the first place I'd gotten to share that big news in person, with people who would become larger parts of my life once I moved. Visiting the city where I'd studied during university and first thought "I could leave the United States" brought things full circle for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I paired on presenting a brand-new workshop and talk, with two different people. This would have been a lot, even without all the uncertaincies and distractions swirling in my life those days. After hustling to adjust the schedule of and present our morning workshop, I distinctly remember choosing to skip the afternoon one I'd planned on attending in order to fill out immigration and relocation paperwork. I'm shocked to find I was able to focus enough on some other peoples' talks to take coherent notes about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/pavilion.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Royal Pavilion in downtown Brighton"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Royal Pavilion in downtown Brighton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anusha_n"&gt;Anusha Nirmalananthan&lt;/a&gt;'s talk about sharing a chronic illness sticks with me today. One of the things I love to jump into is troubleshooting. I hear about a problem, and I'm already thinking of ways to solve it, and asking about what you've tried already. Anusha reminded us that listening and not saying anything can be more helpful and powerful than all the patronizing "Have you tried...?" questions in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ewebber"&gt;Emily Weber&lt;/a&gt; spoke about communities of practice, which have always been billed as "guilds" in places where I've worked. Emily encouraged us to connect with people around our organizations in our discipline in a supportive, voluntary group without a hierarchy or an end date. While the occasional guild meeting I've attended has turned into a groan-fest, dedicating time and energy to fostering change (to code, to job descriptions, to your team's way of working, etc.) gives me that "I did something today" feeling. I'm grateful to be able to make time to learn with my colleagues, and build a support network for when I need advice from outside the bubble of my team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Rosicadia"&gt;Rosie Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;'s talk about logic in testing because it drove me back to the basics. How do we decide what is true? How do I describe my thought process? When the availability of relevant cases prevents effective inductive reasoning (determining a heuristic), we have to move to abductive reasoning (determining the likeliest explanation from the available information). Realizing when you're doing this and what other information might be available to you elevates your testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/logic.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back at my notes from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AWGHodder"&gt;Aaron Hodder&lt;/a&gt;'s talk on structured exploratory testing make me realize how much freedom I can have in my testing when working with an inattentive team. His suggestions about making for easier reporting, fewer rabbit holes, and predictability of a time-table suggest that someone is really breathing down your neck about the status, progress, and depth of your work. The biggest advantage I've had in sharing my testing charters with my team is that I find out which ones aren't valuable before I spend time executing them. Actively choosing not to test something when we don't care about the outcome or the risk it poses is very effective work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alanpage"&gt;Alan Page&lt;/a&gt; spoke about the modern testing principles he'd been shaping on his podcast for a while. My notes boil it down to: testers should do less testing and more coaching. This has certainly served me on teams producing too much for me to personally go as deep as I'd like in testing, but it also pays off when I'm out of the office or unavailable at the office. Working on a team that knows how to test means I get to look at higher-quality code, with more interesting bugs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/northern_tester"&gt;Ash Winter&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk immediately after mine, so perhaps I did not gather everything from it. But I did save these tid-bits: a pipeline is built to prove that something shouldn't go out. A pipeline can provide a massive amount of information, but without a strategy, too much data doesn't help humans make better decisions. Small things you can do to make huge improvements: deploy regularly, and learn source control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the open space, the social events, and the atmosphere at TestBash Brighton 2018 makes me wish for the experience we all missed at the now-cancelled event in 2020. Jumping into the unknown seemed so doable when I knew there'd be so many people to share with and learn from on this side of the Atlantic. I don't know when I'll see you all again, but I look forward to that possibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/stamner.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Can't go to Britain without a proper tea"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Can't go to Britain without a proper tea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>testbash</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-04-19_remembering_testbash_brighton-2018/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Reflecting on Let’s Test 2017</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2019/2019-09-15_reflecting-on-let-s-test-2017/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="f2d3" id="f2d3" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;Good ideas come back around. As I sit here re-reading my notes from Let’s Test 2017, I remember the thrill of coming across so many new ideas there, and realize how much these three things stick out to me even now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/valley-lodge.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Valley Lodge &amp;amp; Spa, Magaliesburg, South Africa"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Valley Lodge &amp;amp; Spa, Magaliesburg, South Africa&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="dc01" id="dc01" class="graf graf--li graf-after--figure"&gt;Causal loop diagrams&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p name="1b99" id="1b99" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;It’s possible I’d seen a causal loop disgram before, but it wasn’t until I went to Jo Perold and Barry Tandy’s “Visualize your way to better problem solving” workshop that I knew the name for them. &lt;a href="https://www.isixsigma.com/tools-templates/cause-effect/causal-loop-diagrams-little-known-analytical-tool/" data-href="https://www.isixsigma.com/tools-templates/cause-effect/causal-loop-diagrams-little-known-analytical-tool/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Here’s an example of how connecting nouns with verbs via bubbles and letters really clears things up.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="0c13" id="0c13" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;During the workshop, Jo and Barry talked about how drawing a diagram of your software in this way can help you discover interaction points between systems. Sharing the diagram is one way to take the invisible software you’re building into a visible space. That allows us to have a conversation about the model, discover if we’re on the same page, and take steps to improve the model and ultimately the software. The more visualizations I see of process and influence on the job, the more I realize they’re exposing &lt;a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/articles/demystifying-conways-law" data-href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/articles/demystifying-conways-law" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Conway’s Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="b91d" id="b91d" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Elisabeth Hendrickson wrote in &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15980494-explore-it" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15980494-explore-it" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Explore It!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; &lt;/em&gt;about how causal loop diagrams can help you discover interesting areas to test. She pointed out that transitions from one state to another take time, and there’s lots to be discovered during the moments of transition about interruptions, errors, and incomplete states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/causal-loop.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title='Repenning, Nelson &amp;amp; Sterman, John. (2003). "Nobody Ever Gets Credit for Fixing Problems That Never Happened: Creating and Sustaining Process Improvement." Engineering Management Review, IEEE. 30. 64- 64. 10.1109/EMR.2002.1167285.'&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Repenning, Nelson &amp;amp; Sterman, John. (2003). "Nobody Ever Gets Credit for Fixing Problems That Never Happened: Creating and Sustaining Process Improvement." Engineering Management Review, IEEE. 30. 64- 64. 10.1109/EMR.2002.1167285.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="5105" id="5105" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;Nelson Repenning and John Sterman used a causal loop diagram to display a human problem: not prioritizing time for improving. Read their whole article to discover terrifying news about how much time you’re wasting all the time by not stopping to improve!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="50d2" id="50d2" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;2. Metaphors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="c76c" id="c76c" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Leo Hepis and Danie Roux’s “Frames at Work” workshop blew my mind. I would tell you they were talking about how metaphors and context framing shape the way we think about our work. And they did that. But the meandering and level of lost I felt on our path there was unprecedented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/rope.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Our table selected “Rope of Awesome” and I stand by that answer."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Our table selected “Rope of Awesome” and I stand by that answer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="e4cd" id="e4cd" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;One of the exercises had us listening to a story about someone’s work and only writing down the metaphors. There seemed to be one every sentence, so many that I thought the speaker was throwing them in there on purpose. (See: &lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;throwing&lt;/em&gt;. They’re everywhere!) He talked about “pulling” and “dragging” his team along. Imagine instead if he were “pushing” or “building” his team. How would he think differently about his work? How different would his work be? Listen more closely to the words people are using to discover terrifying news about how they perceive their work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="bff4" id="bff4" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;3. Reflection and Learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="b1ad" id="b1ad" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Alison Gitelson hosted a session to help the conference attendees think more about what they’d just learned. I was still reeling from the metaphors and framing session, so I wrote down these questions for myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="00fe" id="00fe" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;How do I realize when I’m stuck inside my own head?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="48ba" id="48ba" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Does noticing where a behavior would be useful make it less irritating?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="248b" id="248b" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Was there a better discussion because active disagreement was encouraged?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="0165" id="0165" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Who in my life can help me reframe?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="9408" id="9408" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Why do I feel my effort has to achieve something?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p name="3b02" id="3b02" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;Reflect on these questions yourself for terrifying news about how stuck you can be sometimes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/double-rainbow.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Very slight double rainbow to the right."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Very slight double rainbow to the right.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/reflecting-on-lets-test-2017-efb52723598c"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2019/2019-09-15_reflecting-on-let-s-test-2017/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Agile Testing Days 2018: A Reflection</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2019/2019-07-07_agile-testing-days-2018-a-reflection/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="4f54" id="4f54" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;I was beyond excited to attend Agile Testing Days in Potsdam, Germany for the first time a year and a half ago. Anywhere I went, I met women who I’d previously only known from the internet. It was refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="bd6a" id="bd6a" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Based on the pages of notes I’ve got, I can tell you that the lessons I took away from that week have seeped into the way I work everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="14da" id="14da" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Humans should not be regression testing.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="d815" id="d815" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jezhumble" data-href="https://twitter.com/jezhumble" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jez Humble&lt;/a&gt; kicked off the conference with a session about continuous delivery. He described the barriers of organizational culture and software architecture that can prevent you from getting to a point where you can deliver continuously. Previous places where I worked made this feel like an insurmountable feat; now when I imagine continuous delivery, I can imagine concrete steps we could take to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="0481" id="0481" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Let’s create a small habit everyday to trigger me to learn more.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7bbd" id="7bbd" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke" data-href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lisi Hocke&lt;/a&gt; certainly took this idea from her talk and ran with it. She’s been pair testing remotely with people around the world and learning so much from it. I’ve taken pairing on a smaller scale, with my colleagues or in-person. There are still times when it tests my patience, but the benefits of being able to more precisely explain what I’m doing and what I expect of the software vastly outweigh that investment. All my notes from Lisi’s talk have me nodding my head, like these are the most obvious things in the world. The biggest I’d come across about a year beforehand: having a growth mindset rather than a fixed mindset. &lt;a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2014/01/29/carol-dweck-mindset/" data-href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2014/01/29/carol-dweck-mindset/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;This explanation from Brain Pickings sticks with me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/sanssouci-palace.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Sanssouci Palace in Potsdam."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Sanssouci Palace in Potsdam.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name="f3ae" id="f3ae" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure"&gt;“I am curious why they’re doing what they do.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7ad0" id="7ad0" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NativeWired" data-href="https://twitter.com/NativeWired" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gitte Klitgaard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andreasschliep" data-href="https://twitter.com/andreasschliep" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Andreas Schliep&lt;/a&gt; had an improvised conversation about good and evil. You know, like you do with your friends for fun, but on stage. It can be so hard to believe that people are acting with good intentions at heart. But remembering to have empathy for the situations people find themselves in will help you choose to be the person to repair relationships when things go awry. If you believe in people, they can be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="c286" id="c286" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“People don’t want to collaborate with you when you have twelve spreadsheets for them to go through.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7691" id="7691" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;I’m sure &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/techgirl1908" data-href="https://twitter.com/techgirl1908" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Angie Jones&lt;/a&gt; had other, more profound takeaways from her talk. But this one sticks to my bones. I think of it anytime I open a spreadsheet with more than one sheet in it. I think of it when I’m deciding on a tool to use, and wondering not what’s easiest for me to set up, but what’s easiest for my fellow collaborators to use. Thank you for this gem Angie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/sanssouci-park.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Some dramatic structure in Sanssouci Park."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Some dramatic structure in Sanssouci Park.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name="f5ac" id="f5ac" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure"&gt;“Get ready to fire people to maintain the culture you want.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="f967" id="f967" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/poornima" data-href="https://twitter.com/poornima" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Poornima Vijayashanker&lt;/a&gt; spoke about concrete ways to successfully onboard new employees. But I’m curious about this provocative statement. I haven’t ever worked at a place bold enough to get rid of managers whose direct reports displayed a pattern of escaping them that no one could ignore. I wonder what kind of company is bold enough to take this step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="deaf" id="deaf" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Only put off until tomorrow what you are willing to die having left undone.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="c0ca" id="c0ca" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Punkmik" data-href="https://twitter.com/Punkmik" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kim Knup&lt;/a&gt; said Pablo Picasso came up with this doozie. At my first job, we used a physical board with sticky notes. If the sticky note had been moved around too many times or stuck in one place too long, it would literally fall off the board. At the time this felt like a failure. Now I see it for the blessing it was. Forgetting is a part of life, even if our digital tools would prefer us to forget that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="af08" id="af08" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Do what you say you will. Integrity is important.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="f653" id="f653" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Rob_Lambert" data-href="https://twitter.com/Rob_Lambert" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Lambert&lt;/a&gt; spoke about behaviors of effective Agile teams. It’s resonating with me again now because it’s something I’m addressing in a talk I’m giving about how to build trust. I’m digging into authenticity, which I think goes a step beyond integrity. Doing what you say you will is being externally congruent. Authentic people are also internally congruent; the vision they have of themselves is the one they present to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/downtown.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="I forget what this is but it’s across from the museum downtown and damn the light was lovely."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;I forget what this is but it’s across from the museum downtown and damn the light was lovely.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name="7969" id="7969" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure"&gt;“If you never get feedback, you have one year of experience ten times.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="a539" id="a539" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;This came out in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots" data-href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Huib Schoots&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alex_schl" data-href="https://twitter.com/alex_schl" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Alex Schladebeck&lt;/a&gt;’s workshop on dissecting your testing and discovering the skills present in your exploratory testing. We practiced observing the skills we were using on the meta-level. It allowed me to both see and share how much a year of mob testing for an hour every day had expanded at least two things. First: my field of vision for how to dig and explore software had grown. Second: I was able to explain what I was thinking such that the other people present could understand, contribute to, and question which path we’d take next. It was life-affirming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="b8f8" id="b8f8" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“When we set our own limits, we can change them.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="c8b4" id="c8b4" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;This came up in the context of Natalie Wenert’s talk about cross-team functionality. She chided organizations for relying on hero-worship and fire-fighting over breaking down silos and contributing to the whole. One of my conference buddies was frustrated at Agile Testing Days because they viewed so much of the content as “work therapy.” They weren’t wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="e6da" id="e6da" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“As a user, I want to be locked out of the system after three incorrect password attempts.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="1723" id="1723" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidEvans66" data-href="https://twitter.com/DavidEvans66" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Evans&lt;/a&gt; presented a memorable talk about how the template we stick to for writing user stories does not serve us well. This particular example made me laugh out loud. This story gets the “why” wrong. It’s about security of our system and the user’s data. Being honest about why we’re building the software would make the user story less absurd, and hopefully get us on the path to making better software too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/barberini.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="This doozie is in the Museum Barberini, which is worth checking out if you're in Potsdam."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;This doozie is in the Museum Barberini, which is worth checking out if you're in Potsdam.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name="710c" id="710c" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure"&gt;“Uncertainty is more stressful than inevitable pain.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7f33" id="7f33" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ewebber" data-href="https://twitter.com/ewebber" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Emily Webber&lt;/a&gt; spoke about team interactions and organizational change. (Shout out to all the people who’ve tweet me instead of this other brown-haired white lady with glasses!) I’m on my fifth team in a year at my current company. I’m tired of the change. I know how important it is to build relationships with the people you work with. I’ve expressed that knowing who’s on my team is more important than having the perfect set of people. I look forward to more stability there because I don’t envy the alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="fc3c" id="fc3c" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Mistakes were made.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7aee" id="7aee" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lunivore" data-href="https://twitter.com/lunivore" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Liz Keogh&lt;/a&gt; spoke about how to deliver failure messages. Her message was essentially: don’t. Pointing out the mistake without pointing fingers is enough. Encourage good existing behavior and create more options so that failure can occur safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="20f1" id="20f1" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Are we advocating for those doing a good job?”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="2163" id="2163" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote graf--trailing"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AshColeman30" data-href="https://twitter.com/AshColeman30" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ash Coleman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keithklain" data-href="https://twitter.com/keithklain" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/a&gt; had a late-night after-dinner (over-hyphenated?) bonus-keynote to talk about how culture is a mindset and what we can do to change it. They encouraged allies in the majority to stop talking, and start listening, so you can do something. If you’re uncomfortable, good. You’re learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/agile-testing-days-2017-a-reflection-2ea505b09eec"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2019/2019-07-07_agile-testing-days-2018-a-reflection/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nurture the Bright Spots: Dutch Exploratory Workshop on Testing 2018</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2019/2019-02-09_nuture-the-bright-spots-dutch-exploratory-workshop-on-testing-2018/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="ec08" id="ec08" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;A peer conference is different from a regular conference. If you’re one of the lucky few to get invited, you find yourself in an environment surrounded by the best and the brightest. There will be presentations to spark a discussion, but the facilitated discussion is where the real learning occurs. It certainly puts the “confer” back in conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="3a66" id="3a66" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;The Dutch Exploratory Workshop on Testing (or DEWT for short, rhymes with newt) in the fall of 2018 was the first one of these I attended outside of work. The theme was “Developing expertise in software testing.” The format of the gathering itself paired nicely with one of the main conclusions I took away from the weekend: choose the best people, foster an environment where they have the energy to learn and inspire others, and set aside time to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2019/sunrise.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Gorgeous sunrise on our morning run"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Gorgeous sunrise on our morning run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section name="c8e6" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="05d9" id="05d9" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;Here are some of the things I think about at least once a week back at work:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote name="64ce" id="64ce" class="graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“You let people annoy you by not pushing back.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p name="bc0e" id="bc0e" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;People cannot read your mind. If something is bothering you and you never bring it up, how are they supposed to figure it out? Try to find something small to be firm about, and build from there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote name="b78d" id="b78d" class="graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“People relax when you say it’s time-boxed.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p name="0706" id="0706" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;Sometimes I’d rather stop fighting than win. I think it’s clear that a bug should be investigated, but someone else believes it’s not worth any time. Instead of deciding yes or no based on insufficient information, I’ve found “let’s look at this for two hours and decide if we should keep going” gets more people on board and allows the conversation to move on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote name="1d71" id="1d71" class="graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“When you ask a difficult question, sometimes people ask a simpler question in their head and answer that.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p name="de86" id="de86" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote graf--trailing"&gt;One of the questions I was trying to help answer this week was “should we release next week?” The team and I found it easier to answer adjacent questions instead of the big one we needed. We could find answers to “are there pieces of work we need to complete before the release?”, “are those pieces of work estimated?”, “could the tests that aren’t passing expose risk to our company’s bottom line?”. I can see how some of the answers to these smaller questions can support an answer to the larger one. My worry is that getting “yes, this is fine” to something small will accidentally result in a “yes, this is fine” to the overall question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section name="9449" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="546a" id="546a" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;I don’t have more to add or break down regarding these thoughts, but I can tell you that I nodded knowingly when they were said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="38b9" id="38b9" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Regression sprint.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="59d9" id="59d9" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“I can’t change other people for them.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="bb75" id="bb75" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“If it’s overwhelming, take a smaller step.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="03e4" id="03e4" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“An expert is someone who learns the fastest.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="7532" id="7532" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“My standards are not necessarily ‘the’ standard.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="7aa4" id="7aa4" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“Internal conferences help people see good work.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="d56e" id="d56e" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“As knowledge workers, we are the means of production!”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="c933" id="c933" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“Sometimes you’re only doing enough work not to get fired.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="cc1a" id="cc1a" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li graf--trailing"&gt;“How do I tell you I disagree with you without ending the conversation?”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section name="6858" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="8a07" id="8a07" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;These are the books that were both (a) mentioned explicitly enough for me to find them and (b) worthy of adding to my exponentially-growing Goodreads backlog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="09ef" id="09ef" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8337919-coaching-agile-teams" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8337919-coaching-agile-teams" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;Coaching Agile Teams: A Companion for ScrumMasters, Agile Coaches, and Project Managers in Transition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="aa49" id="aa49" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/571672.The_Satir_Model" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/571672.The_Satir_Model" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;The Satir Model: Family Therapy and Beyond&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="5dfb" id="5dfb" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3090109-how-to-be-an-explorer-of-the-world" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3090109-how-to-be-an-explorer-of-the-world" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;How To Be an Explorer of the World: Portable Life Museum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="4dfb" id="4dfb" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12609433-the-power-of-habit" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12609433-the-power-of-habit" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="a534" id="a534" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6570502-switch?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6570502-switch?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;Switch: How to Change Things When Change Is Hard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name="2ff1" id="2ff1" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li graf--trailing"&gt;(If you’re looking for books you can’t miss about sociology and psychology, follow &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/2204488-maaike" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/2204488-maaike" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Maaike Brinkhof&lt;/a&gt; on Goodreads.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section name="3e2d" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="a362" id="a362" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;The retrospective asked us a big question that I wasn’t prepared to answer in the waning hours of the conference: What were we going to change in our jobs, in our lives, in our coaching of our colleagues when we got back to work on Monday? I only realized later that someone proclaimed a mission statement that I’d like to adopt:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote name="0081" id="0081" class="graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p"&gt;I will bring you discomfort. I will stay critical when everyone else thinks we’re done.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p name="f4e6" id="f4e6" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;I’ll start there. But I’ll also make time. I’ll step back. I’ll think about what you’ve done. Only then can I grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Starting to wonder if the solution to a lot of problems in testing is simply making the world a better and more humane place.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DEWT8?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#DEWT8&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/modestambitions?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#modestambitions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/fixalltehthings?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#fixalltehthings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Joep Schuurkes (@j19sch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/j19sch/status/1053634456534351877?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 20, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="0f62" id="0f62" class="graf graf--p graf--leading graf--trailing"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Thanks to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Arborosa" data-href="https://twitter.com/Arborosa" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Jean-Paul Varwijk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JorisMeerts" data-href="https://twitter.com/JorisMeerts" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Joris Meerts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; for organizing DEWT 2018, and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/klaartjejulia" data-href="https://twitter.com/klaartjejulia" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Klaartje van Zwoll&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ClaireMGoss" data-href="https://twitter.com/ClaireMGoss" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Claire Goss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;, and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Maaikees" data-href="https://twitter.com/Maaikees" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Maaike Brinkhof&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; for reminding me how refreshing peers can be. If you don’t have an entire weekend to discover deep truths with your peers, try watching Vera Gehlen-Baum’s &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/events/a-software-tester-s-guide-to-expertise-vera-gehlen-baum" data-href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/events/a-software-tester-s-guide-to-expertise-vera-gehlen-baum" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;A Software Tester’s Guide to Expertise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; instead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/nuture-the-bright-spots-dutch-exploratory-workshop-on-testing-2018-90c45555ca19"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>DEWT</category><category>peer-conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2019/2019-02-09_nuture-the-bright-spots-dutch-exploratory-workshop-on-testing-2018/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>