<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Software Tester (Posts about conference)</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:8000/categories/conference.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 14:10:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Remembering TestBash Brighton 2018</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2020/2020-04-19_remembering_testbash_brighton-2018/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;TestBash Brighton was one of 10,000 things I had to do in the weeks just before I left my whole life (family, friends, job, apartment, belongings) and moved across the ocean into the unknown. It was the first place I'd gotten to share the news in-person, with people who would become larger parts of my life once I moved here. Visiting the city where I'd studied during university and first thought "I could leave the United States" brought everything together for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I paired on presenting a brand-new workshop and talk, with two different people. This would have been a lot for me even without all the uncertaincies and distractions swirling in my life those days. After hustling to adjust the schedule of and present our morning workshop, I distinctly remember choosing to skip the afternoon one I'd planned on attending in order to fill out immigration and relocation paperwork. I'm shocked to find I was able to focus enough on some other peoples' talks to take coherent notes about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2020/pavilion.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Royal Pavilion in downtown Brighton"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Royal Pavilion in downtown Brighton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anusha_n"&gt;Anusha Nirmalananthan&lt;/a&gt;'s talk about sharing a chronic illness sticks with me today. One of the things I love to jump into is troubleshooting. I hear about a problem, and I'm already thinking of ways to solve it, and asking about what you've tried already. Anusha reminded us that listening and not saying anything can be more helpful and powerful than all the patronizing "Have you tried...?" in the world. I'm glad I have this top-of-mind before I start having 1-on-1 meetings with the members of the team I've just started leading this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ewebber"&gt;Emily Weber&lt;/a&gt; spoke about communities of practice, which have always been billed as "guilds" in places where I've worked. Emily encouraged us to connect with people around our organizations in our discipline in a supportive, voluntary group without a hierarchy or an end date. While the occasional guild meeting has turned into a groan-fest, dedicating time and energy to fostering change (to code, to job descriptions, to your team's way of working) gives me that "I did something today" feeling. I'm grateful to be able to make time to learn with my colleagues, and build a support network for when I need advice from outside the bubble of my team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Rosicadia"&gt;Rosie Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;'s talk about logic in testing because it drove me back to the basics. How do we decide what is true? How do I describe my thought process? When the availability of relevant cases prevents effective inductive reasoning (determining a heuristic), we have to move to abductive reasoning (determining the likeliest explanation from the available information). Realizing when you're doing this and what other information might be available to you elevates your testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2020/logic.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back at my notes from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AWGHodder"&gt;Aaron Hodder&lt;/a&gt;'s talk on structured exploratory testing make me realize how much freedom I can have in my testing when working with an inattentive team. His suggestions about making for easier reporting, fewer rabbit holes, and predictability of a time-table suggest that someone is really breathing down your neck about the status, progress, and depth of your work. The biggest advantage I've had in sharing my testing charters with my team is that I find out which ones aren't valuable before I spend time executing them. Actively choosing not to test something when we don't care about the outcome or the risk it poses is the best use of my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alanpage"&gt;Alan Page&lt;/a&gt; spoke about the modern testing principles he'd been shaping on his podcast for a while. My notes boil it down to: testers should do less testing and more coaching. This has certainly served me on teams producing too much for me to personally go as deep as I'd like in testing, but it also pays off when I'm out of the office or unavailable at the office. Working on a team that knows how to test means I get to look at higher-quality code, with more interesting bugs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the open space, the social events, and the atmosphere at TestBash Brighton 2018 makes me wish for the experience we all missed at the now-cancelled event in 2020. Jumping into the unknown seemed so doable when I knew there'd be so many people to share with and learn from on this side of the Atlantic. I don't know when I'll see you all again, but I look forward to that possibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2020/stamner.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Can't go to Britain without a proper tea"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Can't go to Britain without a proper tea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2020/2020-04-19_remembering_testbash_brighton-2018/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Reflecting on Let’s Test 2017</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2019/2019-09-15_reflecting-on-let-s-test-2017/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="f2d3" id="f2d3" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;Good ideas come back around. As I sit here re-reading my notes from Let’s Test 2017, I remember the thrill of coming across so many new ideas there, and realize how much these three things stick out to me even now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/valley-lodge.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Valley Lodge &amp;amp; Spa, Magaliesburg, South Africa"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Valley Lodge &amp;amp; Spa, Magaliesburg, South Africa&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="dc01" id="dc01" class="graf graf--li graf-after--figure"&gt;Causal loop diagrams&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p name="1b99" id="1b99" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;It’s possible I’d seen a causal loop disgram before, but it wasn’t until I went to Jo Perold and Barry Tandy’s “Visualize your way to better problem solving” workshop that I knew the name for them. &lt;a href="https://www.isixsigma.com/tools-templates/cause-effect/causal-loop-diagrams-little-known-analytical-tool/" data-href="https://www.isixsigma.com/tools-templates/cause-effect/causal-loop-diagrams-little-known-analytical-tool/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Here’s an example of how connecting nouns with verbs via bubbles and letters really clears things up.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="0c13" id="0c13" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;During the workshop, Jo and Barry talked about how drawing a diagram of your software in this way can help you discover interaction points between systems. Sharing the diagram is one way to take the invisible software you’re building into a visible space. That allows us to have a conversation about the model, discover if we’re on the same page, and take steps to improve the model and ultimately the software. The more visualizations I see of process and influence on the job, the more I realize they’re exposing &lt;a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/articles/demystifying-conways-law" data-href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/articles/demystifying-conways-law" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Conway’s Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="b91d" id="b91d" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Elisabeth Hendrickson wrote in &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15980494-explore-it" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15980494-explore-it" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Explore It!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; &lt;/em&gt;about how causal loop diagrams can help you discover interesting areas to test. She pointed out that transitions from one state to another take time, and there’s lots to be discovered during the moments of transition about interruptions, errors, and incomplete states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/causal-loop.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title='Repenning, Nelson &amp;amp; Sterman, John. (2003). "Nobody Ever Gets Credit for Fixing Problems That Never Happened: Creating and Sustaining Process Improvement." Engineering Management Review, IEEE. 30. 64- 64. 10.1109/EMR.2002.1167285.'&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Repenning, Nelson &amp;amp; Sterman, John. (2003). "Nobody Ever Gets Credit for Fixing Problems That Never Happened: Creating and Sustaining Process Improvement." Engineering Management Review, IEEE. 30. 64- 64. 10.1109/EMR.2002.1167285.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="5105" id="5105" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;Nelson Repenning and John Sterman used a causal loop diagram to display a human problem: not prioritizing time for improving. Read their whole article to discover terrifying news about how much time you’re wasting all the time by not stopping to improve!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="50d2" id="50d2" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;2. Metaphors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="c76c" id="c76c" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Leo Hepis and Danie Roux’s “Frames at Work” workshop blew my mind. I would tell you they were talking about how metaphors and context framing shape the way we think about our work. And they did that. But the meandering and level of lost I felt on our path there was unprecedented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/rope.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Our table selected “Rope of Awesome” and I stand by that answer."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Our table selected “Rope of Awesome” and I stand by that answer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="e4cd" id="e4cd" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;One of the exercises had us listening to a story about someone’s work and only writing down the metaphors. There seemed to be one every sentence, so many that I thought the speaker was throwing them in there on purpose. (See: &lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;throwing&lt;/em&gt;. They’re everywhere!) He talked about “pulling” and “dragging” his team along. Imagine instead if he were “pushing” or “building” his team. How would he think differently about his work? How different would his work be? Listen more closely to the words people are using to discover terrifying news about how they perceive their work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="bff4" id="bff4" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;3. Reflection and Learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="b1ad" id="b1ad" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Alison Gitelson hosted a session to help the conference attendees think more about what they’d just learned. I was still reeling from the metaphors and framing session, so I wrote down these questions for myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="00fe" id="00fe" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;How do I realize when I’m stuck inside my own head?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="48ba" id="48ba" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Does noticing where a behavior would be useful make it less irritating?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="248b" id="248b" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Was there a better discussion because active disagreement was encouraged?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="0165" id="0165" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Who in my life can help me reframe?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="9408" id="9408" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Why do I feel my effort has to achieve something?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p name="3b02" id="3b02" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;Reflect on these questions yourself for terrifying news about how stuck you can be sometimes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/double-rainbow.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Very slight double rainbow to the right."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Very slight double rainbow to the right.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/reflecting-on-lets-test-2017-efb52723598c"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2019/2019-09-15_reflecting-on-let-s-test-2017/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Agile Testing Days 2018: A Reflection</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2019/2019-07-07_agile-testing-days-2018-a-reflection/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="4f54" id="4f54" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;I was beyond excited to attend Agile Testing Days in Potsdam, Germany for the first time a year and a half ago. Anywhere I went, I met women who I’d previously only known from the internet. It was refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="bd6a" id="bd6a" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Based on the pages of notes I’ve got, I can tell you that the lessons I took away from that week have seeped into the way I work everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="14da" id="14da" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Humans should not be regression testing.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="d815" id="d815" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jezhumble" data-href="https://twitter.com/jezhumble" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jez Humble&lt;/a&gt; kicked off the conference with a session about continuous delivery. He described the barriers of organizational culture and software architecture that can prevent you from getting to a point where you can deliver continuously. Previous places where I worked made this feel like an insurmountable feat; now when I imagine continuous delivery, I can imagine concrete steps we could take to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="0481" id="0481" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Let’s create a small habit everyday to trigger me to learn more.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7bbd" id="7bbd" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke" data-href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lisi Hocke&lt;/a&gt; certainly took this idea from her talk and ran with it. She’s been pair testing remotely with people around the world and learning so much from it. I’ve taken pairing on a smaller scale, with my colleagues or in-person. There are still times when it tests my patience, but the benefits of being able to more precisely explain what I’m doing and what I expect of the software vastly outweigh that investment. All my notes from Lisi’s talk have me nodding my head, like these are the most obvious things in the world. The biggest I’d come across about a year beforehand: having a growth mindset rather than a fixed mindset. &lt;a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2014/01/29/carol-dweck-mindset/" data-href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2014/01/29/carol-dweck-mindset/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;This explanation from Brain Pickings sticks with me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/sanssouci-palace.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Sanssouci Palace in Potsdam."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Sanssouci Palace in Potsdam.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name="f3ae" id="f3ae" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure"&gt;“I am curious why they’re doing what they do.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7ad0" id="7ad0" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NativeWired" data-href="https://twitter.com/NativeWired" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gitte Klitgaard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andreasschliep" data-href="https://twitter.com/andreasschliep" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Andreas Schliep&lt;/a&gt; had an improvised conversation about good and evil. You know, like you do with your friends for fun, but on stage. It can be so hard to believe that people are acting with good intentions at heart. But remembering to have empathy for the situations people find themselves in will help you choose to be the person to repair relationships when things go awry. If you believe in people, they can be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="c286" id="c286" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“People don’t want to collaborate with you when you have twelve spreadsheets for them to go through.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7691" id="7691" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;I’m sure &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/techgirl1908" data-href="https://twitter.com/techgirl1908" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Angie Jones&lt;/a&gt; had other, more profound takeaways from her talk. But this one sticks to my bones. I think of it anytime I open a spreadsheet with more than one sheet in it. I think of it when I’m deciding on a tool to use, and wondering not what’s easiest for me to set up, but what’s easiest for my fellow collaborators to use. Thank you for this gem Angie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/sanssouci-park.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Some dramatic structure in Sanssouci Park."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Some dramatic structure in Sanssouci Park.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name="f5ac" id="f5ac" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure"&gt;“Get ready to fire people to maintain the culture you want.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="f967" id="f967" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/poornima" data-href="https://twitter.com/poornima" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Poornima Vijayashanker&lt;/a&gt; spoke about concrete ways to successfully onboard new employees. But I’m curious about this provocative statement. I haven’t ever worked at a place bold enough to get rid of managers whose direct reports displayed a pattern of escaping them that no one could ignore. I wonder what kind of company is bold enough to take this step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="deaf" id="deaf" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Only put off until tomorrow what you are willing to die having left undone.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="c0ca" id="c0ca" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Punkmik" data-href="https://twitter.com/Punkmik" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kim Knup&lt;/a&gt; said Pablo Picasso came up with this doozie. At my first job, we used a physical board with sticky notes. If the sticky note had been moved around too many times or stuck in one place too long, it would literally fall off the board. At the time this felt like a failure. Now I see it for the blessing it was. Forgetting is a part of life, even if our digital tools would prefer us to forget that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="af08" id="af08" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Do what you say you will. Integrity is important.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="f653" id="f653" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Rob_Lambert" data-href="https://twitter.com/Rob_Lambert" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Lambert&lt;/a&gt; spoke about behaviors of effective Agile teams. It’s resonating with me again now because it’s something I’m addressing in a talk I’m giving about how to build trust. I’m digging into authenticity, which I think goes a step beyond integrity. Doing what you say you will is being externally congruent. Authentic people are also internally congruent; the vision they have of themselves is the one they present to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/downtown.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="I forget what this is but it’s across from the museum downtown and damn the light was lovely."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;I forget what this is but it’s across from the museum downtown and damn the light was lovely.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name="7969" id="7969" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure"&gt;“If you never get feedback, you have one year of experience ten times.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="a539" id="a539" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;This came out in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots" data-href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Huib Schoots&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alex_schl" data-href="https://twitter.com/alex_schl" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Alex Schladebeck&lt;/a&gt;’s workshop on dissecting your testing and discovering the skills present in your exploratory testing. We practiced observing the skills we were using on the meta-level. It allowed me to both see and share how much a year of mob testing for an hour every day had expanded at least two things. First: my field of vision for how to dig and explore software had grown. Second: I was able to explain what I was thinking such that the other people present could understand, contribute to, and question which path we’d take next. It was life-affirming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="b8f8" id="b8f8" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“When we set our own limits, we can change them.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="c8b4" id="c8b4" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;This came up in the context of Natalie Wenert’s talk about cross-team functionality. She chided organizations for relying on hero-worship and fire-fighting over breaking down silos and contributing to the whole. One of my conference buddies was frustrated at Agile Testing Days because they viewed so much of the content as “work therapy.” They weren’t wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="e6da" id="e6da" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“As a user, I want to be locked out of the system after three incorrect password attempts.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="1723" id="1723" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidEvans66" data-href="https://twitter.com/DavidEvans66" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Evans&lt;/a&gt; presented a memorable talk about how the template we stick to for writing user stories does not serve us well. This particular example made me laugh out loud. This story gets the “why” wrong. It’s about security of our system and the user’s data. Being honest about why we’re building the software would make the user story less absurd, and hopefully get us on the path to making better software too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/barberini.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="This doozie is in the Museum Barberini, which is worth checking out if you're in Potsdam."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;This doozie is in the Museum Barberini, which is worth checking out if you're in Potsdam.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name="710c" id="710c" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure"&gt;“Uncertainty is more stressful than inevitable pain.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7f33" id="7f33" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ewebber" data-href="https://twitter.com/ewebber" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Emily Webber&lt;/a&gt; spoke about team interactions and organizational change. (Shout out to all the people who’ve tweet me instead of this other brown-haired white lady with glasses!) I’m on my fifth team in a year at my current company. I’m tired of the change. I know how important it is to build relationships with the people you work with. I’ve expressed that knowing who’s on my team is more important than having the perfect set of people. I look forward to more stability there because I don’t envy the alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="fc3c" id="fc3c" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Mistakes were made.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="7aee" id="7aee" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lunivore" data-href="https://twitter.com/lunivore" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Liz Keogh&lt;/a&gt; spoke about how to deliver failure messages. Her message was essentially: don’t. Pointing out the mistake without pointing fingers is enough. Encourage good existing behavior and create more options so that failure can occur safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="20f1" id="20f1" class="graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Are we advocating for those doing a good job?”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="2163" id="2163" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote graf--trailing"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AshColeman30" data-href="https://twitter.com/AshColeman30" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ash Coleman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keithklain" data-href="https://twitter.com/keithklain" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/a&gt; had a late-night after-dinner (over-hyphenated?) bonus-keynote to talk about how culture is a mindset and what we can do to change it. They encouraged allies in the majority to stop talking, and start listening, so you can do something. If you’re uncomfortable, good. You’re learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/agile-testing-days-2017-a-reflection-2ea505b09eec"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2019/2019-07-07_agile-testing-days-2018-a-reflection/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nurture the Bright Spots: Dutch Exploratory Workshop on Testing 2018</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2019/2019-02-09_nuture-the-bright-spots-dutch-exploratory-workshop-on-testing-2018/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="ec08" id="ec08" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;A peer conference is different from a regular conference. If you’re one of the lucky few to get invited, you find yourself in an environment surrounded by the best and the brightest. There will be presentations to spark a discussion, but the facilitated discussion is where the real learning occurs. It certainly puts the “confer” back in conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="3a66" id="3a66" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;The Dutch Exploratory Workshop on Testing (or DEWT for short, rhymes with newt) in the fall of 2018 was the first one of these I attended outside of work. The theme was “Developing expertise in software testing.” The format of the gathering itself paired nicely with one of the main conclusions I took away from the weekend: choose the best people, foster an environment where they have the energy to learn and inspire others, and set aside time to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2019/sunrise.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Gorgeous sunrise on our morning run"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Gorgeous sunrise on our morning run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section name="c8e6" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="05d9" id="05d9" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;Here are some of the things I think about at least once a week back at work:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote name="64ce" id="64ce" class="graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“You let people annoy you by not pushing back.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p name="bc0e" id="bc0e" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;People cannot read your mind. If something is bothering you and you never bring it up, how are they supposed to figure it out? Try to find something small to be firm about, and build from there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote name="b78d" id="b78d" class="graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“People relax when you say it’s time-boxed.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p name="0706" id="0706" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;Sometimes I’d rather stop fighting than win. I think it’s clear that a bug should be investigated, but someone else believes it’s not worth any time. Instead of deciding yes or no based on insufficient information, I’ve found “let’s look at this for two hours and decide if we should keep going” gets more people on board and allows the conversation to move on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote name="1d71" id="1d71" class="graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“When you ask a difficult question, sometimes people ask a simpler question in their head and answer that.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p name="de86" id="de86" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote graf--trailing"&gt;One of the questions I was trying to help answer this week was “should we release next week?” The team and I found it easier to answer adjacent questions instead of the big one we needed. We could find answers to “are there pieces of work we need to complete before the release?”, “are those pieces of work estimated?”, “could the tests that aren’t passing expose risk to our company’s bottom line?”. I can see how some of the answers to these smaller questions can support an answer to the larger one. My worry is that getting “yes, this is fine” to something small will accidentally result in a “yes, this is fine” to the overall question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section name="9449" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="546a" id="546a" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;I don’t have more to add or break down regarding these thoughts, but I can tell you that I nodded knowingly when they were said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="38b9" id="38b9" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p"&gt;“Regression sprint.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="59d9" id="59d9" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“I can’t change other people for them.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="bb75" id="bb75" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“If it’s overwhelming, take a smaller step.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="03e4" id="03e4" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“An expert is someone who learns the fastest.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="7532" id="7532" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“My standards are not necessarily ‘the’ standard.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="7aa4" id="7aa4" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“Internal conferences help people see good work.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="d56e" id="d56e" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“As knowledge workers, we are the means of production!”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="c933" id="c933" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li"&gt;“Sometimes you’re only doing enough work not to get fired.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="cc1a" id="cc1a" class="graf graf--li graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--li graf--trailing"&gt;“How do I tell you I disagree with you without ending the conversation?”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section name="6858" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="8a07" id="8a07" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;These are the books that were both (a) mentioned explicitly enough for me to find them and (b) worthy of adding to my exponentially-growing Goodreads backlog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="09ef" id="09ef" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8337919-coaching-agile-teams" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8337919-coaching-agile-teams" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;Coaching Agile Teams: A Companion for ScrumMasters, Agile Coaches, and Project Managers in Transition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="aa49" id="aa49" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/571672.The_Satir_Model" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/571672.The_Satir_Model" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;The Satir Model: Family Therapy and Beyond&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="5dfb" id="5dfb" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3090109-how-to-be-an-explorer-of-the-world" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3090109-how-to-be-an-explorer-of-the-world" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;How To Be an Explorer of the World: Portable Life Museum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="4dfb" id="4dfb" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12609433-the-power-of-habit" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12609433-the-power-of-habit" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="a534" id="a534" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6570502-switch?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6570502-switch?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--li-em"&gt;Switch: How to Change Things When Change Is Hard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name="2ff1" id="2ff1" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li graf--trailing"&gt;(If you’re looking for books you can’t miss about sociology and psychology, follow &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/2204488-maaike" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/2204488-maaike" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Maaike Brinkhof&lt;/a&gt; on Goodreads.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section name="3e2d" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="a362" id="a362" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;The retrospective asked us a big question that I wasn’t prepared to answer in the waning hours of the conference: What were we going to change in our jobs, in our lives, in our coaching of our colleagues when we got back to work on Monday? I only realized later that someone proclaimed a mission statement that I’d like to adopt:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote name="0081" id="0081" class="graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p"&gt;I will bring you discomfort. I will stay critical when everyone else thinks we’re done.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p name="f4e6" id="f4e6" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;I’ll start there. But I’ll also make time. I’ll step back. I’ll think about what you’ve done. Only then can I grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Starting to wonder if the solution to a lot of problems in testing is simply making the world a better and more humane place.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DEWT8?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#DEWT8&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/modestambitions?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#modestambitions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/fixalltehthings?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#fixalltehthings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Joep Schuurkes (@j19sch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/j19sch/status/1053634456534351877?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 20, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="0f62" id="0f62" class="graf graf--p graf--leading graf--trailing"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Thanks to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Arborosa" data-href="https://twitter.com/Arborosa" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Jean-Paul Varwijk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JorisMeerts" data-href="https://twitter.com/JorisMeerts" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Joris Meerts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; for organizing DEWT 2018, and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/klaartjejulia" data-href="https://twitter.com/klaartjejulia" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Klaartje van Zwoll&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ClaireMGoss" data-href="https://twitter.com/ClaireMGoss" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Claire Goss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;, and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Maaikees" data-href="https://twitter.com/Maaikees" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;Maaike Brinkhof&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; for reminding me how refreshing peers can be. If you don’t have an entire weekend to discover deep truths with your peers, try watching Vera Gehlen-Baum’s &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/events/a-software-tester-s-guide-to-expertise-vera-gehlen-baum" data-href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/events/a-software-tester-s-guide-to-expertise-vera-gehlen-baum" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt;A Software Tester’s Guide to Expertise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class="markup--em markup--p-em"&gt; instead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/nuture-the-bright-spots-dutch-exploratory-workshop-on-testing-2018-90c45555ca19"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>DEWT</category><category>peer-conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2019/2019-02-09_nuture-the-bright-spots-dutch-exploratory-workshop-on-testing-2018/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Regression Testing Wisdom from Agile Testing Days 2017</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-12-11_regression-testing-wisdom-from-agile-testing-days-2017/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;At my current job in a regulated industry, our software goes through a validation testing period before it goes live. A build is cut. It gets deployed to the validation environment, integrated with our other products. Depending on the size of the product or service, the testers have a few days to a few weeks to generate documentation that describe the features and the environment in case of an audit. Ideally, we’re regression testing during this time. While we continue to look for unexpected behavior, finding anything out of the ordinary means a headache for more people than I care to admit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2017/sansoucci.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Sansoucci Park in Potsdam, Germany"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Sansoucci Park in Potsdam, Germany&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left my team in the middle of a validation cycle to attend &lt;a href="https://agiletestingdays.com/" data-href="https://agiletestingdays.com/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Agile Testing Days&lt;/a&gt; in Potsdam, Germany November, so I had regression testing on the brain. Here’s some of what stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;section name="0101" class="section section--body section--last"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;h5 name="f529" id="f529" class="graf graf--h4 graf--leading"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jezhumble" data-href="https://twitter.com/jezhumble" class="markup--anchor markup--h4-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jez Humble&lt;/a&gt;: Humans should not be regression testing.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p name="5308" id="5308" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4"&gt;I have this in RED in my notes. His talk about continuous delivery emphasized the speed of delivering customer value through continuous delivery. Enough said I think.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 name="ca30" id="ca30" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke" data-href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke" class="markup--anchor markup--h4-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lisi Hocke&lt;/a&gt;: Get developers to automate regression.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p name="b8b1" id="b8b1" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4"&gt;Lisi had an inspired idea to get this going: invite your developers to help you manually regression test. After a few hours of repetitive tasks, they’ll get motivated to write something that makes both your lives easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 name="1966" id="1966" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/techgirl1908" data-href="https://twitter.com/techgirl1908" class="markup--anchor markup--h4-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Angie Jones&lt;/a&gt;: People don’t want to collaborate with you when you have twelve spreadsheets.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p name="1b2f" id="1b2f" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4"&gt;I get very worried when I see a regression checklist that involves multiple sheets within the same spreadsheet. I start counting up how long it might take to get through, assuming we don’t have to circle back and investigate, ask questions, or report bugs. I wonder if things have changed since items were added. I wonder who was consulted about which items were high-priority, or necessary. I wonder about what might be assumed about the environment setup, or left off entirely. Rather than building confidence or feeling at peace, multiple spreadsheets of regression scenarios raise my blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 name="3663" id="3663" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/poornima" data-href="https://twitter.com/poornima" class="markup--anchor markup--h4-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Poornima Vijayashanker&lt;/a&gt;: Give new employees a particular task.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p name="35bb" id="35bb" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4"&gt;Guided or paired regression testing can be one way to get to know a product when you’re new to a company or a team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 name="6268" id="6268" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rob_lambert" data-href="https://twitter.com/rob_lambert" class="markup--anchor markup--h4-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Lambert&lt;/a&gt;: Be brave. Integrity is important.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p name="93ed" id="93ed" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4"&gt;In the year I’ve been in my current role, I’ve only found a bug that required a deploy in the midst of a validation period once. Raising it was terrifying. This would be the first release of the service, so it was hard for me to tie the bug to customer value. I had to ask a developer to work under extreme time pressure, only to stick myself with the testing of it. Less time to explore meant less confidence after the fix than before. But as a tester, it’s my responsibility to provide relevant information in a timely manner, even if that requires more than my average amount of bravery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 name="7b8f" id="7b8f" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/2bittester" data-href="https://twitter.com/2bittester" class="markup--anchor markup--h4-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mark Winteringham&lt;/a&gt;: The product is large. I cannot observe every change.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p name="40ed" id="40ed" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4"&gt;I’ve worked with people who insisted I caught everything. I didn’t. No one could. Be terrified, but also liberated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 name="e0f8" id="e0f8" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lunivore" data-href="https://twitter.com/lunivore" class="markup--anchor markup--h4-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Liz Keogh&lt;/a&gt;: Tell people failure is expected.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p name="a6cb" id="a6cb" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4 graf--trailing"&gt;Everyone else goes into validation testing expecting success. I go in expecting failure. What if I told people we would fail? What if we planned for it? What if our deadlines accounted for failure?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/regression-testing-wisdom-from-agile-testing-days-2017-a5eb7d9aeef0"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-12-11_regression-testing-wisdom-from-agile-testing-days-2017/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Choose One Thing: Copenhagen Context 2017</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-10-05_choose-one-thing-copenhagen-context-2017/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="4fad" id="4fad" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;All of the talks I attended at Copenhagen Context included this message: change one thing. Try something, see what happens, and go from there. It’s good advice, but it can be hard when it feels like everything needs changing at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2017/copenhagen.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Copenhagen, in context"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Copenhagen, in context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="c31b" id="c31b" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;In a lightning talk, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots" data-href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Huib Schoots&lt;/a&gt; identified one thing every tester can change: practice test reporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Test reports suck. But if we don't learn to write them, we have to do it verbally instead. Practice reporting every day/sprint. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@huibschoots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Elizabeth Zagroba (@ezagroba) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/910896386857668608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 21, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="5ccb" id="5ccb" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keithklain" data-href="https://twitter.com/keithklain" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/a&gt; told us how to kick off a change at an organization: choose one thing, and stop doing it. Stop fear-based management; consider how people are motivated and compensated. Stop focusing on your process; consider the business value of what you’re building. Stop assuming every problem is a technical problem; look inward when the information you provide isn’t valued. Keith picked on test managers who didn’t do much hands-on testing in particular, which was interesting to hear in a room full of test managers I work for. I heard Keith give this talk a few months ago, but there was enough to take away that I still have two pages of notes (different from the last time) full of new ideas to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="b19b" id="b19b" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aarjay" data-href="https://twitter.com/aarjay" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jyothi Rangaiah&lt;/a&gt; spoke about gathering requirements. Rather than wait for other roles to write a story, Jyothi suggest one thing testers can change: start suggesting requirements. Go to the development architecture meeting. Setup a three amigos meeting. Considering all the things testers can do that aren’t listed in their job description, and you’ll start looking to hire passionate people who can fulfill more that just the requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2017/prepared.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="This is what 'prepared' looks like."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;This is what 'prepared' looks like.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="9f7e" id="9f7e" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;I spoke about being an introvert. This seemed to be the biggest takeaway from the talk, which luckily is something you can change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure name="c177" id="c177" class="graf graf--figure graf--iframe graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p name="0ebd" id="0ebd" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;When &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/northern_tester" data-href="https://twitter.com/northern_tester" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ash Winter&lt;/a&gt;’s devops team wanted to upgrade all of their products at once, Ash suggested they choose one product and upgrade that first. Rather than shouldering the burden of testing all the products, a small safe-to-fail experiment would give the team enough information to decide if they should proceed. Ash’s talk was about infrastructure testing, and he noted that testers tend to identify infrastructure problems at the wrong level: in the application. If he had to choose one thing to look at to diagnose issues better, it would be production logs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="559a" id="559a" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HelenaJ_M" data-href="https://twitter.com/HelenaJ_M" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Helena Jeret-Mäe&lt;/a&gt; spoke about observing your process. She suggested changing one thing and taking notes. She described &lt;a href="http://www.nkarten.com/moimodel.pdf" data-href="http://www.nkarten.com/moimodel.pdf" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jerry Weinberg’s MOI(J) model&lt;/a&gt; for teamwork, where the J is for jiggling, or changing one thing. To improve your process, Helena recommended slowing down and stepping away from your default. By challenging your interpretations and considering other explanations, you can more effectively deal with difficult situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="43a3" id="43a3" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" data-href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nancy Kelln&lt;/a&gt; told a great story about “Nancy-driven development,” or when she tried to change a testing process all at once. When people gave her advice and templates to direct her, she realized she had no credibility and she needed to change one thing instead of changing all the things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="3f28" id="3f28" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;I’m so grateful for the time I got to spend learning from the speakers and attendees at Copenhagen Context. It was a pleasure to spend time with my tester friends from around the world. It’s a testament to the hard work of the organizers that there were no duds of presentations, and I missed many worthwhile talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="01a4" id="01a4" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Back at the office this week, I resolved to change one thing: I want to get better at sharing knowledge with my colleagues. What’s the one thing you’re going to change?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2017/together.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Statue in Nørrebro, Copenhagen"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Statue in Nørrebro, Copenhagen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/choose-one-thing-copenhagen-context-2017-dd7334b54da8"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-10-05_choose-one-thing-copenhagen-context-2017/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Romanian Testing Conference 2017</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-05-22_romanian-testing-conference-2017/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="f772" id="f772" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;I’d heard good things about the Romanian Testing Conference from previous years, so I was excited and honored to speak at this year’s event. I was happy to catch up with people I knew, put a face to people I’d only seen on the internet, and meet the testers who worked on software I’ve both &lt;a href="http://www.ns.nl/" data-href="http://www.ns.nl/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;valued&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.adobe.com/marketing-cloud/experience-manager.html" data-href="http://www.adobe.com/marketing-cloud/experience-manager.html" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;loathed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2017/cluj.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="View from my hotel room in Cluj."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;View from my hotel room in Cluj.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="892b" id="892b" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;Goranka Bjedov spoke about scaling up the hardware in Facebook’s data centers. Her childhood in a power-rationed Yugoslavia makes her an ideal candidate to consider the balance between power and performance and reign in the Silicon Valley dream of just adding another server. (In California and around the world, resources are finite!) On the infrastructure side, Goranka knows she has to plan for features to be massively popular, even when they don’t seem like they’ll take off. Photo tagging and slideshow retrospective videos surpassed her expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="56ce" id="56ce" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;The things she was able to tell about were as interesting as the things she wasn’t. She could tell us the measurements Facebook took on IBM machines a few years ago, but not more recently. IBM was using the data to price the machines! She could tell us how many machines could fit on a rack before the spinning shook it too hard, but she couldn’t tell us how many racks there were in each data center. The data centers use evaporative cooling, literally pools of water on top of the racks, rather than air conditioning to save money. I left thinking “that was all interesting, but when am I going to have input on a data center?” It wasn’t until I got back to the office that I remembered we also host our own data centers. It might be sooner than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="775d" id="775d" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/adampknight" data-href="https://twitter.com/adampknight" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Adam Knight&lt;/a&gt; directed his testing at a new company after giving the business side a risk questionnaire, inspired by one a financial advisor gave him. Adam considered examples where humans didn’t accurately evaluate risk. This one stood out to me: Grouping several problems together into one problem underestimates risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="ed19" id="ed19" class="graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p"&gt;Integrity is the most important quality we can demonstrate as testers.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="5890" id="5890" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;While it was hard to write unbiased questions, Adam found some interesting results from the questionnaire. Everyone agreed they needed specialist testers, but they didn’t have any on staff at the time! &lt;a href="https://www.riveragency.com/" data-href="https://www.riveragency.com/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;They’re hiring&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.mdsol.com/en/careers" data-href="https://www.mdsol.com/en/careers" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;So is Medidata&lt;/a&gt;. We build software for clinical trials at Medidata. I think we have a very low tolerance for bugs in production, but more flexibility around scope and deadlines. Adam got me curious about whether our business leaders would agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2017/relaxed.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Someone described me as 'relaxed' here."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Someone described me as 'relaxed' here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="8fd6" id="8fd6" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;I spoke next! Sanda and Raluca kept me calm before I went on. &lt;a href="https://www.stefanfekete.com/" data-href="https://www.stefanfekete.com/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Stefan&lt;/a&gt; managed to capture photographic evidence of &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba" data-href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" target="_blank"&gt;my face&lt;/a&gt; looking normal. I’m grateful for everyone who came and sat scattered among the rows by themselves, or was eager to engage with me afterwards. &lt;a href="https://dojo.ministryoftesting.com/lessons/succeeding-as-an-introvert-elizabeth-zagroba" data-href="https://dojo.ministryoftesting.com/lessons/succeeding-as-an-introvert-elizabeth-zagroba" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Here’s a previous but similar performance if you’re curious&lt;/a&gt;. I appreciated all the follow-up questions in front of the group and individually afterwards. In future performances, I need to do a better job of noting that no one’s an introvert all the time, and the extrovert/introvert distinction isn’t going to be useful for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="89fa" id="89fa" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;I tried to hide for a few minutes because facing the hundreds of people in the lunchroom was too overwhelming after just coming off stage. Unfortunately the interview crew found me! Note for next year: hide in my room and not in the lobby. (Also: find out why people were taking so many desserts.) I missed the beginning of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KeithKlain" data-href="https://twitter.com/KeithKlain" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/a&gt;’s talk because I eat a lot. (Get over it.) Apparently, it began with a joke about him being a money launderer that I both originated and plan to perpetuate. The hundreds of Romanians did not appear to be amused. According to sources familiar with the matter, they rarely do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="86a1" id="86a1" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Keith noted that testers who can’t connect a bug to the business impact in production are doing it wrong. Publicly traded American companies have series 10 forms outlining their business risks. Both Adam and Keith wanted testers to ask the business what quality meant to them. You can become more efficient by doing less testing if you are transparent with what you’re testing and avoid repeating tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="e3fa" id="e3fa" class="graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p"&gt;Testing that adds a lot of value is hard. Good testing raises more questions than it answers.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="c398" id="c398" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/carmen-sighiartau-a360236a/" data-href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/carmen-sighiartau-a360236a/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Carmen Sighiartau&lt;/a&gt; spoke about testing from a developer’s perspective. Until she worked with a tester that caught things she didn’t, she saw testing as a crappy job anyone could do. Like Keith, she saw a lot of redundant testing that didn’t provide value. Now, she wants to work with testers because she sees the unique perspective they can bring to the table. Her growth as a developer reminded me to care about my craft and think about my work without running on auto-pilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="956b" id="956b" class="graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p"&gt;Nothing in life is mandatory.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="0e85" id="0e85" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;Carmen encouraged us to interview candidates for how they work on a team. It’s easier to educate technical skills than social skills. &lt;a href="http://www.huibschoots.nl/wordpress/?p=1666" data-href="http://www.huibschoots.nl/wordpress/?p=1666" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Huib Schoots expanded on how to recognize professional testers in his blog&lt;/a&gt;. When I’m interviewing testers to join one of the teams I’m on, I try to ask one question with a straightforward answer I can verify (“What did you talk about with the previous interviewers?”) so I can make sure they describe a situation clearly. I also ask about teamwork or empathy (“Tell me about a time you had to deliver bad news.”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="a20b" id="a20b" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NicolaO55" data-href="https://twitter.com/NicolaO55" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nicola Owen&lt;/a&gt;’s talk posed the question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="2040" id="2040" class="graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p"&gt;If you were leaving your job soon, would you test differently?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="30ce" id="30ce" class="graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote"&gt;If you’re staying in your job, it can be acceptable for a bug report to need more clarification, or for a colleague to ask you where a document is. Once you’re gone, your abandoned colleagues can’t rely on those valuable conversations. Write things down and put them in an obvious place. Like Carmen, Nicola spoke of developers who’d only had negative experiences with testers. You can show your value by passing on your knowledge before you leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="7c09" id="7c09" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hargolas" data-href="https://twitter.com/hargolas" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Harry Girlea&lt;/a&gt; spoke last to the entire crowd and really put us all to shame. I can’t imagine telling a bunch of adults about my favorite hobby when I was 12 years old. He handled the Q&amp;amp;A like a pro. When someone asked him how he balanced gaming with school, he said he would probably play too much, but his mom keeps him in check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="a298" id="a298" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;The organizers and volunteers at the conference made the logistics a breeze, which left lots of time for conferring. Thanks in particular to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Rob_Lambert" data-href="https://twitter.com/Rob_Lambert" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Lambert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ard_kramer" data-href="https://twitter.com/ard_kramer" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ard Kramer&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EnquireTST" data-href="https://twitter.com/EnquireTST" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beren Van Daele&lt;/a&gt; for lending me their ears. I appreciate all the ideas and I hope I have the opportunity to join this wonderful group again in the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;When in Cluj ... take pictures &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NicolaO55?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@NicolaO55&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ezagroba&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MaikNog?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@MaikNog&lt;/a&gt; @EnquireTST &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rtc2017?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#rtc2017&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/GgVp8HcmvS"&gt;pic.twitter.com/GgVp8HcmvS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Marcel Gehlen (@Marcel_Gehlen) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Marcel_Gehlen/status/863094250736685057?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 12, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/romanian-testing-conference-2017-ec768d64167e"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-05-22_romanian-testing-conference-2017/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Surviving the Conference Social Scene</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-04-09_surviving-the-conference-social-scene/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="63af" id="63af" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;I’ve attended and spoken at conferences. I’ve participated in great sessions and made meaningful connections. And I’ve had terrible times where I go to useless sessions and meet no one. I empathized with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tzb/status/845440755585953794" data-href="https://twitter.com/tzb/status/845440755585953794" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;this Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; about going to a conference where you know no one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="00c9" id="00c9" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;I don’t think there’s a right answer for everyone or every conference. Here are some things that I’ve found helpful in surviving really intense days full of strangers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="3eaa" id="3eaa" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong"&gt;Listen to these smarty pants.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Other people have a lot more public speaking and networking under their belts than I have. Benefit from it. Rob Lambert wrote &lt;a href="http://cultivatedmanagement.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/CM-SurvivingAConference.pdf" data-href="http://cultivatedmanagement.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/CM-SurvivingAConference.pdf" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Blazingly Simple Guide to Surviving a Conference&lt;/a&gt;. It’s directed at speakers, but it’s useful for any conference attendee. &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4865.How_to_Win_Friends_and_Influence_People" data-href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4865.How_to_Win_Friends_and_Influence_People" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;How To Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/a&gt; has more advice about connecting with people quickly without seeming sleazy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="28b6" id="28b6" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong"&gt;Connect with people ahead of time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Let people know you’re going to the conference. Tell people which sessions you’re speaking at or attending so they can find you. Write to people who’ve said they’re going. Tell them you’re excited to see or meet them. Find out which speakers they think are valuable so you end up in better sessions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="ab0f" id="ab0f" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong"&gt;Take a day off before the conference. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Get enough sleep. Get the lay of the land. Give yourself a chance to distance yourself from the minutiae of your work inbox. Don’t talk to anyone for a day so you’re itching to jump into conversations when you arrive. Think about what you’re struggling with at work and how the people you’re about to meet might help you solve it. I spent one conference asking almost everyone I met “Can you think of a way to have a computer tell if a live audio stream is playing a radio show or an ad?” No one did, but even that was helpful information.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="9e1c" id="9e1c" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong"&gt;Get adopted.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;This has been the luckiest and most fruitful thing for me at conferences: people adopt me. People who saw me ask a good question. People who noticed I was rolling my eyes. People who saw a speaker be mean to me. People who spent a whole day with me in a tutorial. (I’m looking at you &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aclairefication" data-href="https://twitter.com/aclairefication" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Claire Moss&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ducksnsquirrels" data-href="https://twitter.com/ducksnsquirrels" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Diana Wendruff&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vds4" data-href="https://twitter.com/vds4" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Martin Hynie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LarsSjodahl" data-href="https://twitter.com/LarsSjodahl" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lars Sjödahl&lt;/a&gt;.) They found me during breaks and introduced me to the brilliant people they knew.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="f780" id="f780" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong"&gt;Find people at a meal. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;People respond to flattery. If you approach a speaker at lunch and say something like “Hi, I’m Elizabeth. I was just in your session about [whatever] and [this thing] really resonated with me. May I sit here?” most speakers will say yes. They’re already seated and eating, and you’ve made it clear that you were listening and impacted by what they said. You can also join a group that already seems to know each other. Try just listening. You may find out which sessions they’re attending, blogs they’re reading, or build up the courage to ask which bar they’re heading to later.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="acff" id="acff" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong"&gt;Use Twitter to find after-hours conferring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;When the conference is in a city or spread over a wider location, physically finding people can be harder. Check out the Twitter hashtag for the conference. Find someone you’d like to speak with again and check out their Tweets &amp;amp; Replies tab. This works especially well at Twitter-heavy conferences like TestBash and CAST. (Note: As a young lady, I don’t think I’m perceived as a creepy stalker. I’m not sure this would be the case for everyone.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="db12" id="db12" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong"&gt;Write about the people you met. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Let people know that you enjoyed connecting with them, or follow-up with people you couldn’t find again. Tweet at them, write them an email, or add them on LinkedIn. They may be a person you can reach out to with a question or a job listing. If nothing else, writing to them will help you both remember each other’s names.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p name="5464" id="5464" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li graf--trailing"&gt;I’m still learning how to get the most out of a conference experience. Sometimes I fail to follow some of the advice I’ve outlined above, but I forgive myself and keep trying to make an effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/surviving-the-conference-social-scene-db13099d85aa"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-04-09_surviving-the-conference-social-scene/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Connections from TestBash Philadelphia</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-01-08_connections-from-testbash-philadelphia/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="04db" id="04db" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3 graf--trailing"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ministryoftesting.com/training-events/testbash-philadelphia-2016/" data-href="http://www.ministryoftesting.com/training-events/testbash-philadelphia-2016/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TestBash Philadelphia&lt;/a&gt; began on November 10th. On November 9th, I woke up and realized the election I witnessed the night before was not a nightmare, a figment of my imagination. I wondered how I could speak on a topic so trivial as introversion when there was important work to be done. I wondered how anyone could listen to what I had to say, or care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;section name="cb95" class="section section--body"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="916d" id="916d" class="graf graf--p graf--leading"&gt;It turned out TestBash was the reset I needed. Smart, supportive, open-minded people listened to me. I encountered new ideas that made me stop and think. Over dinner, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/a_bangser" data-href="https://twitter.com/a_bangser" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Abby Bangser&lt;/a&gt; suggested setting up my deployments before setting up my development environment. I put down my fork and relived my past nine months on a project with an alternate ending. I had many moments like this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p name="6e58" id="6e58" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;I loved how similar ideas serendipitously popped up in different talks:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="0b27" id="0b27" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;Are you communicating with your team in a way they can hear? (Israel Alvarez) Share in a way your team finds useful. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lanettecream" data-href="https://twitter.com/lanettecream" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lanette Creamer&lt;/a&gt;) Keep exposing your team to the vocabulary you aspire to. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" data-href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nancy Kelln&lt;/a&gt;) Have a handoff meeting between development and testing. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AshColeman30" data-href="https://twitter.com/AshColeman30" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ash Coleman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/a_bangser" data-href="https://twitter.com/a_bangser" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Abby Bangser&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spargonaut" data-href="https://twitter.com/spargonaut" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;James Spargo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="78b3" id="78b3" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Are you trusted? (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ctohanian" data-href="https://twitter.com/ctohanian" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Christina Ohanian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TinyTesterTalks" data-href="https://twitter.com/TinyTesterTalks" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Megan Studzenski&lt;/a&gt;) If so, value it. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" data-href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nancy Kelln&lt;/a&gt;) If not, go where you are. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lanettecream" data-href="https://twitter.com/lanettecream" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lanette Creamer&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"Life is precious. Work where your talent is celebrated." &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lanettecream?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@lanettecream&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TestBash?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TestBash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Elizabeth Zagroba (@ezagroba) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/797047565929816064?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="19a6" id="19a6" class="graf graf--li graf-after--figure"&gt;How do you teach others? Pair. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AshColeman30" data-href="https://twitter.com/AshColeman30" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ash Coleman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/a_bangser" data-href="https://twitter.com/a_bangser" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Abby Bangser&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spargonaut" data-href="https://twitter.com/spargonaut" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;James Spargo&lt;/a&gt;) Mob. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maaretp" data-href="https://twitter.com/maaretp" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Maaret Pyhäjärvi&lt;/a&gt;) Recruit context-driven testers (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" data-href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nancy Kelln&lt;/a&gt;) and systems thinkers. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alanpage" data-href="https://twitter.com/alanpage" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Alan Page&lt;/a&gt;) Tie teaching to senior job descriptions. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TinyTesterTalks" data-href="https://twitter.com/TinyTesterTalks" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Megan Studzenski&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="c1e9" id="c1e9" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Don’t listen to every complaint. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TinyTesterTalks" data-href="https://twitter.com/TinyTesterTalks" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Megan Studzenski&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alanpage" data-href="https://twitter.com/alanpage" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Alan Page&lt;/a&gt;) Who matters? (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" data-href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nancy Kelln&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/a_bangser" data-href="https://twitter.com/a_bangser" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Abby Bangser&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spargonaut" data-href="https://twitter.com/spargonaut" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;James Spargo&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FionaCCharles" data-href="https://twitter.com/FionaCCharles" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fiona Charles&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="9939" id="9939" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;You learn more when you’re free to mess up. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maaretp" data-href="https://twitter.com/maaretp" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Maaret Pyhäjärvi&lt;/a&gt;, Israel Alvarez, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FionaCCharles" data-href="https://twitter.com/FionaCCharles" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fiona Charles&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/m_eaden" data-href="https://twitter.com/m_eaden" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Melissa Eaden&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"Don't let 'What if?' stop you from living your life." @m_eaden's 99 second talk &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TestBash?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TestBash&lt;/a&gt; 🙌💃&lt;/p&gt;— Elizabeth Zagroba (@ezagroba) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/797612025983733761?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="98eb" id="98eb" class="graf graf--li graf-after--figure"&gt;People won’t volunteer what they’re really thinking. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maaretp" data-href="https://twitter.com/maaretp" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Maaret Pyhäjärvi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" data-href="https://twitter.com/nkelln" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nancy Kelln&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FionaCCharles" data-href="https://twitter.com/FionaCCharles" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fiona Charles&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="ff21" id="ff21" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Try to answer a question yourself before asking others. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lanettecream" data-href="https://twitter.com/lanettecream" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lanette Creamer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TinyTesterTalks" data-href="https://twitter.com/TinyTesterTalks" class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Megan Studzenski&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p name="988e" id="988e" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;I’m grateful I got to connect with old friends, people I’d admired from afar, including &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/m_eaden" data-href="https://twitter.com/m_eaden" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Melissa Eaden&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stephenjanaway" data-href="https://twitter.com/stephenjanaway" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Stephen Janaway&lt;/a&gt;, and new people I just met. I met fewer people at TestBash Philadelphia than I have at conferences in the past. Perhaps it’s because &lt;a href="https://dojo.ministryoftesting.com/lessons/succeeding-as-an-introvert-elizabeth-zagroba" data-href="https://dojo.ministryoftesting.com/lessons/succeeding-as-an-introvert-elizabeth-zagroba" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;I announced to the entire room that I hate small talk&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href="https://dojo.ministryoftesting.com/lessons/elizabeth-live-from-testing-in-the-pub-at-testbash-philadelphia" data-href="https://dojo.ministryoftesting.com/lessons/elizabeth-live-from-testing-in-the-pub-at-testbash-philadelphia" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;went on a podcast to reinforce the point&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="7488" id="7488" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing"&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rosiesherry" data-href="https://twitter.com/rosiesherry" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rosie Sherry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FriendlyTester" data-href="https://twitter.com/FriendlyTester" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Richard Bradshaw&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://fringearts.com/" data-href="http://fringearts.com/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;FringeArts&lt;/a&gt;, and everyone who helped make TestBash Philadelphia a success. All the presentations are available on the &lt;a href="https://dojo.ministryoftesting.com/series/testbash-philadelphia-2016-ministry-of-testing" data-href="https://dojo.ministryoftesting.com/series/testbash-philadelphia-2016-ministry-of-testing" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ministry of Testing Dojo&lt;/a&gt;. I appreciate everyone who gave me feedback on my talk. I’m looking for resources about extroverts interacting with introverts before I present it again. If you come across something useful, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba" data-href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pass it along&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section name="cf57" class="section section--body section--last"&gt;&lt;div class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;hr class="section-divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="section-content"&gt;&lt;div class="section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn"&gt;&lt;p name="b307" id="b307" class="graf graf--p graf--leading graf--trailing"&gt;We can’t change the outcome of the election. We can listen to each other. We can affect incremental change with receptive audiences. We can consider where there might be errors in our thinking. We can improve. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23testbash%20from%3Aezagroba&amp;amp;src=typd&amp;amp;lang=en" data-href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23testbash%20from%3Aezagroba&amp;amp;src=typd&amp;amp;lang=en" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;We can amplify the voices we admire&lt;/a&gt;. We can move forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/connections-from-testbash-philadelphia-1a89c3d7aea4"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2017/2017-01-08_connections-from-testbash-philadelphia/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Some Takeaways from Let’s Test 2016</title><link>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2016/2016-07-13_some-takeaways-from-let-s-test-2016/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p name="0768" id="0768" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3"&gt;I had the great honor and privilege to speak at &lt;a href="http://lets-test.com/?page_id=4067" data-href="http://lets-test.com/?page_id=4067" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Let’s Test in Sweden&lt;/a&gt; this year. In the time since the conference, I’ve had a chance to reflect on the presentations and see what’s resonated with me back at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="5f0d" id="5f0d" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;The Only Thing it Really Depends on is Money — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sbarber" data-href="https://twitter.com/sbarber" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;Scott Barber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="67db" id="67db" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;I wish all of my colleagues from &lt;a href="http://www.hugeinc.com/" data-href="http://www.hugeinc.com/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the advertising agency where I work&lt;/a&gt; could have been in the room for this discussion. Every contract our company signs, every feature we develop, every time we choose a severity level for a bug, our decision comes down to the value we’re providing a client. With this in mind, software testers should aim to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="752c" id="752c" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;Deliver what the client wanted, not what they asked for.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="910b" id="910b" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Provide informative testing metrics. When a client asks for a metric that isn’t useful, provide them with a different metric that still provides enough information to evaluate progress and make decisions. One useful question is “What shouldn’t I do if I were to demo this to the client today?”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="501a" id="501a" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;See what people are using the most in the product. Make those things better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="a958" id="a958" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Bundle the cost of testing with the cost of the product. Nobody wants to pay separately for testing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="831e" id="831e" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;It doesn’t matter if a product is fast if nobody buys it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p name="7699" id="7699" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;But the one thing I think about every time that I write a bug or ping a colleague is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote name="c4ae" id="c4ae" class="graf graf--pullquote graf-after--p"&gt;Testing as an isolated activity has no inherent value. Nobody pays for testing. People pay for the information testing provides.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p name="347b" id="347b" class="graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote"&gt;It’s useless if I find a bug and I only tell the other testers, or the developers don’t understand the bug I wrote, or the severity isn’t properly evaluated. The bug fix won’t find its way back to the client to make the product better. To keep the most important issues top of mind, schedule a periodic bug triaging meeting with the product owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="892e" id="892e" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;These other thoughts that came up during the discussion weren’t directly related to the topic of the presentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="6ef8" id="6ef8" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;Use the few extra minutes after scrum to define some terms with your product owner.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="4ca6" id="4ca6" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;For job satisfaction, you want to be a trusted advisor. You want important people asking you interesting questions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p name="6713" id="6713" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;Context Eats Process for Breakfast — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/testpappy" data-href="https://twitter.com/testpappy" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;Patrick Prill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="f362" id="f362" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Patrick walked us through a couple exercises about describing your morning breakfast routine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="83cf" id="83cf" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;Describe the perfect cup of coffee.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="6dde" id="6dde" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Draw how you make toast.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p name="d63e" id="d63e" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;Like some other participants, I had no idea what made a perfect cup of coffee. &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.com/ezagroba/fancy-a-cup/" data-href="https://www.pinterest.com/ezagroba/fancy-a-cup/" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;My perfect cup of coffee is tea&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s my version of toast:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://127.0.0.1:8000/images/posts/2016/toaster.jpeg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="1. Break off a piece of baguette. 2. Put it in the toaster oven for five minutes when it’s a darker color. 3. Serve on a plate. 4. Butter is too hard to draw."&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;1. Break off a piece of baguette. 2. Put it in the toaster oven for five minutes when it’s a darker color. 3. Serve on a plate. 4. Butter is too hard to draw.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name="b06f" id="b06f" class="graf graf--p graf-after--figure"&gt;I drew my toast with a few steps involving a baguette and a toaster oven. Most others had more steps that involved money, stores, butter, sliced bread, and a conventional toaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="6e6c" id="6e6c" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Patrick used our descriptions and drawings as a springboard to distinguish tacit (unstated, assumed) from explicit (stated, known) knowledge. By asking questions to clarify the assignment and our audience, we could have made the task more explicit and come closer to the tacit expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="d18b" id="d18b" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Just as with breakfast, testers need to be able to question assumptions and accurately describe their processes in the course of their work like when they:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="370b" id="370b" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;Describe steps to reproduce a bug.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="7b73" id="7b73" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Write a training manual or other technical documentation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="30b2" id="30b2" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Code a test script.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p name="4a0d" id="4a0d" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;Providing too little context confuses the audience. Providing too much context distracts them. Finding a balance is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="881f" id="881f" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;The Human Factor: Exploring Social Engineering — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thetestdoctor" data-href="https://twitter.com/thetestdoctor" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;Dan Billing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="7320" id="7320" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Dan’s presentation changed how I want to test and generally live my life. I thought I was comfortable with how much personal information I shared, both on the internet and in person. Dan had us try to find out as much as we could about someone else in the room by Googling them. And showering them with flattery. I was able to get a lot out of people. It was probably enough information to guess a password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="b68f" id="b68f" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Before the end of the presentation, I was completely paranoid about what every salesperson, person around the office, or person near my calendar or phone could be learning about me. But Dan shared a deeply personal story with us. He trusted us. So after destroying my faith in humanity, Dan helped restore it. Thanks Dan!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="dd2a" id="dd2a" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Dan shared his slides and more information about social engineering &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/1rCOmx1" data-href="http://bit.ly/1rCOmx1" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="bf7e" id="bf7e" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;Gaining Consciousness — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FionaCCharles" data-href="https://twitter.com/FionaCCharles" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;Fiona Charles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="b94c" id="b94c" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Fiona’s closing keynote centered around a paired exercise. One person was the business owner, explaining their context to the tester. The other person was a tester, asking questions about the context. After a few minutes of brainstorming, the pair compared notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="e43c" id="e43c" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;Ideally, the business owner would have given the tester all the right details to answer the tester’s questions. But no pair had a complete matching set of information. Overwhelmingly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="postList"&gt;&lt;li name="6e65" id="6e65" class="graf graf--li graf-after--p"&gt;Testers did not ask about the business model.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li name="ac40" id="ac40" class="graf graf--li graf-after--li"&gt;Business owners didn’t provide information about the users or politics of the people on the project.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p name="9d9e" id="9d9e" class="graf graf--p graf-after--li"&gt;So testers and the business owners rarely start on the same page. To get more in sync, Fiona recommended having a periodic sanity check of your test strategy with the business owner. We need a space to say “Here’s what I’m thinking about. What do you think?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="1ba0" id="1ba0" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p"&gt;&lt;strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong"&gt;Other presentations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name="4968" id="4968" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing"&gt;I’m still thinking and talking about all the presentations I attended. Thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/robertasabourin" data-href="https://twitter.com/robertasabourin" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Sabourin&lt;/a&gt;, Anne DeSimone, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/teglbjaerg" data-href="https://twitter.com/teglbjaerg" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bolette Stubbe Teglbjærg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/a_cederholm" data-href="https://twitter.com/a_cederholm" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Andreas Cederholm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/clebond" data-href="https://twitter.com/clebond" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Christopher Lebond&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/helenaj_m" data-href="https://twitter.com/helenaj_m" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Helena Jeret-Mäe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brickuz" data-href="https://twitter.com/brickuz" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Erik Brickarp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/robbowyer" data-href="https://twitter.com/robbowyer" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Bowyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vds4" data-href="https://twitter.com/vds4" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Martin Hynie&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dsynadinos" data-href="https://twitter.com/dsynadinos" class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Damian Synadinos&lt;/a&gt;. I’m enormously grateful to all the presenters at Let’s Test, the conference for giving me the opportunity to speak, and everyone I talked to over those three days. Learning more about your journeys is what keeps me in this profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ezagroba/some-takeaways-from-lets-test-2016-8ad6d37d0f67"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><guid>http://127.0.0.1:8000/posts/2016/2016-07-13_some-takeaways-from-let-s-test-2016/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>