<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Organizational Anarchist (Posts about conference)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/conference.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 18:55:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>EuroSTAR Testing Voices 2021</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/01_29_eurostar_testing_voices/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In June of 2021, EuroSTAR ran a &lt;a href="https://huddle.eurostarsoftwaretesting.com/testing-voices-2021/"&gt;free online event&lt;/a&gt;. Having either Maaret Pyhäjärvi and Keith Klain on the program would have been enough to add this to my calendar; having both got me there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Maaret Pyhäjärvi: Testing Becoming Harder to be Valuable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, Maaret sees a bright and exciting future for her role that I have trouble reconciling with my reality. In Maaret's vision, crowdsourced testers find the obvious bugs. She's left to skim the cream off the milk,  performing the interesting, thoughtful work of understanding a complex system. She and her fellow testers are not repositories for or regurgitators of information. They share testing ideas before they become results or automated tests, with the goal of making others more productive. They tell compelling stories of the unseen: bugs that never happened, testing they never performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dream big Maaret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Panel: Different Teams, Different Testers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veerle Verhagen hosted this panel. If you're feeling a bit exhausted, I can recommend a small dose of Veerle directly to your brain. These were my top three takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best way to skill up automation is to do it on the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can give assignments back. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raise problems even if they're outside the current scope. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keith Klain: Test as Transformation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith speaks from a position of connecting testing to the business strategy, which is exactly what he recommends we all do. Talk the talk of driving innovation and managing risk to get people's attention and connect what you're doing to the money. Writing a pile of cheap flaky checks (or even consistently passing ones!) may give you a false sense of security that hides the bigger risks. Strive to gather more information to soundly evaluate the risks in your products, enough to understand what would have happened if you hadn't caught it and how to prevent something similar in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the EuroSTAR team for pulling this together and (not charging for it). &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/01_29_eurostar_testing_voices/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Agile Testing Days 2021</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/agile_testing_days_2021/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/unicorn-colors.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;Amazingly, a week physically away from work and present with other human software tester beings was refreshing. And I didn't contract COVID — shoutout to vaccines! Note to self: bring honey, because your voice will be tired from talking through an N95 mask in a loud room. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much &lt;a href="https://agiletestingdays.com/"&gt;Agile Testing Days&lt;/a&gt; for the honor and privilege of serving on your program committee this year, and the straight-up spoiling that comes with attending a conference and not speaking. I've said for years that I enjoy the learning more than the being-in-the-spotlight. This year's edition allowed me to do just that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Dagmar Monett - Coming to terms with intelligence in machines&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody can agree on what intelligence is; it's context-dependent and culture-bound. Human-level AI is not inevitable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Klaartje van Zwoll - How therapy made me a better teamplayer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All needs are valid! By making your needs specific, it's easier for others to meet them. Journaling can help close the gap between when you experience a thing and when you analyze it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boundaries are high-quality information that people need to love you best. If someone crosses a boundary: specify the behavior, tell them the story of how it made you feel, and describe both the behavior you'd prefer and how that would improve things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you say no, sit in the discomfort of the silence instead of offering excuses. Klaartje also did a great explanation of ask culture vs. guess culture which I've filed as American/Dutch vs. British/Belgian in my head. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Alex Schladebeck - Unit Testing and TDD from the tester perspective&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of decisions get made when we're writing code that we never talk about. Writing unit tests for legacy code is hard! Being curious (instead of incredulous) gets you (and your pair) to learn more and have better conversations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Maryam Umar - The Power of Coaching for Leading Test Teams&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions Maryam asked the audience that are worth a bit of reflection: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are my career goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I want to change personally? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I value? What do I enjoy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What outcomes are within my control?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Gitte Klitgaard - The choice is yours&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choices still happen even if they're not active choices. Options expire. When you make a commitment at the last responsible moment, remember the &lt;em&gt;responsible&lt;/em&gt; part. There's space between the stimulus and the response where you can choose how you react. Be the captain of your own ship! We have so much more influence than we think. We can't have everything at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Raj Subrameyer - It is time for Toxic Leaders to come out of their closet&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Masculinity is toxic. Moving on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Jutta Eckstein - Agile Comes with a Responsibility for Sustainability.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software consumes energy: take responsibility. Change your definition of done. Shift the question we ask in and around the product. Testers are the right people to start doing that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Zeb Ford-Reitz - What's a Quality Dojo?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zeb's quality dojo: low-risk, low-commitment, high-safety, and long-running. The learning is the product. (The product is the friends you make along the way?) If something is unclear, you need to ask. If you're hoping for a particular outcome, it's not so much an experiment as a bet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;9. João Proença - Limitless within our boundaries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a lot of choices is not necessarily better than only having a few choices. Making decisions all the time will lead to decision fatigue. Embrace the constraints that life gives you. Charters and time-boxes are constraints for exploratory testing. Set up the right constraints to be successful: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the risks you're mitigating?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;10. Lena Wilberg - Delivering fast &amp;amp; slow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be aware of what is the worst that can happen. Know &lt;a href="https://nordictestingdays.eu/files/files/fiona_charles-10_commandments_for_ethical_testers_keynote_ntd2017.pdf"&gt;Fiona Charles's 10 Commandments for Ethical Software Testers&lt;/a&gt;. Know your personal and career risk tolerance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;11. Bruce Hughes - How to be an Ally to Non-binary Folk in Tech&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never again should you have to explain or justify your existence. Listening is a beautiful skill. Labels are for communicating with other people. You don't owe anyone your time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;12. Lisi Hocke - Growing an Experiment-driven Quality Culture&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include a hypotehsis in your experiments. Identify exit criteria, whether or not you succeed. Are the teams ready, eager, and committed? What is the goal? Tackle the unknown, automate the known. Build on people's curiosity. Metrics work locally, temporarily, in context, at the grassroots level. What information do we need for each context? Raise awareness about options. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;13. Dr. Karen Holland - Food for Thought&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental healthy people can cope with the normal stresses of life. Healthy diets allow us to cope better. Deficiences cannot be fixed by food alone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;14. Vera Baum - The Tester's Learning Toolkit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts produce extraordinary results over a long period of time, but only come about after deliberate practice for four hours a day for ten years. Experts should analyze intuitive reactions. Becoming an expert is not everyone's goal! Only generic knowledge is transferrable. Training wheels are holding you back — you can learn from your failures. Reflection is key. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;15. Vernon Richards - What does the 'Coach' in 'Quality Coach' mean?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reward structures can promote anti-patterns. Be comfortable with silence. Stay in the present. Notice how they're saying something, and how they're feeling about what they're saying. Decide when to &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/give_them_the_fish_then_teach_them_to_fish/"&gt;give them the answer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the urge to name-drop all my friends here, but also, who cares? This isn't a popularity contest. Just look at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23agiletd"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to see who was there.  I'm grateful to everyone who I was able to give an suspicious eyebrow across the table to, everyone who shared commentary during sessions, everyone whose conversations caused me to skip a session, everyone who patiently waited for me to poorly construct and pronounce Dutch sentences at them, everyone who thought it was fine for me to have a mask on, and most especially, whoever left a piano unlocked. Thank you, and please leave the grand piano unlocked next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have the urge to apologize for all the exclamation points in these notes, but I regret to inform you that (1) they do reflect my actual enthusiasm over hearing these message delivered directly from someone's mouth into my ears, and (2) I look forward to the day when our writing can reflect how we'd like to communicate instead of how the patriarchy expects us to. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>agile-testing-days</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/agile_testing_days_2021/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 10:08:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TestBash Manchester 2019, The Last One</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/test_bash_manchester_2019/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/growthvsfixed.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I didn't know in September of 2019 that TestBash Manchester was the last TestBash I'd be attending for a while. I've revisited my notes from the workshop Joep Schuurkes and I ran about test reporting several times since then: for a video series, an &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/series/testing-ask-me-anything"&gt;Ask Me Anything&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://club.ministryoftesting.com/t/ask-me-anything-test-reporting/46827"&gt;forum thread&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/events/essentials-an-introduction-to-reporting-your-testing"&gt;99-minute workshop&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/map_out_your_stakeholders/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. I'm just revisiting my notes now from the talks I was able to attend in the couple days after our workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My notes from Pierre Vincent's talk on observability read like a wishlist of features I'd already been asking for in the app I was testing: unit testing, centralized logging, trace ids for integration debugging, etc. The app was also in a private beta at the time, so data collected from production would be filled with more anomalies than patterns. I'm still discovering how much more influence I have in my new role as Quality Lead to present the impact and influence the improvement of testability features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan Smart and Yong He spoke about failure. The quote "Hey failors, how's the failing?" captures the essence of their talk: expect failure, and celebrate it, together. I get psyched anytime distinguishes between a fixed and a growth mindset as they did, which I still find best described in &lt;a href="https://www.themarginalian.org/2014/01/29/carol-dweck-mindset/"&gt;this Marginalian (formerly Brain Pickings) piece&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see in my notes from Conor Fitzgerald's talk on Kanban that kan = visual and ban = card. In the two years I spent running a Kanban team in the meantime, I can't remember how many times a week (a day? a minute of standup?) I asked "should we visualize that on the board?" Two of my big legacies on my former team were reinforced by Conor's talk: 1) eliminating of context-switching, and 2) not waiting until the retro to make changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What does it mean to be responsible for quality?" asks Past Elizabeth to Present Elizabeth from the notes on Gary Fleming's continuous testing talk. It doesn't have a straightforward answer, and exploring this is part of what my job gets to be now. Some of his examples (separating deployment from release, example mapping) are what I get to inspire my whole department to consider as part of their strategy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saskia Coplans's talk on security testing really stuck with me. Her ability to make the unnamable company she consulted for a joke every time she mentioned it was a level of comedy I can only dream of aspiring to in a talk. Familiarity with the STRIDE model and the OWASP Top 10 gives me a leg up in thinking about how to identify and mitigate risk in our software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Areti Panou's talk about a deployment pipeline resonates more deeply now, after two years of running and maintaining a pipeline, than it did at the time, when a pipeline was just a glimmer in the eye of a teammate. I held an expectation setting and reaffirmation workshop about one pipeline in my department last week. Areti's expectations that a pipeline should have a clear purpose, failure criteria, and fix deadlines could help fix the bystander effect I've experienced myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incomparable and unstoppable Lisi Hocke gave a talk about becoming more code-confident that still influences how I approach goals and objectives. Specifically: it's ok to re-evaluate if goals should still apply, and to establish pause or exit criteria to know when to give up. While I can be strong in saying no to what others expect, giving up on something I expect of myself can still be a struggle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Matthews's talk on technical risks with AI prompted me to add a "write about these times when you tested a machine learning application" card to the backlog for this blog. I wonder if I'll get around to writing that, since it would be hard to explain it better than Bill did that day. He talked about how training data reinforces stereotypes, and how understanding the domain is crucial to determining what's a random failure vs. what's a systematic failure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Louise Gibbs gave a talk on starting her automation journey with a record and playback tool. That's also what got me excited about automation originally, and I'm etnerally grateful to have had the right people steer me towards tests at a lower application level before UI auomation became the only tool in my toolbelt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suman Bala's introduction to Charles Proxy was a memorable one. She'd hooked up her phone to the projected screen without turning her notifications off, so we got to see all the tweets streaming in in real time! If you're just diving into Charles Proxy, the &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/breaking-boundaries-using-charles-suman-bala"&gt;recording of this talk&lt;/a&gt; is a great place to start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominic Kua's talk on bash commands, Wim Selles's talk on Appium, and Henrik Stene's talks on consumer-driven contracts definitely fell into the "these people really know their tool" category. If they were tools I was using, I'd certainly consult their tips and advice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily Bache's talk shared the ideas from the State of DevOps reports and ultimately the Accelerate book. As a team lead and co-host for a testing ensemble, I was able to help empower people across teams and help build a culture of psychological safety. In my new role as Quality Lead, I'm just starting to collect the DORA metrics to help me decide where I should focus my efforts within the department. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a memorable group of people, location, and journey it was to TestBash Manchester 2019. I hope the &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/news/testbash-brighton-2022-cancellation-and-testbash-uk"&gt;upcoming TestBash UK&lt;/a&gt; is in the cards for me this coming year, and not only because I still dream about &lt;a href="https://www.mowglistreetfood.com/"&gt;this Indian food&lt;/a&gt; I had on the way in and out of Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>testbash</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/test_bash_manchester_2019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SoCraTes UK June 2021 </title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/socrates_uk_june_2021/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/socrates-schedule.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I had a long drought between when I was last able to just attend a conference (rather than running a session or organizing) and SoCraTes UK in June. A year I think? And what a welcome rain it was. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heloá hosted a session on meditation. I recognized many of the symptoms she described as her motivators for picking up the habit from &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/assets/slides/introvert.pdf"&gt;a talk I did about introversion years ago&lt;/a&gt;. And the mindset she described (trying over succeeding, recognizing reactions without trying to impose a particular one) echoed back to a conversation on stoicism that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SimplySanne"&gt;Sanne Visser&lt;/a&gt; hosted at the first TestCraftCamp. I was completely convinced by the benefits she described ("People say I sound calmer. I'm breathing more deeply.") but I haven't built a habit around it yet. C'est la vie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to two different sessions &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maaretp"&gt;Maaret Pyhäjärvi&lt;/a&gt; hosted. (Does this make me a groupie?) The first, an ensemble testing session, reminded me that the most valuable exploratory testing bugs come when you understand enough about the business and the architecture to know what matters to some person who matters. The second session was about scaling workshops (and really, herself). I joined late after the lightning talks ended, but still helped plant the seed of what I and SoCraTes can do to bring more people into learning about good software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I selfishly hosted a "help me out here" session in the afternoon. As I predicted, the testers extraordinaire Maaret and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke"&gt;Lisi Hocke&lt;/a&gt; were exactly the people I needed to give me perspective on my current and evolving role at work, though the other attendees contributed as well. I came away with more questions than answers, which I'm still mulling over and digging into weeks later. I look forward to sharing more about the shape of things as they come to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander (What is your last name?? Sorry!) held a session on habits you've developed or changed during the pandemic. How lovely it was to be in a small conversation trading notes about remote music lesssons and holding remote workshops. It was exactly the kind of hallway conversation I'd be looking to fall into at a flesh-and-blood conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't write down who gave the lightning talk about saying no, but thank you. I rarely (never?) regret saying no, but I needed that extra push and specific language to have those "If you want me to pick this up, which of these things should I be putting down then?" conversations I've had lately. I have "Saying no commands respect" in my notes, and I guess I need a throw pillow of that too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SoCraTes reinforces for me how a welcoming, inclusive open space is done. It's through &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmelieCornelis/status/1393945719413825542"&gt;explaining what an open space is for people who haven't attended&lt;/a&gt;. It's who's on the organizing committee. It's reminding people to take time off from the sessions. It's about ending up in the "Rose Garden" at the same time as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EvaNanyonga"&gt;Eva Nanyonga&lt;/a&gt;, who's working to improve the dispatching of home helathcare workers in Uganda, and finding out you sparked her curiosity and delight in the exploratory testing session earlier in the day. It's about providing a subsidized ticket option to make the event accessible to more people. It's in offering advice to the hosts at the start, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask for help facilitating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kick off the discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include everyone in the conversation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for holding this space. It's got me excited to host the open space that TestCraftCamp has evolved into, Friends of Good Software (&lt;a href="https://frogsconf.nl/"&gt;FroGS Conf&lt;/a&gt;) in September. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/socrates_uk_june_2021/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My First Agile Testing Days: Four Years Later</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/agile_testing_days_2017/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;After years of getting rejected, the talk I submitted to Agile Testing Days in 2017 finally got me accepted. It was such a privilege and an honor to meet so many of the people I'd only know from the internet. Reading through my notes now, much of what I wrote down has become engrained into how I go about my work everyday. What a blessing it was to encounter the people I needed to learn from in my career at the time I needed to learn from them. I'm glad to see how routine their wisdom has become for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke"&gt;Lisi Hocke&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk about growth. I've since seen more of her talks and prepared a workshop with her; I see how she embodies this in her approach to the world. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NativeWired"&gt;Gitte Klitgaard&lt;/a&gt; reminded me that believing in people will allow them to be better. Stay curious about why people are doing what they do before placing judgment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Punkmik"&gt;Kim Knup&lt;/a&gt; spoke about a zero bug policy (not any bugs in your backlog). I was not ready to hear this message at the time, having come from places with years-old products and tens or hundreds of bugs in the backlog. But now I see exactly what she was describing: the psychological relief that comes from less time in JIRA and fewer meetings about priorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/katrinaclokie"&gt;Katrina Clokie&lt;/a&gt; pulled up Noah Sussman's reimagining of the testing pyrmaid (lots of small tests, fewer large ones) upside-down as a bug filter. And suddenly, it clicked for me. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alex_schl"&gt;Alex Schladebeck&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots"&gt;Huib Schoots&lt;/a&gt; challenged me to think on a meta-level about the testing I was doing, to name the skills and techniques I was using. It would help me as I spent the following years sharing exploratory testing skills with other testers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ewebber"&gt;Emily Webber&lt;/a&gt; spoke about building trust on teams. I find myself recommending the &lt;a href="https://emilywebber.co.uk/the-team-manual-a-exercise-to-help-build-empathy-in-teams/"&gt;team manual&lt;/a&gt; she developed to somebody about once a month, plus she helped spark an idea for a future conference talk I developed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lunivore"&gt;Liz Keogh&lt;/a&gt; gave me the words I needed to build a safe-to-fail environment for my team members, where failure is an expected, inevitable part of complex systems. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized in compiling this blog post that I'd already written about Agile Testing Days just one month after I'd attended in 2017. At that point, I was looking specifically at regression testing advice, which is what I was in the thick of at work. What am I in the thick of now, and when will it become clear to me?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>agile-testing-days</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/agile_testing_days_2017/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TestCraftCamp: Spice Up Your Relationship (with Your Project)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/testcraftcamp_spice_up_your_relationship_with_your_project/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/tcc-mar-2021.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://testcraftcamp.nl/"&gt;TestCraftCamp&lt;/a&gt;, the unconference I co-organize, had its third installment yesterday. I'm glad I had enough energy to attend more sessions this time, though of course the "too many good things happen at once" problem remained, as it does with any valuable conference. I was able to join a discussion &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maaretp"&gt;Maaret Pyhäjärvi&lt;/a&gt; (who is so often a driving force behind gatherings like these) about low and high value work, a discussion Joep Schuurkes led on daily writing practices, part of a session &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/witchofthetest"&gt;Veerle Verhagen&lt;/a&gt; hosted on testing without touching (before I realized I'd spent too long looking at the product under test already), as well as finding some of my brethren in between the sessions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took notes in a sprawling mind map for another session Veerle hosted, which she pitched as "spicing up your long-term relationship! (with your project)." Besides the memorable pitch, I was excited to see this topic on the schedule for a couple reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I've been working on my current product for two years. Some new people have joined the project recently, and having to explain and document the intricacies of our product keeps giving me new reasons to question the decisions we've made as the product has been developed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I don't think this it's something we typically acknowledge: our skills can get stale and our motivation can wane when we've developed a certain level of comfort and mastery with a particular team and product. Even without changing jobs or teams, it can be worthwhile to shake things up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my project, adding permanent designers and engineers to the team is shaking things up. The hive mind in the session came up with many other ways to get new people involved in testing, if temporarily: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hold a bug hunt or an &lt;a href="https://www.lisihocke.com/2021/02/ensemble-is-the-new-mob.html"&gt;ensemble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;teach an intern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;swap products with another tester&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bring your product to a meetup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pay for &lt;a href="https://www.hackerone.com/product/bounty"&gt;crowdsourced testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collected a sprawling list of people's ideas for how you as an individual can gain perspective and change the way you're looking at your work. Taking notes on a multi-faceted conversation is hard, and in reviewing them, I realize they fall better into these groups: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify the assumptions you've built over time (which aren't true? which can be discarded? what's hard to talk about? how can I change perspective?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;think about risks (&lt;a href="https://testobsessed.com/2006/12/the-nightmare-headline-game-planning-for-the-unexpected/"&gt;nightmare headlines&lt;/a&gt;, investigate competitors, talk to users, &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/testsphere/riskstorming"&gt;riskstorming&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use different testing personas (extreme conditions, &lt;a href="https://www.logigear.com/logi_media_dir/Documents/whitepapers/soap_opera_testing.pdf"&gt;soap operas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.stickyminds.com/article/10-exploratory-testing-tours-you-can-use-analyze-artifacts"&gt;testing tours&lt;/a&gt;, dogfooding/drinking your own champagne, &lt;a href="https://theuserisdrunk.com/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;step back (take a break, go on vacation, switch projects)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a counterpoint, the group in the session did acknowledge that reaching a point of comfort and mastery can be a good thing. (See chapter 4 of &lt;a href="https://leanpub.com/becomingatechnicalleader"&gt;Jerry Weinberg's Becoming a Technical Leader&lt;/a&gt; for more on plateaus and ravines.) After months or years on a project, you'll know where to look first for what your developers typically miss. You'll know what's not worth testing. In Veerle's case, the application has been getting 5-star reviews, which provides one positive angle on product quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks so much to the facilitators, participants, and other organizers of TestCraftCamp. It's so fulfilling to get to the end of a long day and hear that we created a "safe environment," people who were only planning to stay for the morning lasted all day, and people were able to take breaks when they needed to. I'm glad we were able to fill others back up with energy. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>note-taking</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/testcraftcamp_spice_up_your_relationship_with_your_project/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TestBash NYC 2015: A Push in the Right Direction</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/testbash_nyc_2015/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/testbash-nyc.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 2015 when TestBash came to the United States for the first time, it was to New York. I was living in the city, but I was stuck at a job that wouldn't pay for a ticket. "Ask Rosie if you can volunteer," my mentor/sponsor/benefactor Martin Hynie suggested. Rosie, who I knew only as the lady who'd mailed me Ministry of Testing stickers from England for...no reason at all, obviously let me in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People ask "can we do it?" instead of asking "should we do it?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to crash the speakers dinner. I got to go to Selena Delesie's workshop about leadership and change. At the end of the day, she praised my active participation and thanked me for being in her workshop. I was already confident in my testing skills, but she helped me see myself as a potential leader. In a follow-up coaching session I had with Selena about negotiating a higher salary, she asked me why I wanted more money. I'd recently moved into an apartment by myself, and couldn't think of what I would do with more money. It's something I think about with every job change, every growth in title and responsibility. Realizing I didn't want or need more money was a crucial step on the path to life-changing relocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common denominator in all your dysfunctional relationships is you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Keith Klain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a break between talks the following day, I snuck on stage wearing "the" Ministry of Testing tutu. During another, I wrote a bunch of notes to give a 99-second talk about leaving a closing comment on a story (which I completely forgot about, &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/defining-story-completion-as-a-software-tester"&gt;before later writing on this topic for the Dojo&lt;/a&gt;). While waiting on stage behind dozens of people waiting to give their 99-second talks, I improvised one about moonwalking instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/99-second-talk.jpg" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="The 99-second talk I didn't give"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;The 99-second talk I didn't give&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Helena Jeret-Mäe, Maaret Pyhäjärvi, Dan Ashby, who along with the conference friendships I was just beginning to foster, gave me a vision of what my career could be, and where it could go at a time when I knew I needed something different. Helena saw my talk at Let's Test the following spring, and gave me valuable critical feedback that helped shaped future talks. Maaret introduced me to strong-style pairing, which changed the way I worked with my colleagues to this day. Dan had me on his podcast, reinforcing for me the success of my talk at the following year's TestBash USA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down when you receive a compliment. Maybe it's true. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~&lt;cite&gt;Helena Jeret-Mäe&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I revisiting my notes from this conference six years later? I might be feeling a bit nostalgic for the seeing-people-in-person events a year into pandemic-induced isolation. I'm also in the middle of reading "Becoming a Technical Leader" by Jerry Weinberg. One of the questions asks you to read an autobiography of someone you admire. It turns out none of the people I shared TestBash NYC with have published autobiographies...yet. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>conference</category><category>testbash</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/testbash_nyc_2015/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Karen Johnson at CAST 2015</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/karen_johnson_moving_testing_forward_cast_2015/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/karen-johnson.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was about to throw away a whole notebook full of conference notes I'd already blogged about. But because I'd already shipped these notes across an ocean and ignored them for a few years, I figured I'd give them a final read first. Luckily I found a few pages of gems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen Johnson's talk at CAST (The Conference for the Association of Software Testing) in 2015 covered the breath and depth of her experience in the software industry. I've taken on the career coaching role for some colleagues, and so much of what Karen emphasized is what I've been saying to them as they try to advocate for that promotion, discover their next step, or accept that they have done the best they could given the circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mi5R3mOILrw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Testers should have a portfolio&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you make your work visible? Particularly when your work is invisible when done well? Tell people about it in standups. Tell your boss at your 1-on-1. Write it down and then share a link the next time it comes up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;If you were to do a retro on yourself, what would you want it to be?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen advocated for giving back to the community, and challenged the gentleman who pointed out this was not strictly part of the job description. "That's just who I am." The senior roles at my current company are often differentiated not by technical prowess, but by building others up. Sharing to a big audience trips people up, but the steady radiating of information in writing, pairing with people to solve problems, and being the go-to person for questions serves to enrich and scale a company more effectively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Where's the gap between what you're doing now and what you want to do?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I'm able to concretely address within my company, when I know how the departments are structured and how the job descriptions fit into the org chart. I've made a list (or tasked my colleagues to do this for themselves) comparing their current job description to the one they're aiming for. Next to each item, list what you're already doing to fill that gap, or at least one thing you could be doing in that direction. Sometimes it's a matter of recognizing for yourself how much you already do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Your boss may never be your mentor&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These talks from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vXIZpe-x4o8"&gt;Marianne Duijst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/the-lost-art-of-the-journeyman-martin-hynie"&gt;Martin Hynie&lt;/a&gt; dive into this deeper, but find help where you can get it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;In five years you might specialize in something that doesn't exist today&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel a bit silly asking people in 2021 where they see themselves in the future, or even what they want for themselves. Don't feel bad if you don't have it all planned out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How to get promoted&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be reliable, dependable, the one to be counted on, and willing to take on more. Who wouldn't want someone like that around all the time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen says during the talk that she doesn't know what mark she will leave on the testing community. I certainly appreciate this bit of her wisdom. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/karen_johnson_moving_testing_forward_cast_2015/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Agile Testing Days 2020</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-11-29_agile_testing_days_2020/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;When you say no to what you don't have the energy for, you leave your time, attention, and devotion free to pursue what keeps you energized. Through a tumult of plans and dreams that only 2020 could continue to crush, the Agile Testing Days crew put on a revitalizing conference. I only caught a glimpse of the preparation that went into providing a top-notch experience for speakers and participants, and I have to commend the group on their commitment to the cause. Bravo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talks were recorded. I've decided to cut myself off on catching up on missed talks after two weeks. Reflecting on what wisdom I've garned from a small subset of the offerings at Agile Testing Days will be more valuable than being exposed to every last word. In that spirit, let me give you a few takeaways in place of an exhaustive recap or analysis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parveen Khan: watch this if you're looking to collaborate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is in doing the work that we discover what we must do. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't get stuck when learning something alone; pair. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;João Proença: watch this if you need a different direction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing a health check and making a diagnosis are different skills. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What barriers do we set for ourselves?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The product is all the pieces the customers see, including the cloud infrastructure (and whatever else your team isn't responsible for). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Holland &amp;amp; Huib Schoots: watch this if your automation isn't providing valuable information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sunk cost fallacy means we're unlikely to get rid of automation code, even if it's ineffective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We often fail at getting people to change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gitte Kligaard talk: watch this if you've been hiding your true self at work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I'm just going to rewind." (Possibly my favorite takeaway from this conference, I'm going to use this anytime I trip over my words.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creativity comes when inspired by others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being professional is knowing your craft, and admitting when you don't know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend time with yourself to listen to yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Schladebeck &amp;amp; Ashley Hunsberger: no recording, but follow these ladies on Twitter for how to balance life and leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell people what you want. They may be able to help you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a clear vision of what you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down your fear. Ask yourself: Why is this positive? How can I build the courage to do this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be explicit about what you're doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show how you're working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a practice of reflection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angie Jones: watch this if you need a push to get into automation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine your goal first. If you don't know it, you'll definitely fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you're a leader, celebrate the small victories. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's no reason to shame people for being creative and doing the best they can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's not realistic to assume master level by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out why developers don't participate in automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob Meaney: watch this if you don't get why observability is important&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We learn profound lessons from painful experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build relationships. Influence people at the right time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pain + reflection =&amp;gt; progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't matter how much we test a thing if nobody wants to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobias Geyer: watch this if you're struggling with an ethical dilemna &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could ethics be a non-functional requirement?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the codes of ethics proposed by the IEEE, ISTQB, ACM, and James Bach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A hippocrattic oath for software testing: avoid harm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote environment sustainability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smita Mishra: watch this if you're interviewing users &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to be able to ask clarifying questions and dig deeper. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask users: their objective, what they found, about the impact, where they're struggling, what could make their lives easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eveline Moolenaars: watch this if you're learning to coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"We have a policy; it's somewhere on the internet" isn't enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Everyone deserves a coach to make them aware of what they've forgotten." ~Brad Gilbert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federico Toledo: watch this if you or those around you are losing steam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tester with a sense of purpose is more resilient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on strengths more than weaknesses, turning up the good. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide visibility that you're doing something with the feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask people if they're getting what they need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicola Sedgwick: watch this if you're the gatekeeper for quality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not correlate your own successes with the quality of the entire system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contract-driven work is not holistic quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report when there has been no progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for a code walk-through before a build is ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift quality left all the way to the executive team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testers were hoarding responsibility for quality. Let it go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joep Schuurkes: watch this if (or while) you're stuck in an ineffective meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: is my work inside or outside of meetings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the right group of people in the room before holding a meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Express specific appreciations for things done well so people will keep doing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meetings are synchornous collaboration with a purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standups should remove impediments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The metaphors we choose say something about how we feel about our work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership is creating an environment where everyone can contribute to solving a problem. ~Jerry Weinberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clare Norman: watch this if you're truly stuck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality is everyone's care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Success is liking who you are, what you do, and how you do it." ~Maya Angelou&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your courage quota for the day might vary. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don't get better by doing the same thing everyday. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn't know how I needed to be helped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can't drag someone through time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We live far less in the present than we ought to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How magical is it when people value the change that you're making?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passion spreads when other people share in your excitement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a cheerleader in your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/success.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Clare Norman channeling Maya Angelou on success"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Clare Norman channeling Maya Angelou on success&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny Bramble: watch this if your tests are failing on expected behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many defects I filed are never fixed. Unfixed defects become expected behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation has never found a defect. Automation tells us behavior has changed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests should pass on expected behavior, including some defects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document your tests for others, including your future self.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Lyndsay &amp;amp; Anne Colder: watch this if you feel like an impostor &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge when you can't help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you could take one step forward, what would you do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to your person, or ask a smaller group of people if they have an answer to your problem. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forgiveness is one of the most powerful things you can do as a human being.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After you make a mistake: wallow in it (really feel it first), forgive yourself, then dance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your job title allows other people to figure out how to work with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gitte Klitgaard AMA: watch this if you miss the hallway track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to hear what's being said, not to respond. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can't read minds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a safe space allows you to feel uncomfortable. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silence is a tool. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sophie Küster: watch this if you're ready to tell your colleagues your big secret&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is strength in showing vulnerability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People want to help you. Let them. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: how am I treating myself?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything worth doing is worth doing poorly. Poorly done is better than not done at all. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gitte Klitgaard &amp;amp; Morgan Ahlström: watch this if you want to get psychological safety in the boardroom and on the roadmap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make time to address psychological safety. Put it on the same level in your team's goals as your product goals. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are role models. We lead by example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More people were uncomfortable giving than receiving code reviews. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ard Kramer: watch this if you're getting burned out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humans have an unrealitic belief in our own influence. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing your testing role doesn't make you popular. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most people looking for confirmation that the software is working. To form a logical proof, we look for evidence that the software doesn't work. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: which circumstances could I control? Did I manage expectations correctly? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm grateful I got to connect with people who keep me going. I'm grateful Agile Testing Days tried to make this work in person. I'm grateful I was able to drop my workshop instead of abaondoning people in breakout rooms to do something they've never done before. I'm grateful the mobbing session I helped organize and facilitate went smoothly. I'm grateful that my job allows me the time and space to be rejunivated by this all. I'm grateful.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>agile-testing-days</category><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-11-29_agile_testing_days_2020/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SoCraTes UK, August 2020</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-08-02_socrates-uk-august-2020/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;After years of envying the tweets and stories from SoCraTes conferences, this cursèd disease finally made attending one possible. I could afford the time (part of one day, instead of a whole weekend + travel) and the cost (£2.50, instead of €€€). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm preparing to host an open space of our own in September (&lt;a href="http://testcraftcamp.nl/"&gt;TestCraftCamp&lt;/a&gt;, tickets are free!), so aside from the sessions, I was also interested in the infrastructure of the event. The hosts hung out in one central Zoom room (a one-month subscription cost them £10). Each attendee was appointed co-host, allowing us to move around among the many breakout rooms as we pleased. (There may have been as many breakout rooms as there were participants, named with varying levels of creativity but functionally the same.) A &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/"&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; board captured the user-generated schedule, along with links to the &lt;a href="https://www.mural.co/"&gt;Mural&lt;/a&gt; whiteboards the organizers created for each room, rather than for each session. Chat happened in a &lt;a href="https://discord.com/"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; channel, but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1287372791168278529"&gt;I wouldn't recommend it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first session I attended was a discussion about the value and hazards of leaving a job. First: decide where you want to go, what kind of thing you're looking for. You're not going to get where you want to go by running away from your current role. Run &lt;em&gt;towards&lt;/em&gt; something. Have honest conversations with your peers, manager, mentor, coach, etc. about what change you can affect at the organization. (Things like the nature of the product, the tech stack, or the customer base are unlikely to change quickly.) If you do decide to change jobs, it will take a lot of energy to find something new and build your network at the new place. You may have to prove yourself all over again, and solve the problems you've already solved with this different group of people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After taking a total of three bullet points in my notebook, the host of the second session I attended about hypergrowth was having trouble taking notes and listening to/facilitating the session. I volunteered to jump in to take the notes. Here's what I made:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2020/hypergrowth.png" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Notes from hypergrowth session"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Notes from hypergrowth session&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was trying to capture what people said, change the background colors, and move the notes around to put similar ideas next to each other. It was hard to know in the moment whether all of that is legible or helpful for anyone else. Luckily people in the session and in the Discord channel later thanked me for my work. I'm still struggling with how to impart any note-taking skill onto others, particularly when this can be seen as a gendered task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men: Wow, you are so good at taking notes!&lt;br&gt;
Me: You would be too if you got stuck being the one doing it all the time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I digress, back to hypergrowth: The things that worked before COVID and at smaller orgs don't work at a bigger org today. Find your people within the smaller org - your department, your mentor, your friends - so you can feel stable even as things around you grow and change. Communicate your expectations clearly, for yourself and for your team. Keep a journal of what you've accomplished to feel more anchored in the value of your work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch, I started off in the wrong room because I didn't notice the sessions had been moved, but found my way to the one about coaching your peers. The conversation floated from a definition of terms to how to make space for mentoring. In order for people to mentor, there must be consent from the mentee. Ideally there is also some expertise in the organization around what is good, and someone (mentor or not) to teach the mentee what is good. The conversation reminded me of a talk I saw from Marianne Duijst; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vXIZpe-x4o8?t=595"&gt;here's the moment she started talking about the difference between coaches, sponsors, teachers, and role models, and how they can support you in different ways&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anytime Maaret Pyhäjärvi is running an exploratory testing session, go to it. You will be better for it. This time, we tested a simple web application. We ended up spending most of the time adding scenarios to the automated tests Maaret had already set up in Robot framework. One of the questions it brought up for me: do you leave failed tests in your automation suite to highlight unexpected behavior? I had this problem this week: I'd updated a schema to validate against the current behavior while the story was in progress, instead of the behavior we wanted when it was done, so I could verify other fields in the output. Next time I think I'll separate them into two tests and leave them both as pending (marked as xfail in the pytest framework) so it's clear something needs to change before the software is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the SoCraTes organizers for, as I learned a coach does, holding this space for us to examine ourselves and reflect. As someone who is much more fluent in emoji than GIF, I'm grateful to have won the hearts of the participants with this "letting the cat out of the bag" GIF in the GIF challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="img_container" style="display: inline-block;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://media1.tenor.com/images/e49bc18b66056a71171ae6f16046a2a4/tenor.gif?itemid=11543319" style="display:block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Cat aggressively jumping out of a backpack"&gt;&lt;span class="img_caption" style="display: block; text-align: center;"&gt;Cat aggressively jumping out of a backpack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>note-taking</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-08-02_socrates-uk-august-2020/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>