<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Software Tester (Posts about humans)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/humans.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 07:34:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Long Haul</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_long_haul/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been both the lead of my team and a tester on that team for a year now. Getting answers, adapting to change, and identifying solutions have completely different time horizons in each of these roles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tester experiments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing experiments can run quickly. A testing experiment might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call an API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare that to the specification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Question whether either or both need changing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to a developer about the changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the specification and/or tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of that happens within minutes or hours, or days if schedules are extremely incompatible and asynchronous communication is failing. I can be confident in the experiment's outcome. I can weigh the relative merits of caring vs. not caring about a particular error response code or required field, and leave my work at work. The next time I see a particular error response, I know what to look for and where changes might be needed. A failing test is evidence that something used to work in a particular way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Team lead experiments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team lead experiments take longer. A team lead experiment might look something more like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team members complain that it's hard to get their ideas in during refinement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I mention this to the talking-dominant team member at a 1-on-1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member dominates following refinement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I remind talking-dominant team member in Slack about our previous conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member spills over their allotted time during big unit meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bring both of these instances in our 1-on-1, sharing the consequences (they're the single point of failure, other team members aren't heard) of their actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member does it again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ask team member what I can do to help them change their behavior, given that we are both adults in control of our own behavior. They agree that change is their responsibility. We agree that setting their microphone on mute at the start of the meeting would help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member dominates some of the following refinement, until I remind them to mute, after which other team members have time to think and contribute too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ask talking-dominant team member to set up a Slackbot to send them a reminder to mute their microphone each week before the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other people are able to contribute at the following refinement. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This took place over months. We're not to a point where we have a solution that works every time. I went in with a different hypothesis each time, not knowing when I'd hit on the right one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. I think the talking-dominant team member isn't aware of their behavior.&lt;br&gt;
4. I think the team member has forgotten our first conversation.&lt;br&gt;
6. I think the team member doesn't understand the impact of their behavior.&lt;br&gt;
8. I think the team member hasn't found a tool or a trigger to change their habit.&lt;br&gt;
10. I think the team member needs both a tool and a trigger to change their habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of the first four experiments taken by itself looks like a failure. The talking-dominant team member prevents other team members from contributing effectively. It takes me time as a leader to come up with a different hypothesis, try something else, and discover where to go from there. And this was a relatively straightforward issue to assess. Imagine how long it might take to find an effective response to a problem with more variables and more consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also thinking not just about the experiments themselves, but how they might come across to the wider team. For the testing experiment, I could present my results in standup the next day as "I tested it, everything's good" but it's more valuable for everyone if I &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/defining-story-completion-as-a-software-tester"&gt;tell a bit more of the story&lt;/a&gt;. In the team lead experiment, I can imagine my team member telling my boss "Elizabeth told me to be quiet" or me telling my boss "The talking-dominant team member is giving room for others to contribute." Telling a slightly longer story of the journey displays my value as a team lead in a better light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What experiments are you running right now? Is something that looks or feels like a failure getting you closer to a solution? How long is your time horizon?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>critical-thinking</category><category>humans</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>teaching</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_long_haul/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Humans Conf, June 2020</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-12_humans_conf_june_2020/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found Humans Conf on Twitter, and found myself in a position to attend when &lt;em&gt;gestures at the general state of the world&lt;/em&gt; moved it online. You can check out the output from the entire open space on the &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/June-2nd-2020-Virtual-Open-Space-26d1d0595b4b4574baf647025f3be544"&gt;Notion page&lt;/a&gt;. It took place for a few hours on a Tuesday night. I discovered the energy it takes to listen and participate attentively in the evening affected my work for the following couple of days. I am only human!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first session I attended was about making diversity more inclusive, and hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/buggylina"&gt;Lina Zubyte&lt;/a&gt;. Due to the makeup of the participants, the conversation veered towards being a woman in tech. We spoke about incorrect assumptions, how we felt about particular language (especially &lt;code&gt;guys&lt;/code&gt;), and how much energy that drains from us all the time. I heard stories from other women that echoed situations from my experience. I recognized how telling a story from a memorably bad day helps others understand and connect. I pondered if there's a way to make people understand, without reliving everyday indignities. My takeaway from the conversation was clear: you get to decide how to spend your energy. There will be people whose minds need changing, but the energy you would expend making that happen wouldn't be worth it. Let those people who challenge the premises of the problem space fall off your radar, and invest in people where you can make a difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second session, I started off in motivating interactions, hosted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/innoviva"&gt;Maren Baermann&lt;/a&gt;. I truly enjoyed the model she introduced regarding &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-determination_theory#Motivations"&gt;extrinsic vs. intrinsic motivation&lt;/a&gt;, and tying those to our &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-determination_theory#Basic_needs_and_intrinsic_motivation"&gt;basic needs&lt;/a&gt;. But when the Zoom gods kicked me out of the free room, I took it as a sign to go search for a less interactive session where I could just listen. I landed in a session relating couples therapy to your team dynamics, hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DariaDorda"&gt;Daria Dorda&lt;/a&gt;. The conversation covered some national stereotypes, how people get distracted from the real message, and how to get the necessary distance to engage with a topic. My takeaway here was: if you don't set boundaries, others will for you. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm grateful to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/benjamin"&gt;Benjamin Reitzammer&lt;/a&gt; who hosted the open space, and all the others who made it run smoothly. Seeing just a handful of familiar faces set me at ease. I'd never seen Zoom chat used effectively, but the rush of answers to the closing questions at the end of the evening gave me that warm &amp;amp; fuzzy feeling like I'd actually attended a conference in person. I needed that, so thank you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think I can bring myself to join the next Humans Conf on Wednesday, 15 July. I've got a week off, and I need some time away from Zoom to be feeling more human. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>humans</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-12_humans_conf_june_2020/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>