<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Organizational Anarchist (Posts about humans)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/humans.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 14:47:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Amateur Professional Career Coach</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/08_13_amateur_professional_career_coach/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/rose.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;People come to me for career advice. It's been everybody -- colleagues, former colleagues, testers from the community, friends I know outside of software, younger family members -- everybody. I am not completely sure why. I have a job I enjoy, but I'm not a professional coach. I seem to be an amateur coach of professionals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do have (and am happy to share) strong opinions about what people should do when they describe particular situations they're in. I can immediately tell them what I would do. But figuring out what &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; should do is much more useful. So in response to tough questions, I ask them tough questions back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is this so hard?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People come to me with tricky situations with their current roles. For some, venting is enough. But I might ask someone who seems exhausted, sick of it, checked-out, or seems stuck for too long: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much longer could you let things stay the way they are? Another six weeks? Another six months? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It sounds like you're having {X} trouble with {Y} person. Have you told them this directly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't have the skills to mentor you in {Z}. Do you know someone who does? Or where could you find someone like that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would aligning expectations help? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is saying "no" an option here? (I've been called the "&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aahunsberger/status/1534974206680629248"&gt;No Coach&lt;/a&gt;" for this.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What should I do next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know what you should do next, or even if you should change what you're doing now! But here's what I will ask you about so you can decide: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you like about what you do now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What parts of your current job do you want to stay the same? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you avoid or dread? What keeps you in bed in the morning?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do people come to you for help with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is there no hope of changing in your current situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/estherderby"&gt;Esther Derby&lt;/a&gt; gave a webinar in March of 2021 describing the tipping point between whether you can reconcile your needs and values with your employer, or whether you should leave. But unforunately both the webinar and her name for this zone is lost to me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do you think of my CV?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've written both for the &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/how-to-interview-like-a-tester"&gt;Minsitry of Testing&lt;/a&gt; and on my own blog about &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_27_cvs_from_a_hiring_perspective/"&gt;resumes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2017/2017-08-06_doubt-builds-trust/"&gt;how they relate to the interview&lt;/a&gt;. TL;DR: Tell me about the &lt;em&gt;impact&lt;/em&gt; of what you've done, and give me some indication of how fluent vs. on the shelf the skill is for you. Other things I end up asking people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know you {did this other thing} or {have this other skill} too. Don't you want to brag about that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It sounds like your skills would be a great match for {this kind of job}. Is that the kind of role you're applying for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a recruiter were trying to find someone like you on LinkedIn, what keywords would they search for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the feedback I've received after recent resume reviews: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Thanks again for your feedback on my CV, it was INCREDIBLY useful and very gentle at that."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"You are a great feedback provider."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Elizabeth was so good in helping me with my resume!!"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm curious who you've gone to for career advice. Were they in your industry? What made you seek them over other people for advice or wisdom? What question or piece of advice has changed the way you look at your current job or for a new one?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>coaching</category><category>humans</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/08_13_amateur_professional_career_coach/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cutting People Off</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/cutting_people_off/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/shushing.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;Impatience is a virtue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If impatience is solely your own, sorry, but you're the asshole. But if impatience is shared, saving your colleagues from a tiresome conversation will make their day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notice that a topic should come to a close&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you listen actively, you'll notice when something has already been said. It is much easier (particularly when remote) to give up, zone out, and think about something else. Don't be that person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engage with your colleagues! Save yourself and others from the perpetual purgatory that is an ineffective meeting. Pay attention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Decide whether you are the right person to close a topic&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be settings where you are the right person to decide if a topic should come to a close: in a small group of relative equals, when you're the appointed facilitator, or you're in some other position of power relative to the individuals or the subject matter. Recognize when you're not in the right position to change what's happening in the moment, and skip to Follow-up for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the group already has expectations about what is or isn't on topic, your interruption should be enough. If it doesn't, or you want to take this opportunity to set a new one, interrupt with a meta-question. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How to deliver this message&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not always in the best position to decide whether now is the right time for a topic, so I tend to deliver topic-closing messages as questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I agree with your point about Thing B, but can we come back to Thing D?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We agreed that Person A is going to follow-up with Person C, is there anything more that we need to discuss about Thing B right now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could discuss Thing B more in this group, but since we're missing Person C's crucial input, should we?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've captured what Person A said here in the notes. Was there anything I missed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Person A already said Thing B, shall we move on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It sounds like we're still discussing Thing B after we just agreed not to, am I understanding that correctly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we leave it there for now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're not sure if it's the right time for a question, try a meta-question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is now the right time to decide if we should keep talking about Thing B?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we going to be able to come to Decision D today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did we decide on a next step towards Thing B, or is that what you were describing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give the group a chance to decide, but don't be afraid to hold them to their decision. These are not questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've agreed to that. Let's move on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That's all we needed Person A for, let's let them go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That's all I have for you, I'll let you go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thank you for your input/time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got it, thanks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Follow-up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get feedback on your behavior. This is how you learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A retrospective or 1-on-1 would be a good place to find out if the balance was right between gathering/sharing information and staying on topic. Asking someone to watch out for this particular behavior ahead of time will allow them to give you better feedback afterwards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A colleague once declared me the "queen of cutting people off" because I did so very politely. I have a compliment stickie note from "ruling refinement with an iron fist." We should all be so lucky to have our work appreciated this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on meta-information, see &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/delivering_information_vs_delivering_meta_information/"&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;. For more on setting agendas and preparing for meetings to make them effective, see &lt;a href="https://j19sch.github.io/slides/atd2020-making-meetings-work.html"&gt;this deck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>humans</category><category>leadership</category><category>meetings</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/cutting_people_off/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Mental Load of One Meeting</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_mental_load_of_one_meeting/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2021/outlook-calendar-week.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I facilitated a meeting today. It was scheduled for 45 minutes on my agenda, for me and some other tech and team leads in my unit. We covered what we needed to move forward planning an epic with a set of relatively straightforward stories, both in execution and work distribution among the teams. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some of the people attending today, they showed up without preparing, and didn't remember what the topic was. I filled them in. Because this is what the meeting preparation looked like from my side: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in a planning meeting two weeks ago with a variety of people from the unit. I picked up the implication that that follow-up (combination solo thinking/document review followed by meeting) was needed soon with a few tech and team leads. I checked the out of office schedule (that I created and keep updated as people mention when they'll be out) and noticed that two weeks was an achievable time span for "soon". I mentioned this while we were still in that planning meeting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the next 48 hours, two people from the planning meeting asked when I'd scheduled the follow-up. I explained that I was giving the other leads a chance to schedule it first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I scheduled the follow-up, I made the title of the Outlook invitation "review the comments you've already added to the document" so the purpose and expectations were both clear and impossible to miss. I added the document to review to the body of the invitation. I let the two inquiring minds know that this occurred. I found a couple of 45-minute blocks when all four people present at the planning meeting, plus the one person that had been forgotten, were available simultaneously. I chose the one on Tuesday, giving the person who was out for a week Monday to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added a Slackbot reminder for Monday afternoon for the person who's out the previous week. They're on my team and typically have trouble saying no when someone tries to pull their focus. &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_long_haul/"&gt;We've found that Slackbots help&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting time arrives. The Slackbot reminder person and I have reviewed the document. The others haven't. I check in and ask whether we should hold this meeting after they're available to do so. Silence. I move on, facilitating the discussion, taking notes, and keeping us on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not the only person capable of scheduling a meeting. I am not the person best equipped to review this document. It is not my responsibility to come up with systems for my peers to remember to do their work. I can let this fail, just not follow-up, and I do with smaller, safer-to-fail experiments. But it doesn't solve the problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't do a better job of explaining &lt;a href="https://english.emmaclit.com/2017/05/20/you-shouldve-asked/"&gt;the burden of carrying the mental load than Emma does in her comic&lt;/a&gt;. But to summarize: a lot of work is the work of noticing what work needs doing. It's the difference between "Let me know if you need help" and finding a way to actually help. It's the difference between having 45 minutes blocked on your calendar, and &lt;a href="https://j19sch.github.io/slides/atd2020-making-meetings-work.html#/"&gt;everything else that had to happen to make it successful&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I wonder now is: how much is this skill of carrying the mental load noticed? How much is it valued? How do we interview for this skill? How do I train my fellow team members to have it? How do I teach the ownership of a team and a project? How do I get people to ask each other about the next step in picking up the work instead of coming to me to be the dispatcher? How do I make myself, instead of irreplacable, completely replaceable? &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>humans</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_mental_load_of_one_meeting/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Long Haul</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_long_haul/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've been both the lead of my team and a tester on that team for a year now. Getting answers, adapting to change, and identifying solutions have completely different time horizons in each of these roles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tester experiments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing experiments can run quickly. A testing experiment might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call an API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect the output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare that to the specification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Question whether either or both need changing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to a developer about the changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the specification and/or tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of that happens within minutes or hours, or days if schedules are extremely incompatible and asynchronous communication is failing. I can be confident in the experiment's outcome. I can weigh the relative merits of caring vs. not caring about a particular error response code or required field, and leave my work at work. The next time I see a particular error response, I know what to look for and where changes might be needed. A failing test is evidence that something used to work in a particular way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Team lead experiments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team lead experiments take longer. A team lead experiment might look something more like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team members complain that it's hard to get their ideas in during refinement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I mention this to the talking-dominant team member at a 1-on-1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member dominates following refinement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I remind talking-dominant team member in Slack about our previous conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member spills over their allotted time during big unit meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bring both of these instances in our 1-on-1, sharing the consequences (they're the single point of failure, other team members aren't heard) of their actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member does it again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ask team member what I can do to help them change their behavior, given that we are both adults in control of our own behavior. They agree that change is their responsibility. We agree that setting their microphone on mute at the start of the meeting would help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking-dominant team member dominates some of the following refinement, until I remind them to mute, after which other team members have time to think and contribute too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ask talking-dominant team member to set up a Slackbot to send them a reminder to mute their microphone each week before the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other people are able to contribute at the following refinement. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This took place over months. We're not to a point where we have a solution that works every time. I went in with a different hypothesis each time, not knowing when I'd hit on the right one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. I think the talking-dominant team member isn't aware of their behavior.&lt;br&gt;
4. I think the team member has forgotten our first conversation.&lt;br&gt;
6. I think the team member doesn't understand the impact of their behavior.&lt;br&gt;
8. I think the team member hasn't found a tool or a trigger to change their habit.&lt;br&gt;
10. I think the team member needs both a tool and a trigger to change their habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of the first four experiments taken by itself looks like a failure. The talking-dominant team member prevents other team members from contributing effectively. It takes me time as a leader to come up with a different hypothesis, try something else, and discover where to go from there. And this was a relatively straightforward issue to assess. Imagine how long it might take to find an effective response to a problem with more variables and more consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also thinking not just about the experiments themselves, but how they might come across to the wider team. For the testing experiment, I could present my results in standup the next day as "I tested it, everything's good" but it's more valuable for everyone if I &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/defining-story-completion-as-a-software-tester"&gt;tell a bit more of the story&lt;/a&gt;. In the team lead experiment, I can imagine my team member telling my boss "Elizabeth told me to be quiet" or me telling my boss "The talking-dominant team member is giving room for others to contribute." Telling a slightly longer story of the journey displays my value as a team lead in a better light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What experiments are you running right now? Is something that looks or feels like a failure getting you closer to a solution? How long is your time horizon?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>critical-thinking</category><category>humans</category><category>leadership</category><category>mindset</category><category>teaching</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2021/the_long_haul/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Humans Conf, June 2020</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-12_humans_conf_june_2020/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I found Humans Conf on Twitter, and found myself in a position to attend when &lt;em&gt;gestures at the general state of the world&lt;/em&gt; moved it online. You can check out the output from the entire open space on the &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/June-2nd-2020-Virtual-Open-Space-26d1d0595b4b4574baf647025f3be544"&gt;Notion page&lt;/a&gt;. It took place for a few hours on a Tuesday night. I discovered the energy it takes to listen and participate attentively in the evening affected my work for the following couple of days. I am only human!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first session I attended was about making diversity more inclusive, and hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/buggylina"&gt;Lina Zubyte&lt;/a&gt;. Due to the makeup of the participants, the conversation veered towards being a woman in tech. We spoke about incorrect assumptions, how we felt about particular language (especially &lt;code&gt;guys&lt;/code&gt;), and how much energy that drains from us all the time. I heard stories from other women that echoed situations from my experience. I recognized how telling a story from a memorably bad day helps others understand and connect. I pondered if there's a way to make people understand, without reliving everyday indignities. My takeaway from the conversation was clear: you get to decide how to spend your energy. There will be people whose minds need changing, but the energy you would expend making that happen wouldn't be worth it. Let those people who challenge the premises of the problem space fall off your radar, and invest in people where you can make a difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second session, I started off in motivating interactions, hosted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/innoviva"&gt;Maren Baermann&lt;/a&gt;. I truly enjoyed the model she introduced regarding &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-determination_theory#Motivations"&gt;extrinsic vs. intrinsic motivation&lt;/a&gt;, and tying those to our &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-determination_theory#Basic_needs_and_intrinsic_motivation"&gt;basic needs&lt;/a&gt;. But when the Zoom gods kicked me out of the free room, I took it as a sign to go search for a less interactive session where I could just listen. I landed in a session relating couples therapy to your team dynamics, hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DariaDorda"&gt;Daria Dorda&lt;/a&gt;. The conversation covered some national stereotypes, how people get distracted from the real message, and how to get the necessary distance to engage with a topic. My takeaway here was: if you don't set boundaries, others will for you. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm grateful to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/benjamin"&gt;Benjamin Reitzammer&lt;/a&gt; who hosted the open space, and all the others who made it run smoothly. Seeing just a handful of familiar faces set me at ease. I'd never seen Zoom chat used effectively, but the rush of answers to the closing questions at the end of the evening gave me that warm &amp;amp; fuzzy feeling like I'd actually attended a conference in person. I needed that, so thank you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think I can bring myself to join the next Humans Conf on Wednesday, 15 July. I've got a week off, and I need some time away from Zoom to be feeling more human. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>humans</category><category>testing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2020/2020-07-12_humans_conf_june_2020/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>