<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Zagroba: Organizational Anarchist (Posts about writing)</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/categories/writing.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>© 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:me@elizabethzagroba.com"&gt;Elizabeth Zagroba&lt;/a&gt; Mozilla Public License 2.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 14:47:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>CVs From A Hiring Perspective</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_27_cvs_from_a_hiring_perspective/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In my department at work, every tester is on their own team. I'm in a position where I look at tester resumes before we decide to screen them. Some of the resumes come in from people applying on the company website. We've also got a recruiter searching for people on LinkedIn. She asked me before we posted a new job: if we're not requiring experience with a particular tech stack, what should she search for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't have a great answer for her at first. It took me some time to think about what we'd value in this role, what would make a candidate's resume stand out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't look for particular buzzwords on resumes, and no particular buzzword can eliminate you from the hiring process. But I do look for some of the same &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/defining-story-completion-as-a-software-tester"&gt;things I look for in a test report&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/how-to-interview-like-a-tester"&gt;an indicator of the depth and quality of your work, and an ability to connect your work to the value to the development team or the business&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A resume that regurgitates the calendar or job description of the candidate doesn't stand out to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attended standup, refinement, sprint planning, sprint review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made test plan, executed tests, reported tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to know what was hard about it. I want to know who else was there and how you interacted with them. I want to know what you do that other people in your position don't do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitated hybrid standup across three time zones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refined ideas into user stories with acceptance criteria that met our definition of ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoke to key stakeholders to identify risks and incorporate them into a test plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared test results verbally to spark conversation with developers about impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented test plan at guild to inspire other testers to shift left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on a &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/series/testbash-careers-2022/lessons/discussion-creating-cvs-that-get-noticed-elizabeth-zagroba-nicola-martin-peet-michielsen"&gt;TestBash Careers panel&lt;/a&gt; about having a CV that gets you noticed. (I regret to inform you that my ability to think of an answer and unmute are not always fast enough to chime in!) I'm digging into the unanswered questions on &lt;a href="https://club.ministryoftesting.com/t/testbash-careers-2022-discussion-with-elizabeth-zagroba-nicola-martin-a-peet-michielsen/59274"&gt;the club thread&lt;/a&gt;, and can tell you that my fellow panelists and host are more shrewed about when or when not to reveal a personal detail on a resume. I am privileged enough to &lt;a href="https://elizabethzagroba.com/assets/resumes/trustworthy-resume.pdf"&gt;lean towards the truth&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at work, I told the recruiter there were a couple things should could search for: exploratory testing and integration testing. Our desire to cast as wide and inclusive a net as possible has been an investment of her time, and the time of the team members who speak to the candidates first. It's not cheap. I hope it's worth it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jobs.lever.co/mendix/92c1c255-2455-4c25-bd78-a05c154d5f8e"&gt;Join us if you're interested&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/women-interview.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@wocintechchat?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Christina @ wocintechchat.com&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>communication</category><category>testbash</category><category>writing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_27_cvs_from_a_hiring_perspective/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Communicate Using Three Layers of Information</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_12_communicate_using_three_layers_of_information/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've joked about writing Buzzfeed-style clickbait titles for JIRA tickets: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Stuck in purgatory after hitting logout &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Maybe not so clickbait-ey but I logged this for more than one system I tested. The navigation had a different login state than the page and you couldn't escape.)&lt;/p&gt;— Elizabeth Zagroba (@ezagroba) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ezagroba/status/1503647930061885444?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 15, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partly, clickbait titles gave me an easy way to search the database, or type a few words in my browser bar, to pull up the right issue quickly. The JIRA ticket itself had steps to reproduce, an explanation of why it was important, and an annotated screenshot for people to easily understand if what I saw was happening on their machine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partly, clickbait titles gave us a convenient shorthand to help us remember whether it's this logout issue or some other logout that we're talking about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partly, clickbait titles made the developers interested to investigate and pick up the issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading Giles Turnbull's &lt;a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/876240f0-8657-4482-b5c5-8160bef6d372"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The agile comms handbook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last weekend and found the &lt;em&gt;lure&lt;/em&gt; part of the three communication layers he described (&lt;em&gt;lure&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;detail&lt;/em&gt;) reminiscent of the clickbait JIRA ticket titles I'd written. And that I'd see these three communication layers (title, description, details) described similarly in lots of places before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lure, context, detail&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole (short and great) &lt;em&gt;The agile comms handbook&lt;/em&gt; is about how to communicate in ways that move as fast as the work does on an Agile team while still being effective for busy people to consume. In the book, Giles Turnbull describes creating different layers of information as &lt;em&gt;lure&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;detail&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Lure&lt;/em&gt; grabs the attention of busy people and gets them interested in knowing more. &lt;em&gt;Context&lt;/em&gt; gets people to the point where they know just enough. &lt;em&gt;Detail&lt;/em&gt; is for people who need to know more and have the time to follow a link to another page, read a whole PDF, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why, how, what&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek describes it as &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qp0HIF3SfI4"&gt;this TED Talk on "How great leaders inspire action"&lt;/a&gt;. He gives the example of an advertisement for Apple, where starting with the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; is much more inspiring and motivating than starting with the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;. Getting people to buy into your vision will ensure that they follow along to the goal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Title, executive summary, list of issues&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we worked together, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vds4"&gt;Martin Hynie&lt;/a&gt; taught me to write weekly test reports with a &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;executive summary&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;list of issues&lt;/em&gt;, with the idea that the &lt;em&gt;executive summary&lt;/em&gt; should be enough for the busy person to understand, but that less busy and more curious people would want the detail in the &lt;em&gt;list of issues&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Intent, location, details&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maaretp"&gt;Maaret Pyhäjärvi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/dojo/lessons/mob-testing-an-introduction-experience-report"&gt;describes the ensemble (mob) programming practice&lt;/a&gt; of communicating at the highest level of abstraction (&lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt;) before being more specific about where we're going (&lt;em&gt;location&lt;/em&gt;) or if necessary, mouse clicks and keystrokes (&lt;em&gt;details&lt;/em&gt;). Giving keystrokes and mouse clicks to someone who knows how to operate the software is frustrating, but so is giving a high-level explanation to someone who's never used the software before. Expressing intent first can lead to better action, even if another member of the ensemble has a different action in mind than you do. Being able to identify when to jump between the levels is key for effective communication. Knowing when to jump to a different layer of communication is the skill I find hardest to build while learning to ensemble. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Title, lede, body&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the content management system I tested for New York Public Radio, article pages were broken down into &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;lede&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;body&lt;/em&gt;, presumably reflecting something every journalist learns on their first day at a newspaper. On the website, &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;lede&lt;/em&gt; were displayed on the homepage and tag pages. You'd only see the &lt;em&gt;body&lt;/em&gt; once you clicked in to read or listen to the story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read so many JIRA tickets and Slack messages that only contain the lowest/detail level of information. The person trying to bring everyone else up-to-speed on an issue does need to include all the detail. It makes sense that that's where their mind is. Giles Turnbull identifies why the detail layer of information is the default: the details already exist. Creating the other lure and context layers of information takes more work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to zoom out and answer the kinds of questions you'd expect in a refinement meeting ("Who will benefit from this? How does it work now and why does it need to change?") helps you prioritize the work. It helps the team understand how what they're doing fits into the bigger picture. Learning how to write the &lt;em&gt;lure&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt; is a separate technical skill that needs to be recognized and built. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you learn to break down your communication into different layers? Do the title, headers, and paragraphs of this blog post fit this model? Which of these breakdowns resonates most with you? Where are you practicing communicating this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/colorful-layers.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@snapsbyclark?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Clark Van Der Beken&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/elevated?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>writing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/05_12_communicate_using_three_layers_of_information/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What's You're Missing in Your Conference Abstract: Spoilers</title><link>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/04_10_what_youre_missing_in_your_conference_abstract_spoilers/</link><dc:creator>Elizabeth Zagroba</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've had the unique honor of participating in the program committee for &lt;a href="https://agiletestingdays.com/"&gt;Agile Testing Days&lt;/a&gt; for 2021 and 2022. I get to see anonymized submissions for talks and workshops (not keynotes), rate the entries on a number of criteria, and provide a few sentences of feedback for the author and the conference organizers to understand how and whether the submission fits in the program. I've also helped review papers in the &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/testbash/review"&gt;Ministry of Testing call for papers&lt;/a&gt;. Anyone can. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all of them are missing one thing: spoilers. I want spoilers. I want them to tell me how they faced a problem or general trend in the market at their job and what they did about it. I want enough detail, any detail, to know what I'll be seeing beyond the first two slides. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what that looks like for a talk and a workshop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a talk, I'm expecting a particular format: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description of a problem the author has experienced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journey or decision point that led the author to change their behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details about the direction going forward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I'm missing the author's personal connection in 1. (looks like they'll summarize a book, article, someone else's work, etc.) or why a change was needed in 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's 3. that I long for. Authors tell me that they solved a problem, or had trouble solving it, but not how. "I spent three months migrating our tests from Selenium to Playwright and faced trouble." Where did you face trouble? Was it because of differences between the languages? Developers couldn't read the failing test output anymore? What happened?? Tell me about the journey of what that looked like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workshops&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a workshop, I want to see: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description of a skill the author was missing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journey where the author built this skill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journey participants will go on to build this skill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workshops ideas are great with 1. and often include 2. But you know what participants will mostly care about before they get trapped in a room for hours with you? That's right, it's 3. Will this be a lecture disguished as a workshop so the author has more time to speak? Will participants be working in groups? Will this get them on the first step towards building a skill? How much will they be able to do differently at work on Monday? Give me some sense of what the activities are, how long they might take, and how much you expect people to achieve during them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More tips on conference submissions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anytime I submit an abstract to a conference, I find something in Rob Lambert's &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/blazingly-simple-guide-submitting-conferences-rob-lambert/"&gt;Blazingly Simple Guide To Submitting To Conferences&lt;/a&gt; that makes me reconsider what I've written. Read it if you're anywhere on the journey from "do I even have an idea for this conference?" to "you mean I'm supposed to speak on stage in front of all these people sitting before me?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lisihocke"&gt;Lisi Hocke&lt;/a&gt; also has a &lt;a href="https://www.lisihocke.com/p/speaking-at-conferences.html"&gt;soup-to-nuts overview of conference speaking&lt;/a&gt; that will get you feeling like you can do this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://elizabethzagroba.com/images/posts/2022/orange-desert.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@brandi1?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Brandi Redd&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conference</category><category>testing</category><category>writing</category><guid>https://elizabethzagroba.com/posts/2022/04_10_what_youre_missing_in_your_conference_abstract_spoilers/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>